<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>A DevOps Blog</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.valewood.org/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.valewood.org/</link>
	<description>Occasionally a developer makes an Ops!</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 22:22:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.valewood.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/A-DevOoops-1-e1660773390219.png</url>
	<title>A DevOps Blog</title>
	<link>https://www.valewood.org/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>How to SSH into a K8s pod</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/how-to-ssh-into-pod-k8s/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 20:24:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Kubernetes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[howto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tools]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2314</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Taking the paradigm shift from running applications on servers to running them in containers is quite the mental jump. The technology industry has spent the last 50 years creating technology to accelerate on top of servers whether they are physical&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Taking the paradigm shift from running applications on servers to running them in containers is quite the mental jump. The technology industry has spent the last 50 years creating technology to accelerate on top of servers whether they are physical or virtual.</p>



<p>Containers showed up on the scene in 2013, though the mechanics for containers had been showing up in the Linux kernel earlier than that. The adoption of containers has been steady but has also been slow over time.</p>



<p><a href="https://kubernetes.io/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="4" title="Kubernetes" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Kubernetes</a> was released in 2015 and has greatly accelerated container adoption in the industry. Because of Kubernetes&#8217; close ties with <a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a>, and the rapid adoption of DevOps, nearly everyone in the technology space has had to rapidly pick up and try to make sense of this paradigm shift.</p>



<p>An activity that any systems administrator has performed is the remote administration of a server. On Linux, there will be an exchange of key files, and an SSH connection is established to an internal or external IP address, and boom you are in!</p>



<p>How do you remotely administer a container running in a Kubernetes cluster? Let&#8217;s explore that question below!</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>What is a Container Runtime?</h2>



<p>A container runtime is a software component that is responsible for executing and managing containers on a host. It provides the necessary infrastructure to launch and manage containers, including creating and destroying containers, allocating resources to containers, and providing networking and storage services to containers.</p>



<p>There are several different container runtime implementations available, including <a href="https://www.docker.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="16" title="Docker" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Docker</a>, ContainerD, and CRI-O. These runtime implementations are typically used in conjunction with a container orchestration platform, such as Kubernetes, to manage the deployment and scaling of containers in a distributed environment.</p>



<p>In general, a container runtime is responsible for the low-level management of containers, including tasks such as starting and stopping containers, providing isolation between containers, and managing resource allocation for containers. The container orchestration platform, on the other hand, is responsible for higher-level tasks such as scheduling containers across multiple hosts, ensuring that the desired number of replicas of a container is running, and providing load balancing and networking services for containers.</p>



<h2>How Does a Container Work?</h2>



<p>Containers are a way to package and distribute applications and their dependencies in a lightweight and portable way. They allow developers to build and deploy applications that can run consistently across different environments, such as developer laptops, staging servers, and production environments.</p>



<p>Containers work by using the operating system&#8217;s kernel to allow multiple isolated user-space instances, or containers, to run on a single host. Each container shares the host&#8217;s kernel but has its own user space, which includes the libraries, system tools, and application code needed to run the application.</p>



<p>When a container is created, it is based on a container image, which is a lightweight, stand-alone, and executable package that includes everything needed to run the application, including the application code, libraries, system tools, and runtime. The container image is built from a set of instructions called a Dockerfile, which specifies the steps needed to create the image.</p>



<p>To run a container, you can use a container runtime, such as Docker, to start the container based on the container image. The container runtime creates a new container instance and allocates the necessary resources, such as CPU, memory, and storage, to the container. The container runtime then launches the application inside the container and provides it with the necessary networking and storage services.</p>



<h2>How Do I SSH Into a Running Container?</h2>



<p>The short answer is this; unless the container is running an SSH server with a port mapped to a service, you don&#8217;t. The right question to ask is &#8220;How do I access a running Container or Pod&#8217;s Shell?&#8221; That question is answered in another section down below.</p>



<p>A container is essentially carved out of user space from the operating system&#8217;s kernel which is running one or more processes in isolation. When you SSH into a server, that server is running a process like OpenSSH to facilitate your connection and login. If your containers are not running an OpenSSH server as a process, then SSHing is not the answer.</p>



<p>What you are really trying to do is start up a new process inside of the container which provides you with a running TTY Shell.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>How Do I access a running Container or Pod&#8217;s Shell?</h2>



<p>To SSH into a pod, or more correctly stated &#8220;gain terminal access into a pod&#8221;, in Kubernetes, you can use the kubectl exec command. This command allows you to execute a command in a specific container within a pod.</p>



<p>Here is an example of how to use kubectl exec to SSH into a pod:</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code language-bash"><code>kubectl exec -it -n &lt;namespace&gt; &lt;pod-name&gt; -- /bin/bash</code></pre>



<p>This will open a shell inside the container of the pod. You can then use the ssh command to connect to another server from within the container. If your pods do not have /bin/bash on them, then you can try something like /bin/sh or /bin/zsh.</p>



<p>Keep in mind that the pod must be running in order for you to be able to exec into it. If the pod is not running, you will need to start it before you can exec into it.</p>



<p>You can also use the kubectl exec command to execute other commands in the container, such as running scripts or checking the status of processes.</p>



<h2>Caveats for accessing Container or Pod&#8217;s Shell</h2>



<h3>Scratch Container</h3>



<p>A scratch container is a special type of container image that is built from scratch, without any base image. It is used as a starting point for building other container images, and typically includes only the bare minimum required to run a container, such as the operating system kernel and the init process.</p>



<p>Scratch containers are useful when you need to build a container image that is as lightweight as possible, or when you want to start with a completely blank slate and build up your container image from the ground up. They can also be useful when you want to build a container image that includes only the specific tools and dependencies that your application requires, rather than relying on a larger base image that might include unnecessary packages.</p>



<p>To use a scratch container, you can specify it as the base image when building your container image using a tool such as Docker. For example, the following Dockerfile uses a scratch container as the base image:</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code language-dockerfile"><code>FROM scratch
COPY my-app /
CMD &#091;"/my-app"]</code></pre>



<p>This Dockerfile will build a container image that includes only the my-app binary, without any other packages or dependencies.</p>



<p>If the base of the container you are running is &#8220;scratch&#8221; then you will not have a shell installed on that container unless you explicitly add one as part of the build process.</p>



<h3>Missing Shell or Command Language Interpreter</h3>



<p>A shell, or command language interpreter, is a software program that provides a command-line interface for interacting with an operating system. It allows users to execute commands and run programs by typing them into a terminal window or console.</p>



<p>The shell acts as an intermediary between the user and the operating system, taking input from the user, executing the requested commands, and displaying the results. It also provides a set of built-in commands and functions for performing common tasks, such as navigating the file system, managing files and directories, and launching programs.</p>



<p>There are many different shells available for different operating systems, each with its own unique syntax and features. Some common shells include the Bourne shell (sh), the C shell (csh), the Korn shell (ksh), and the Bourne-Again shell (bash).</p>



<p>In addition to providing a command-line interface, shells can also be used to write scripts that automate tasks and processes. These scripts, called shell scripts, are written in the syntax of the shell and can be executed from the command line or triggered by certain events.</p>



<p>If the base of the container you are running is &#8220;scratch&#8221; then you will not have a shell installed on that container unless you explicitly add one as part of the build process. The container you are running may also be limited to something like /bin/sh and may not have your favorite shell such as fish installed.</p>



<h3>The Container is not Running</h3>



<p>If your container is not running, you may not be able to exec in to get a shell. You may need to spin up an out-of-band pod that does not fail so that you can get in and review things like env vars or connection params. Below is how Kubernetes recommends you do this with their DNS debug container.</p>



<p>The DNS debug container is a tool that can be used to troubleshoot issues with DNS resolution in a Kubernetes cluster. It is a special container image that includes a number of utilities for diagnosing DNS problems, such as dig, nslookup, and host.</p>



<p>To use the DNS debug container in Kubernetes, you will need to create a pod that runs the container. You can do this using the kubectl command-line tool and a manifest file that specifies the pod&#8217;s configuration.</p>



<p>Here is an example manifest file that creates a pod with the DNS debug container:</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code language-yaml"><code>apiVersion: v1
kind: Pod
metadata:
  name: dns-debug
spec:
  containers:
  - name: dns-debug
    image: k8s.gcr.io/dns-debug:1.16.7</code></pre>



<p>To create the pod, save the manifest file and then run the following command:</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code language-bash"><code>kubectl apply -f manifest.yaml</code></pre>



<p>Once the pod is created, you can use kubectl exec to connect to the pod and run the DNS debugging utilities. For example, to run dig, you can use the following command:</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code language-bash"><code>kubectl exec dns-debug -it -- dig example.com</code></pre>



<p>This will execute the dig command inside the DNS debug container, allowing you to troubleshoot DNS issues in your cluster.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Frequently Asked Questions</h2>



<p>Below are some frequently asked questions relating to SSHing (or gaining access) to a k8s pod:</p>


<div id="rank-math-faq" class="rank-math-block">
<div class="rank-math-list ">
<div id="faq-question-1672161158864" class="rank-math-list-item">
<h3 class="rank-math-question ">How do I get SSH access to a k8s pod?</h3>
<div class="rank-math-answer ">

<p>To get SSH access to a Kubernetes (k8s) pod, you&#8217;ll need to do the following:</p>
<p>1. <strong>Make sure that the pod has an SSH server running inside it.</strong> This typically involves installing and running an SSH daemon  <code>sshd</code> inside the container.<br />2. <strong>Expose the pod&#8217;s SSH service to the network.</strong> This can be done by creating a Kubernetes Service object that exposes the pod&#8217;s SSH port (usually port 22) to the cluster. Alternatively, you can use a tool like <code>kubectl port-forward</code> to forward traffic from a local port to the pod&#8217;s SSH port.<br />3. <strong>Connect to the pod&#8217;s SSH service using an SSH client.</strong> You&#8217;ll need to know the pod&#8217;s IP address or hostname, as well as any authentication credentials required to log in.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s worth noting that SSH access to a k8s pod is not the recommended way to access and manage a pod. Instead, it&#8217;s generally better to use the k8s API and tools like <code>kubectl</code> to interact with and manage your pods.</p>

</div>
</div>
<div id="faq-question-1672161161788" class="rank-math-list-item">
<h3 class="rank-math-question ">Is it possible to SSH into a k8s pod?</h3>
<div class="rank-math-answer ">

<p>Yes, it is possible to SSH into a Kubernetes (k8s) pod, as long as the pod has an SSH server running inside it and the pod&#8217;s SSH service is exposed to the network.</p>

</div>
</div>
<div id="faq-question-1672161172612" class="rank-math-list-item">
<h3 class="rank-math-question ">How do I troubleshoot connectivity issues when trying to SSH into a k8s pod?</h3>
<div class="rank-math-answer ">

<p>If you&#8217;re having connectivity issues when trying to SSH into a Kubernetes (k8s) pod, here are some steps you can take to troubleshoot the problem:</p>
<p>1. <strong>Check the pod&#8217;s status:</strong> Make sure that the pod is running and ready. If the pod is not running or is in a failed state, you won&#8217;t be able to SSH into it. You can use the <code>kubectl get pods</code> command to check the status of your pods.<br />2. <strong>Check the pod&#8217;s IP address:</strong> Make sure that you have the correct IP address or hostname for the pod. You can use the <code>kubectl describe pod</code> command to get the IP address of a pod.<br />3. <strong>Check the pod&#8217;s SSH port:</strong> Make sure that you&#8217;re trying to connect to the correct SSH port on the pod. The default SSH port is 22, but it&#8217;s possible that the pod&#8217;s SSH service is listening on a different port.<br /><strong>4. Check the pod&#8217;s network connectivity: </strong>Make sure that the pod has network connectivity and that there are no network issues or firewalls blocking the connection. You can use the <code>kubectl exec</code> command to run a command inside the pod and verify that it has network connectivity.<br />5. <strong>Check the pod&#8217;s SSH service:</strong> Make sure that the pod&#8217;s SSH service is running and accessible. You can use the <code>kubectl exec</code> command to run a command inside the pod and check the status of the SSH service.<br />6. <strong>Check your SSH client and configuration:</strong> Make sure that your SSH client is configured correctly and that you&#8217;re using the correct authentication credentials.<br />7. <strong>Check the pod&#8217;s logs:</strong> You can use the <code>kubectl logs</code> command to view the pod&#8217;s logs, which may contain clues about the cause of the connectivity issues.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s worth noting that SSH access to a k8s pod is not the recommended way to access and manage a pod. Instead, it&#8217;s generally better to use the k8s API and tools like <code>kubectl</code> to interact with and manage your pods.</p>

</div>
</div>
<div id="faq-question-1672161178009" class="rank-math-list-item">
<h3 class="rank-math-question ">Can I use a private key to authenticate when SSHing into a k8s pod?</h3>
<div class="rank-math-answer ">

<p>Yes, you can use a private key to authenticate when SSHing into a Kubernetes (k8s) pod. This is typically done by creating a key pair (consisting of a private key and a public key) and installing the public key on the pod. The private key is then used to authenticate the connection when you SSH into the pod.</p>

</div>
</div>
<div id="faq-question-1672161196133" class="rank-math-list-item">
<h3 class="rank-math-question ">Is it possible to use a bastion host to SSH into a k8s pod?</h3>
<div class="rank-math-answer ">

<p>Yes, it is possible to use a bastion host to SSH into a Kubernetes (k8s) pod. A bastion host is a secure, remote server that acts as a gateway or jump host for accessing other servers on a network. By connecting to the bastion host first, you can then use the bastion host to SSH into the k8s pod, which can be useful for security or convenience reasons.</p>

</div>
</div>
<div id="faq-question-1672161205027" class="rank-math-list-item">
<h3 class="rank-math-question ">Can I use a tool like Ansible to manage SSH access to k8s pods?</h3>
<div class="rank-math-answer ">

<p>Yes, you can, but this is so far off the beaten path of how you should be managing a Kubernetes (k8s) cluster that I would highly recommend going back and reviewing all of your design decisions to ask yourself &#8220;Why??&#8221;</p>

</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>


<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>The answer to the question &#8216;How to SSH into pod K8s&#8217; is simply, you don&#8217;t. What you are really looking to do is exec a Command Language Interpreter, or shell, inside of a running container.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Beginner&#8217;s Guide to Unlocking the Power of ImagePullPolicy</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/kubernetes-imagepullpolicy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 17:22:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Kubernetes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[howto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tools]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2300</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Are you looking to unlock the full potential of ImagePullPolicy? If yes, then you’ve come to the right place! In this guide, we will discuss everything you need to know about ImagePullPolicy – from understanding what it is, to the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Are you looking to unlock the full potential of ImagePullPolicy? If yes, then you’ve come to the right place! In this guide, we will discuss everything you need to know about ImagePullPolicy – from understanding what it is, to the benefits of using it, getting started, setting it up, and more.</p>



<p>By the end of this guide, you will have all the knowledge you need to make the most of ImagePullPolicy. Let’s get started!</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>What Is The ImagePullPolicy?</h2>



<p>ImagePullPolicy is a set of rules used to control how images are pulled from container registries. It allows users to specify which images can be pulled when they can be pulled, and where they can be pulled from. This allows users to have greater control over their images and how they are used.</p>



<p>ImagePullPolicy is also a great way to ensure that images are kept up to date. By setting rules that limit when images can be pulled, users can ensure that their images are always up-to-date and that they are not using outdated versions of their images. This can help to reduce the risk of security vulnerabilities and ensure that their applications are running the latest versions of their images.</p>



<p>The ImagePullPolicy field in a <a href="https://kubernetes.io/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="4" title="Kubernetes" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Kubernetes</a> Pod spec does not directly enhance security, but it can be used as part of a security strategy by controlling when and how container images are pulled.</p>



<p>For example, you can set the ImagePullPolicy to IfNotPresent to ensure that the container image is only pulled from the registry if it is not already present on the node. This can help prevent unauthorized images from being deployed to your cluster.</p>



<p>You can also use the ImagePullPolicy to control when container images are updated. For example, you can set the policy to Always to ensure that the latest version of the image is always used, or you can set it to Never to prevent the image from being updated. This can be useful for ensuring that your deployments are consistent and that you are using known, stable versions of container images.</p>



<p>Overall, while the ImagePullPolicy is not directly related to security, it can be used as part of a security strategy by controlling when and how container images are pulled and updated.</p>



<h2>Benefits of Using ImagePullPolicy</h2>



<p>There are many benefits to using ImagePullPolicy, including improved security, increased control, and better efficiency. Let’s look at each of these in more detail:</p>



<h3>Improved Security</h3>



<p>By setting rules that limit which images can be pulled, when they can be pulled, and where they can be pulled from, users can be confident that their images are pulled from a secure location. This can help to reduce the risk of security vulnerabilities and ensure that their applications are running the latest versions of their images.</p>



<h3>Increased Control</h3>



<p>ImagePullPolicy also allows users to have greater control over their images and how they are used. By setting rules that limit when images can be pulled, users can ensure that their images are always up-to-date and that they are not using outdated versions of their images. This can help to ensure that their applications are running the most recent versions of their images and that any security vulnerabilities are addressed as quickly as possible.</p>



<h3>Better Efficiency</h3>



<p>Finally, ImagePullPolicy can also help to improve the efficiency of the image pull process. By setting rules that limit when images can be pulled, users can ensure that their images are pulled only when necessary. This can help to reduce the time and resources spent on pulling images and ensure that their applications are running the most up-to-date versions of their images.</p>



<h2>ImagePullPolicy Configuration Facets</h2>



<p>An image pull policy in Kubernetes specifies how a container should handle image updates. The relevant information configured in an image pull policy includes the following:</p>



<ol>
<li><strong>The image repository:</strong> This is the location from which the container should pull the image. The repository can be a public registry like <a href="https://www.docker.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="16" title="Docker" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Docker</a> Hub or a private registry. If the image is hosted on Docker Hub then this can be specified by image name shorthand instead of the fully qualified repository URL.</li>



<li><strong>The image tag:</strong> The image tag specifies the version of the image that should be used. If no tag is specified, the default latest tag is used.</li>



<li><strong>The policy: </strong>The policy specifies whether the container should always attempt to pull the latest version of the image (Always) or only pull the image if it is not already present on the host machine (IfNotPresent).</li>
</ol>



<p>These details are typically specified in the container configuration file, which is used to create the container in a Kubernetes deployment. The image pull policy is just one aspect of the container configuration, and other details such as the container name, resources, and environment variables may also be specified.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Getting started with ImagePullPolicy</h2>



<p>Now that we’ve discussed the benefits of using ImagePullPolicy, let’s look at how to get started. The first step is to set up an ImagePullPolicy. This is a simple process that involves creating a set of rules that define how images are pulled from your registries. Once your rules are set up, you can start to apply them to your images.</p>



<p>To set up ImagePullPolicy, you will need to create a set of rules that define which images can be pulled, when they can be pulled, and where they can be pulled from. This can be done using the ImagePullPolicy configuration file. This file is written in the YAML format and contains all the necessary information about your images and how they should be pulled.</p>



<p>Once your ImagePullPolicy configuration file is complete, you will need to apply it to your images. This can be done by adding a “pull policy” label to your images. This label will include the rules that you set in your ImagePullPolicy configuration file. Once your images are labeled, they will be subject to the rules you set in the configuration file and will only be pulled when the rules are met.</p>



<h3>Examples ImagePullPolicy Configurations</h3>



<p>Here is an example of a Kubernetes Pod specification that includes an ImagePullPolicy:</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code language-yaml"><code>apiVersion: v1
kind: Pod
metadata:
  name: my-pod
spec:
  containers:
  - name: my-container
    image: nginx:1.19
    imagePullPolicy: IfNotPresent
  ...</code></pre>



<p>In this example, the ImagePullPolicy field is set to IfNotPresent, which means that the container image will only be pulled from the specified registry if it is not already present on the node.</p>



<p>You can also set the ImagePullPolicy field to Always or Never, depending on your specific requirements. For example:</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code language-yaml"><code>apiVersion: v1
kind: Pod
metadata:
  name: my-pod
spec:
  containers:
  - name: my-container
    image: nginx:1.19
    imagePullPolicy: Always
  ...</code></pre>



<p>This would cause the container image to be pulled from the registry every time the Pod is started, ensuring that the latest version of the image is always used.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code language-yaml"><code>apiVersion: v1
kind: Pod
metadata:
  name: my-pod
spec:
  containers:
  - name: my-container
    image: nginx:1.19
    imagePullPolicy: Never
  ...</code></pre>



<p>This would prevent the container image from being pulled from the registry, and the existing image on the node would be used even if it is out of date.</p>



<h2>Setting up ImagePullPolicy</h2>



<p>Now that you know how to get started with ImagePullPolicy, let’s look at how to set it up correctly. Setting up ImagePullPolicy can be a bit tricky, so it’s important to follow the steps carefully.</p>



<p>The first step is to create an ImagePullPolicy configuration file. This file is written in the YAML format and contains all the necessary information about your images and how they should be pulled. This includes the specified image that can be pulled, when they can be pulled, and where they can be pulled from.</p>



<p>Once your ImagePullPolicy configuration file is complete, the next step is to apply it to your images. This can be done by adding a “pull policy” label to your images. This label will include the rules that you set in your ImagePullPolicy configuration file. Once your images are labeled, they will be subject to the rules you set in the configuration file and will only be pulled when the rules are met.</p>



<p>Finally, you will need to set up the ImagePullPolicy workflow. This workflow will define the steps that need to be taken when an image is pulled. This includes verifying that the image is authorized, ensuring that it is up-to-date, and pulling it from the correct registry.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Understanding the ImagePullPolicy workflow</h2>



<p>Now that you know how to set up ImagePullPolicy, let’s look at how the workflow works. The ImagePullPolicy workflow is made up of several steps that must be completed in order for an image to be pulled. These steps include verifying that the image is authorized, ensuring that it is up-to-date, and pulling it from the correct registry.</p>



<p>The image pull policy for a container in a Kubernetes deployment specifies how the container should handle image updates. There are two options for the image pull policy:</p>



<ol>
<li><strong>Always:</strong> This policy means that the container will always attempt to pull the latest version of the image from the specified container image registry.</li>



<li><strong>IfNotPresent:</strong> This policy means that the container will only pull the image from the repository if it is not already present on the host machine. If the image is present on the host, the container will use the local version of the image.</li>



<li><strong>Never:</strong> This policy is meant to tell Kubernetes to never pull down new images on behalf of a node.  Administrators need to make sure that they make images available on a node prior to pod deployment.</li>
</ol>



<p>The logical flow for the image pull policy would depend on the specific deployment and configuration, but generally, the container would check the specified image repository for updates based on the specified policy, and then either pull the updated image or use the local version as appropriate.</p>



<h2>Troubleshooting ImagePullPolicy</h2>



<p>There are a few steps you can take to troubleshoot issues with the image pull policy for a container in a Kubernetes deployment:</p>



<ol>
<li>Check the status of the container to see if it is running or has failed. You can use the kubectl describe command to get more information about the status of the container.</li>



<li>Check the container logs for any error messages or other clues about what might be causing the issue. You can use the kubectl logs command to view the container logs.</li>



<li>Check the image repository to ensure that the image is available and can be pulled. You can use the docker pull command to manually pull the image and see if there are any issues.</li>



<li>Check the container configuration to ensure that the ImagePullPolicy is set correctly and that the image repository and tag are correct.</li>



<li>If the issue persists, you may want to try redeploying the container or rolling back to a previous version of the image to see if that resolves the issue.</li>
</ol>



<p>It may also be helpful to consult the documentation or seek guidance from the maintainers of the image or the deployment if you are unable to resolve the issue on your own.</p>



<h2>Best Practices for using ImagePullPolicy</h2>



<p>Here are some best practices for using the image pull policy in Kubernetes deployments:</p>



<ol>
<li><strong>Use the IfNotPresent policy whenever possible:</strong> This policy allows you to use a local copy of the image if it exists locally, which can be faster and more reliable than pulling the image from a remote repository every time.</li>



<li><strong>Use version tags for your images:</strong> By using version tags, you can easily roll back to a previous version of an image if needed.</li>



<li><strong>Regularly check for updates to your images:</strong> It&#8217;s a good idea to regularly check for updates to your images and deploy the latest versions to ensure that you are using the most up-to-date and secure versions of your software.</li>



<li><strong>Use a private image repository:</strong> If you are using proprietary or sensitive images, it is recommended to use a private image repository to ensure that the images are secure and only accessible to authorized users.</li>



<li><strong>Use a container registry that is close to your deployment:</strong> To minimize the time it takes to pull images, it is recommended to use a container registry that is physically close to your deployment. This can be especially important for large images or deployments with many containers.</li>
</ol>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Frequently Asked Questions</h2>



<p>Below are some frequently asked questions about ImagePullPolicy:</p>


<div id="rank-math-faq" class="rank-math-block">
<div class="rank-math-list ">
<div id="faq-question-1672161780792" class="rank-math-list-item">
<h3 class="rank-math-question ">What is an ImagePullPolicy?</h3>
<div class="rank-math-answer ">

<p>An ImagePullPolicy tells Kubernetes how you should like your pods to be refreshed or made available on your nodes.  <br />A policy of Always will tell Kubernetes to never use the local cache when deploying new containers.  This can be useful if you are using the latest tag but has security implications that you should do your research on before utilizing Always.<br />A policy of IfNotPresent will tell Kubernetes to only download a new image if an image matching your specific tag is not already present on your node.  This is useful to speed up deployments, by skipping a download step.<br />A policy of Never ensures that Kubernetes will never download any new images.  It is up to the administrator to ensure that images are cached locally on the node prior to deployment.</p>

</div>
</div>
<div id="faq-question-1672161782439" class="rank-math-list-item">
<h3 class="rank-math-question ">How does ImagePullPolicy work in Kubernetes?</h3>
<div class="rank-math-answer ">

<p>In Kubernetes, the ImagePullPolicy is a property of a container in a pod that determines when and how the container image should be pulled from a registry. When a pod is created or updated, the ImagePullPolicy for each container in the pod is used to determine whether to pull the image from the registry and when to do so.</p>

</div>
</div>
<div id="faq-question-1672161792716" class="rank-math-list-item">
<h3 class="rank-math-question ">Can I specify different ImagePullPolicy values for different containers in the same pod?</h3>
<div class="rank-math-answer ">

<p>Yes, you can specify different ImagePullPolicy values for different containers in the same pod in Kubernetes. Each container in a pod can have its own ImagePullPolicy, which determines when and how the container&#8217;s image should be pulled from the registry.</p>

</div>
</div>
<div id="faq-question-1672161817204" class="rank-math-list-item">
<h3 class="rank-math-question ">Can I change the ImagePullPolicy after a pod or deployment has been created?</h3>
<div class="rank-math-answer ">

<p>Yes, simply modify your configuration files and push a new config to Kubernetes.</p>

</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>


<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>In conclusion, ImagePullPolicy is a powerful tool that can help to improve security, increase control, and improve efficiency. By setting up ImagePullPolicy correctly, following the best practices for using it, and troubleshooting any issues, you can ensure that your images are secure and that they are pulled correctly and efficiently.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Solving the &#8216;This Combination of Host and Port Requires TLS&#8217; Error in Kubernetes</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/kubernetes-port-requires-tls/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 17:15:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Kubernetes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tools]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2292</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Kubernetes is a powerful container orchestration platform that enables users to deploy, manage, and scale applications quickly and easily. It has gained a lot of favor in the DevOps community for its ability to be highly automated. Unfortunately, like any&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://kubernetes.io/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="4" title="Kubernetes" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Kubernetes</a> is a powerful container orchestration platform that enables users to deploy, manage, and scale applications quickly and easily.  It has gained a lot of favor in the <a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> community for its ability to be highly automated.  Unfortunately, like any other software, it can sometimes present cryptic errors which are hard to debug.</p>



<p>One such error is the “This combination of host and port requires TLS” error.</p>



<p>In this blog, we’ll explore what this error is, what causes it, and how to troubleshoot and fix it. We’ll also discuss some tips for avoiding this error and common mistakes to avoid when dealing with it. Lastly, we’ll look at some Kubernetes best practices for avoiding this error.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>What is the &#8216;This Combination of Host and Port Requires TLS&#8217; error?</h2>



<p>The “This combination of host and port requires TLS” error is an error in Kubernetes that occurs when a user attempts to connect to a cluster without using a secure protocol such as Transport Layer Security (TLS). It is a common error that is seen in Kubernetes clusters and is usually caused by misconfigured network settings or incorrect authentication credentials.</p>



<p>The error looks something like this:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>Error: This combination of host and port requires TLS</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The “This combination of host and port requires TLS” error is a type of TLS handshake error. TLS is a cryptographic protocol that is used to secure communications between two entities. It is a vital part of any secure network, and thus it is important to ensure that TLS is enabled and configured properly in order to avoid this error.</p>



<h2>What causes the &#8216;This Combination of Host and Port Requires TLS&#8217; error?</h2>



<p>The “This combination of host and port requires TLS” error is usually caused by one of three things: an incorrect network configuration, an incorrect authentication configuration, connecting to a secure service via HTTP instead of HTTPS, or a missing or incorrect TLS certificate.</p>



<p><strong>Incorrect network configurations</strong> can cause this error if the user is attempting to connect to the wrong host or port. This can happen if the user has mistakenly entered the wrong IP address or hostname, or if the user has entered the wrong port number. It is also possible that the user has misconfigured the network settings, such as a firewall or a proxy, which can prevent the user from connecting to the cluster.</p>



<p><strong>Incorrect authentication configurations</strong> can also cause this error. If the user’s credentials are incorrect, then the user will not be able to connect to the cluster. This can happen if the user has entered the wrong username or password, or if the user has not set up authentication correctly.</p>



<p><strong>Connecting to a secure service via HTTP instead of HTTPS</strong> can also cause this error to be displayed. Since Kubernetes services are a mapping between a load-balanced IP address and a running pod and Kubernetes can do this mapping on almost any port, your cluster is attempting to provide a helpful message telling you that the port you have configured only negotiates encrypted traffic transports.</p>



<p>Finally, a <strong>missing or incorrect TLS certificate</strong> can also cause this error. TLS certificates are used to authenticate a user and allow them to connect to the cluster. Certificates are also used to perform end-to-end encryption between a user and a Kubernetes service. If the TLS certificate is missing or incorrect, then the user will not be able to connect to the cluster.</p>



<h2>How to troubleshoot the &#8216;This Combination of Host and Port Requires TLS&#8217; error</h2>



<p>The first step in troubleshooting the “This combination of host and port requires TLS” error is to check the network configuration. Make sure that the user has entered the correct IP address or hostname, as well as the correct port number. Additionally, check to make sure that all of the network settings, such as firewalls and proxies, are configured properly.</p>



<p>The next step is to check the use of HTTPS versus HTTP in the URL being requested from the Kubernetes cluster. If your service is set up to utilize a certificate, but the request you are making is HTTP, then this error message will be returned.</p>



<p>Finally, check the TLS certificate. Make sure that the TLS certificate is present and that it is valid. If the TLS certificate is missing or incorrect, then the user will not be able to connect to the cluster.</p>



<p>Below are a few different reference examples of how you can configure Kubernetes to utilize SSL certificates on your cluster. The exact configuration will depend on your specific requirements and the characteristics of your environment.</p>



<h4>Reference Service Definition</h4>



<p>Here is an example Kubernetes service configuration that utilizes TLS certificates:</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code language-yaml"><code>apiVersion: v1
kind: Service
metadata:
  name: my-service
spec:
  type: LoadBalancer
  selector:
    app: my-app
  ports:
    - name: https
      port: 443
      targetPort: 8443
      protocol: TCP
  loadBalancerSourceRanges:
    - 0.0.0.0/0
  externalTrafficPolicy: Local
  sessionAffinity: ClientIP
  tls:
    - secretName: my-tls-certs
      termination: edge
</code></pre>



<p>This configuration defines a Kubernetes service called &#8220;my-service&#8221; that exposes port 443 to external traffic and directs it to port 8443 on the pods in the &#8220;my-app&#8221; deployment. It also specifies a TLS secret called &#8220;my-tls-certs&#8221; that contains the necessary certificates and keys for establishing a secure connection. The termination field is set to edge, which means that the service will terminate TLS at the edge of the cluster.</p>



<h4>Reference Ingress NGINX Definition</h4>



<p>Here is an example Kubernetes Ingress configuration that utilizes TLS certificates with NGINX:</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code language-yaml"><code>apiVersion: networking.k8s.io/v1
kind: Ingress
metadata:
  name: my-ingress
  annotations:
    kubernetes.io/ingress.class: nginx
    nginx.ingress.kubernetes.io/ssl-redirect: "true"
spec:
  tls:
  - secretName: my-tls-certs
  rules:
  - host: example.com
    http:
      paths:
      - path: /
        backend:
          serviceName: my-service
          servicePort: 443
</code></pre>



<p>This configuration defines an Ingress resource called &#8220;my-ingress&#8221; that routes incoming traffic to the &#8220;my-service&#8221; service on port 443. It also specifies a TLS secret called &#8220;my-tls-certs&#8221; that contains the necessary certificates and keys for establishing a secure connection. The <a target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" href="http://nginx.ingress.kubernetes.io/ssl-redirect">nginx.ingress.kubernetes.io/ssl-redirect</a> annotation tells NGINX to redirect all HTTP traffic to HTTPS.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>How to fix the &#8216;This Combination of Host and Port Requires TLS&#8217; error</h2>



<p>To fix the &#8220;This Combination of Host and Port Requires TLS&#8221; error in Kubernetes, you will need to ensure that TLS is correctly configured for the host and port combination you are trying to access. Here are the steps you can take to do this:</p>



<ol>
<li><strong>Confirm that TLS is required:</strong> Make sure that the service you are trying to access requires TLS. If it does not, then the error may be caused by a misconfiguration or a typo in your configuration.</li>



<li><strong>Check your TLS configuration:</strong> Review your TLS configuration to ensure that it is correct and complete. This includes verifying that you have the necessary certificates and keys and that you have specified the correct host and port in your configuration.</li>



<li><strong>Use the correct host and port combination: </strong>Make sure that you are using the correct host and port combination in your configuration. If you are not sure what the correct combination is, you can consult the documentation for the service you are trying to access.</li>



<li><strong>Use the correct protocol:</strong> Make sure that you are using the correct protocol (e.g. HTTPS) when accessing the service.</li>



<li><strong>Check for typos: </strong>Check your configuration for typos or other mistakes that may be causing the error.</li>



<li><strong>Restart affected services:</strong> If you have recently made changes to your TLS configuration, try restarting the affected services to see if that resolves the error.</li>



<li><strong>Consult the documentation:</strong> If you are still having trouble, consult the documentation for the service you are trying to access, as well as the documentation for Kubernetes and TLS, to see if there are any additional troubleshooting tips or requirements you need to be aware of.</li>
</ol>



<p>By following these steps, you should be able to resolve the &#8220;This Combination of Host and Port Requires TLS&#8221; error and successfully access the service.</p>



<h2>Tips for avoiding the &#8216;This Combination of Host and Port Requires TLS&#8217; error message</h2>



<ol>
<li><strong>Configure TLS correctly: </strong>Make sure that you have correctly configured TLS for your host and port combination. This includes setting up the necessary certificates and keys and specifying the correct host and port in your TLS configuration.</li>



<li><strong>Use the correct host and port combination:</strong> Double-check that you are using the correct host and port combination in your configuration. If you are not sure what the correct combination is, you can consult the documentation for the service you are trying to access.</li>



<li><strong>Use the correct protocol:</strong> Make sure that you are using the correct protocol (e.g. HTTPS) when accessing the service.</li>



<li><strong>Check for typos: </strong>Check your configuration for typos or other mistakes that may be causing the error.</li>



<li><strong>Use a linting tool:</strong> There are several linting tools specifically designed for linting Kubernetes configurations, such as kube-linter, kubeval, and conftest. These tools can check your configurations for common mistakes, syntax errors, and best practices violations.</li>



<li><strong>Use the Kubernetes API server:</strong> You can use the Kubernetes API server to validate your configurations by sending them to the server and checking for errors. To do this, you can use the <code>kubectl create</code> or <code>kubectl apply</code> commands with the <code>--dry-run</code> flag, which will send your configurations to the API server for validation without actually creating any resources.</li>



<li><strong>Use a configuration management tool:</strong> Configuration management tools like Helm, <a href="https://www.ansible.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="7" title="Ansible">Ansible</a>, and Terraform have built-in linting functionality that can check your Kubernetes configurations for errors and best practices violations.</li>



<li><strong>Consult the documentation:</strong> If you are still having trouble, consult the documentation for the service you are trying to access, as well as the documentation for Kubernetes and TLS, to see if there are any additional troubleshooting tips or requirements you need to be aware of.</li>
</ol>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>In conclusion, the “This combination of host and port requires TLS” error is an error in Kubernetes that occurs when a user attempts to connect to a cluster without using a secure protocol such as TLS. This error can be caused by an incorrect network configuration, an incorrect authentication configuration, or a missing or incorrect TLS certificate. In order to troubleshoot and fix this error, the user should check the network configuration, the authentication configuration, and the TLS certificate. Additionally, there are several tips for avoiding this error as well as some common mistakes to avoid when dealing with it. Lastly, Kubernetes provides several best practices for avoiding this error.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How ChatGPT Can Speed Up DevOps by Writing Ansible</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/how-chatgpt-can-speed-up-devops-by-writing-ansible/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 16:33:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[howto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syntax-highlight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tools]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2103</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Did you know that ChatGPT can help you write Ansible? ChatGPT utilizes the same OpenAI that GitHub Copilot uses to generate code on the fly in your favorite IDE or code editor. You can ask ChatGPT questions about how to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Did you know that <a href="https://openai.com/blog/chatgpt/" data-type="URL" data-id="https://openai.com/blog/chatgpt/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">ChatGPT</a> can help you write <a href="https://www.ansible.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="7" title="Ansible">Ansible</a>?  ChatGPT utilizes the same <a href="https://openai.com/" data-type="URL" data-id="https://openai.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">OpenAI</a> that <a href="https://github.com/features/copilot" target="_blank" data-type="URL" data-id="https://github.com/features/copilot" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">GitHub Copilot</a> uses to generate code on the fly in your favorite IDE or code editor.  You can ask ChatGPT questions about how to write code, and to the best of its ability, it will send back an answer that is usually pretty good.  This is especially useful when writing automation as part of a team focused on the <a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> methodology.</p>



<p>In DevOps you will be hit with many unfamiliar and abstract contexts simply because the space is rapidly evolving and new stuff is being introduced daily.  ChatGPT is trained on information up to 2021, so you will not get anything up the minute, but there are already a lot of problems that have been solved on the internet, but searching for them may be problematic.  </p>



<p>ChatGPT is really good, almost scary, at understanding your request and returning working code examples for you to consume.  Better yet, it is excellent at also providing descriptions about the code it just wrote to help you understand it using natural language.</p>



<p>Let&#8217;s talk about the good, the bad, and the ugly side of AI-generated code and how to use chat GPT to write some Ansible!</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>The Good: Asking ChatGPT to Create an ESXi Virtual Machine with Ansible</h2>



<p>I posted an article a few months back about the flow that I use to <a href="https://www.valewood.org/ansible-create-vmware-esxi-vm/" data-type="post" data-id="1213">create an ESXi virtual machine</a> using native ansible.  This example comes directly from my home lab setup where I have automated a complete end-to-end <a href="https://kubernetes.io/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="4" title="Kubernetes" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Kubernetes</a> deployment utilizing Ansible and kubespray.  This bit of code was extracted and abstracted to provide that example on my website.</p>



<p>Let&#8217;s see if ChatGPT could answer the question:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>Using Ansible, how would i create a virtual machine in ESXi?</p>
</blockquote>



<p>And here is the response that I got back:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>To create a virtual machine in ESXi using Ansible, you would need to use the <code>vmware_guest</code> module. This module allows you to manage virtual machines in VMware vSphere.</p>



<p>Here is an example of how you can use this module to create a new virtual machine:</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code language-yaml"><code>- name: Create a new virtual machine
  vmware_guest:
    hostname: "{{ vsphere_hostname }}"
    username: "{{ vsphere_username }}"
    password: "{{ vsphere_password }}"
    datacenter: "{{ datacenter_name }}"
    cluster: "{{ cluster_name }}"
    name: "{{ vm_name }}"
    folders: "{{ folder_name }}"
    template: "{{ template_name }}"
    state: present
    networks:
    - name: "{{ network_name }}"
      ip: "{{ ip_address }}"
      netmask: "{{ netmask }}"
      gateway: "{{ gateway }}"
      domain: "{{ domain_name }}"
</code></pre>



<p>In the above example, we are creating a new virtual machine with the specified <code>name</code> and <code>template</code> on the specified <code>datacenter</code> and <code>cluster</code>. We are also specifying the network settings for the virtual machine, such as the <code>ip</code> address, <code>netmask</code>, and <code>gateway</code>.</p>



<p>Keep in mind that this is just an example, and you may need to adjust the parameters and settings based on your specific environment and requirements.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>This is an excellent example of how to perform this task.  If you search google for this exact same search query &#8220;Using Ansible, how would I create a virtual machine in ESXi?&#8221;, the first thing that you get is some obscure ansible documentation that does not really answer the question you were after.  ChatGPT understood exactly what I was looking for and returned a good relevant explanation along with code and a description of variables that you need to define to utilize this code.</p>



<p>Now; ChatGPT is not connected to the internet, or so they claim, so you are unable to ask it for references to relevant documentation, but anyone savvy enough to read this should be able to utilize the provided code to perform a much more detailed search on google to hone in on what they want.</p>



<h3>Extending the Search</h3>



<p>I went back to ChatGPT to ask:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>How would I integrate that utilizing an existing disk image?</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Unfortunately, ChatGPT returned the exact same response as it did to my original question.  This is going to be where ChatGPT will fall short.  The example code that I linked above assumes that you have an existing disk image that you are looking to copy and register as a new virtual machine.  ChatGPT, using OpenAI v3, won&#8217;t really be able to contextually understand that use case today, but might in the future!</p>



<h3>How else could I use this?</h3>



<p>I asked ChatGPT this question next:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>How would I do that with GoLang?</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Please take note, I have not asked any other questions than what I have put in this thread.  ChatGPT is contextually understanding the conversation that we are having and is deriving its responses based on that context.  This means that it still knows that I am trying to clone out an ESXi virtual machine even though that was 2 messages back.</p>



<p>Here is the response that I got back:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>To create an ESXi virtual machine using GoLang, you would need to use the vSphere API provided by VMware. The vSphere API allows you to manage and interact with ESXi hosts and their virtual machines.</p>



<p>Here is an outline of the steps you would need to follow to create an ESXi virtual machine using GoLang:</p>



<ol>
<li>Install and configure the GoLang programming language on your computer.</li>



<li>Use the vSphere API to connect to your ESXi host and authenticate with the host.</li>



<li>Use the vSphere API to create a new virtual machine on the ESXi host. This will involve specifying the hardware configuration for the virtual machine, such as the amount of memory and CPU resources to allocate, as well as the virtual disk size and format.</li>



<li>Use the vSphere API to configure the network settings for the virtual machine, such as the network adapter type and network settings.</li>



<li>Use the vSphere API to install an operating system on the virtual machine. This will involve booting the virtual machine from an ISO image and installing the operating system according to the instructions provided by the operating system vendor.</li>



<li>Use the vSphere API to start the virtual machine and verify that it is running correctly.</li>
</ol>



<p>Overall, creating an ESXi virtual machine using GoLang will require a good understanding of both the GoLang programming language and the vSphere API. It may also require some knowledge of virtualization and ESXi host management.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>This response is interesting.  With the Ansible response, code was provided.  With the GoLang response, steps were provided.  This shows a bit of the inconsistency still left to shake out of the system.</p>



<p>I pivoted a bit and asked:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>How would I do this with Code?</p>
</blockquote>



<p>And the response looks much better!</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote go">
<p>Here is an example of how you might use the vSphere API in GoLang to create a new virtual machine on an ESXi host:</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code language-go"><code>import "github.com/vmware/govmomi/vim25/types" // Import the vSphere API package

// Connect to the ESXi host and authenticate
client, err := govmomi.NewClient(ctx, esxiURL, true)
if err != nil {
    // Handle error
}

// Create a new virtual machine on the ESXi host
vm, err := object.NewVirtualMachine(client.Client, vmConfig)
if err != nil {
    // Handle error
}

// Configure the virtual machine's hardware settings
err = vm.WaitForIP(ctx)
if err != nil {
    // Handle error
}

// Install an operating system on the virtual machine
err = vm.Create(ctx, pool, spec)
if err != nil {
    // Handle error
}

// Start the virtual machine and verify that it is running
err = vm.PowerOn(ctx)
if err != nil {
    // Handle error
}
</code></pre>



<p>This is just an example of how you might use the vSphere API in GoLang to create an ESXi virtual machine. There may be other ways to accomplish this task using the vSphere API, and your specific implementation may vary depending on your specific requirements and use case. I recommend consulting the vSphere API documentation and GoLang documentation for more information and guidance.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Pretty impressive that you can get 2 different results for the same tasks in different programming languages all provided by the same AI language model.  Now this response is extremely basic and I would not run it in production anywhere without a lot more inspection and real error handling, but it is perfect to get someone going in a space they are unfamiliar with!</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>The Bad: Asking ChatGPT to Convert Text to JSON with Ansible</h2>



<p>Things here get a little bit messier. I have an article <a href="https://www.valewood.org/ansible-text-to-json/" data-type="post" data-id="1187">here</a> to help people understand how to convert a text file to JSON using ansible.  This post was inspired by someone asking the exact same question over on Reddit, and rather than answering it there, I figured it was a good opportunity to write something a bit more long-form that was easier to find that an obscure Reddit thread.  </p>



<p>Let&#8217;s see if ChatGPT could answer this relatively simple question on doing the exact same conversion.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>Using Ansible, how would i convert a text file to JSON and write it to a new file?</p>
</blockquote>



<p>And here is the response that I got back:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>To convert a text file to JSON using Ansible, you can use the <code>json_query</code> filter to extract the desired data from the text file and then use the <code>to_json</code> filter to convert it to JSON format. You can then use the <code>file</code> module to write the JSON data to a new file.</p>



<p>Here is an example playbook that shows how this can be done:</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code language-yaml"><code>---
- hosts: localhost
  tasks:
    - name: Read the text file
      delegate_to: localhost
      slurp:
        src: "path/to/text/file"
      register: text_file

    - name: Convert the text file to JSON
      delegate_to: localhost
      set_fact:
        json_data: "{{ text_file.content | json_query(query) | to_json }}"

    - name: Write the JSON data to a new file
      delegate_to: localhost
      file:
        path: "path/to/new/file.json"
        mode: "0644"
        state: "touch"
        content: "{{ json_data }}"
</code></pre>



<p>In this example, the <code>json_query</code> filter is used to extract the desired data from the text file using the <code>query</code> variable. You can use any valid JSON query to extract the data you need. The extracted data is then converted to JSON format using the <code>to_json</code> filter and saved in a variable called <code>json_data</code>.</p>



<p>Finally, the <code>file</code> module is used to create a new file called <code>file.json</code> and write the JSON data to it. You can customize the path, permissions, and other attributes of the file as needed.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Pretty neat!  Breaking this down a bit, ChatGPT first provides a text-based description of what it is going to do.  The problem is, <code>query</code> is currently not a defined variable meaning that this code is not actually going to run.  </p>



<p>Structurally, this code looks awesome and looks fully functional, but in the end, is not a good representation of a working Ansible that will actually produce the result you are looking for.  If you are looking for a more correct example, please follow the link that I provided above.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>The Ugly: The Evolving Landscape</h2>



<p>Right now ChatGPT is a bit slow to respond and is very popular meaning that it is overloaded frequently.  There is also no guarantee that ChatGPT will remain free and open forever.  It is currently pulling from a dataset that is powering a paid product called <a href="https://www.github.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="6" title="Github" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">GitHub</a> CoPilot meaning that OpenAI has the incentive to lock this functionality down in the future.  </p>



<p>While working on this piece, I had to put things down and come back the next day to finish up.  I decided to run a few questions against ChatGPT again to see what kind of response I would get.  The reality is, they had changed.  ChatGPT engineers are constantly doing training tweaks to the AI to better respond to requests, meaning you will get different responses each time you use it.</p>



<p>I think that this is a very fun toy while it lasts, but I would not consider wrapping this into any kind of mission-critical environment just yet.  But, if you are an aspiring engineer that is having trouble sourcing any kind of kickstart material, or you are just curious, ride this train while the ride is free!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Solve Your Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff Woes in No Time</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/kubernetes-crashloopbackoff-error/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 17:29:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[howto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kubernetes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tools]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2065</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you are running a Kubernetes cluster, chances are you&#8217;ve come across the dreaded &#8216;CrashLoopBackoff&#8217; error. This error can be incredibly frustrating, as it can be difficult to troubleshoot and solve. In this article, we&#8217;ll be discussing everything you need&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>If you are running a <a href="https://kubernetes.io/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="4" title="Kubernetes" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Kubernetes</a> cluster, chances are you&#8217;ve come across the dreaded &#8216;CrashLoopBackoff&#8217; error. This error can be incredibly frustrating, as it can be difficult to troubleshoot and solve.</p>



<p>In this article, we&#8217;ll be discussing everything you need to know about Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff, including what causes it, how to troubleshoot it, and how to solve it.</p>



<p>So, if you&#8217;re ready to get your Kubernetes cluster back up and running in no time, read on!</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Understanding Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff</h2>



<p>Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff is an error that occurs when an application running in a Kubernetes cluster fails to start or restart successfully. The issue you are having is right in the name; your application is crashing in a loop and Kubernetes is using a backoff algorithm so that it doesn&#8217;t try to restart your failing app at lightspeed.</p>



<p>CrashLoopBackoff is an algorithmic protection mechanism for Kubernetes clusters. A backoff loop usually happens due to an issue with the application itself, or underlying infrastructure. When this error occurs, Kubernetes will try to restart the application several times, and if it fails all of those attempts, it will log the &#8216;CrashLoopBackoff&#8217; error.</p>



<p>At its core, Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff is simply a way for Kubernetes to notify you that something is wrong with an application in your cluster. It is not necessarily an indication of a problem with Kubernetes itself, so it is important to understand what is causing the issue in order to properly troubleshoot and solve it.</p>



<h2>What Causes Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff?</h2>



<p>Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff can be caused by a number of different issues, ranging from application issues to underlying infrastructure issues. The most common causes of Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff are:</p>



<ul>
<li>Application issues such as bugs, memory leaks, or incompatible configurations.</li>



<li>Infrastructure issues such as insufficient resources, networking issues, or misconfigured storage.</li>



<li>Failing dependencies can cause a backoff loop to happen as well. If your app requires a database, but the database server is down the app may fail rapidly and Kubernetes will report a CrashLoopBackoff error.</li>



<li>An incorrect or missing API key or authentication credentials.</li>



<li>Issues with the Kubernetes API server or the Kubernetes control plane.</li>
</ul>



<p>It is important to understand what is causing the CrashLoopBackoff in order to properly troubleshoot and solve the issue.</p>



<h2>How to Troubleshoot Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff</h2>



<p>When it comes to troubleshooting Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff, the first step is to identify what is causing the issue.</p>



<p>To do this, you should start by looking at the logs for the application. The logs should provide insight into what is causing the CrashLoopBackoff, such as an application bug or a misconfigured resource. Once you have identified the cause of the issue, you can begin troubleshooting the problem.</p>



<p>Next, check if the application has been configured correctly, if the resource allocations are sufficient, and if the application is running in the correct environment. You should also check for any networking or storage issues that could be causing the CrashLoopBackoff.</p>



<p>Here is a list of checks to work through when diagnosing CrashLoopBackoff errors:</p>



<ol>
<li><strong>App logs: </strong>When experiencing a CrashLoopBackoff, there are a few things you can look for in the application logs that may help you troubleshoot the issue. First, you can check for any error messages that may indicate what is causing the CrashLoopBackoff. This could be anything from a syntax error in your code to an issue with a specific dependency or resource that your application is trying to access. These resources could be services such as databases or API endpoints where access may not be properly configured.</li>



<li><strong>Kubernetes Events: </strong>When experiencing a CrashLoopBackoff scenario in Kubernetes, there are a few events that you should evaluate to help troubleshoot the issue. First, you should check the events for your pod to see if there are any error messages that indicate what is causing the CrashLoopBackoff. This could be anything from a syntax error in your code to an issue with a specific dependency or resource that your application is trying to access. Additionally, you should check the events for the kubelet on the node where your pod is running to see if there are any messages related to the CrashLoopBackoff itself, such as a message indicating that the kubelet is restarting your pod due to the CrashLoopBackoff condition. Finally, you should check the events for the Kubernetes control plane components, such as the API server and the scheduler, to see if there are any messages that could provide insight into the cause of the CrashLoopBackoff.</li>



<li><strong>Run the command &#8220;kubectl describe pod -n &lt;namespace> &lt;pod name>&#8221;</strong>: <code>kubectl describe pod</code> provides detailed information about a specific Kubernetes pod. This information includes the pod&#8217;s name, namespace, and status, as well as the node on which it is running and the containers that are included in the pod. Additionally, <code>kubectl describe pod</code> provides metadata about the pod, such as labels and annotations, and it also displays any events that have been associated with the pod. This can be useful for troubleshooting issues with your Kubernetes clusters, as it provides a detailed view of the pod and its components.</li>



<li><strong>Enable pod debugging:</strong> This may not be applicable everywhere, but if the application supports debugging environment variables then you should enable this to get more logs from the pod itself. This may show what is causing the CrashLoopBackoff errors to occur.</li>



<li><strong>Investigate pod replicas: </strong>If you have multiple replicas, you may have a running replica pod that you can investigate to compare with your pod that is in a CrashLoopBackoff state. In my experience, if there is at least one running replica, then you would be looking for something more environmental such as improperly configured PVCs, networking, resource allocation, etc.</li>



<li><strong>kube-dns:</strong> To troubleshoot issues with kube-dns in Kubernetes, you can use the <code>kubectl</code> command-line tool to check the status of the kube-dns service and its associated components. First, you can use the <code>kubectl get pods</code> command to see if the kube-dns pods are running and to check their status. If the pods are not running, you can use the <code>kubectl describe pod</code> command to get more information about the issue and to see if there are any error messages that can help you diagnose the problem. Additionally, you can use the <code>kubectl logs</code> command to view the logs for the kube-dns pods and look for any error messages that may provide insight into the issue.</li>



<li><strong>Environment variables: </strong>When investigating CrashLoopBackoff errors, environment variable misconfiguration is a quick and easy place to validate. Ensure that all of the correct environment variables are set for your application. Check the case (uppercase and lowercase) of the variable names if your application is case-sensitive. Check that secrets are mapped properly to env vars if you are mapping secrets.</li>



<li><strong>Secrets:</strong> Keeping secrets safe in Kubernetes is very important. Out of the box, secrets are base64 encoded strings which is not very secure. There are a lot of great mechanisms out there to provide better security. Most of these will require definitions around access to secrets to ensure only resources with delegated access can decrypt and utilize them. Check the documentation for the provider you are using to ensure things delegation are configured correctly.</li>



<li><strong>Ports:</strong> If you are experiencing CrashLoopBackoff errors and suspect that the issue may be related to your port configuration, there are a few steps you can take to diagnose the problem. First, you can check the logs for your application to see if there are any messages that indicate a problem with the port configuration. For example, if your application is unable to bind to the specified port, you may see an error message in the logs indicating this issue. Additionally, you can use the <code>netstat</code> command to view a list of the currently open ports on your system and see if the port that your application is trying to use is already in use by another process. If the port is already in use, you will need to either configure your application to use a different port or stop the other process that is using the port in order to resolve the issue.</li>



<li><strong>Health Probes:</strong> If you are experiencing CrashLoopBackoff errors and suspect that the issue may be related to health probes, there are a few steps you can take to diagnose the problem. First, you can check the logs for your application to see if there are any messages that indicate a problem with the health probes. For example, if your application is failing the health probe because it is unable to connect to a required dependency, you may see an error message in the logs indicating this issue. Additionally, you can use the <code>kubectl</code> command-line tool to view the status of the health probes for your application. For example, you can use the <code>kubectl</code> describe pod command to see the results of the health probes for your pod, and you can use the <code>kubectl</code> describe deployment command to see the overall health of your deployment. This information can help you determine whether the health probes are failing and why, which can provide insight into the root cause of the CrashLoopBackoff errors.</li>



<li><strong>Readiness Probes:</strong> If you are experiencing CrashLoopBackoff errors and suspect that the issue may be related to readiness probes, there are a few steps you can take to diagnose the problem. First, you can check the logs for your application to see if there are any messages that indicate a problem with the readiness probes. For example, if your application is failing the readiness probe because it is unable to connect to a required dependency, you may see an error message in the logs indicating this issue. Additionally, you can use the <code>kubectl</code> command-line tool to view the status of the readiness probes for your application. For example, you can use the <code>kubectl</code> describe pod command to see the results of the readiness probes for your pod, and you can use the <code>kubectl</code> describe deployment command to see the overall readiness of your deployment. This information can help you determine whether the readiness probes are failing and why, which can provide insight into the root cause of the CrashLoopBackoff errors.</li>



<li><strong>Node Health: </strong>To check the health of a Kubernetes worker node, you can use the kubectl command-line tool to view the status of the node and its associated components. First, you can use the <code>kubectl</code> get nodes command to see a list of all the nodes in your cluster, along with their status. This will let you see which nodes are healthy and which ones may be experiencing issues. You can then use the <code>kubectl</code> describe node command to get more detailed information about a specific node, including its overall status and any events that have occurred on the node. This information can help you determine whether the node is healthy and identify any potential issues that may be affecting its performance.</li>
</ol>



<p>Once you have identified and resolved the underlying issue, you can attempt to restart the application. If the restart is successful, the CrashLoopBackoff should be resolved. If the restart is unsuccessful, you may need to look into other potential issues.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Step-by-Step Guide for Solving Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff</h2>



<p>If you&#8217;re looking for a step-by-step guide for solving Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff, here&#8217;s what you need to do:</p>



<ol>
<li>Identify the cause of the CrashLoopBackoff by looking at the application logs.</li>



<li>Check if the application has been configured correctly, if the resources are sufficient, and if the application is running in the correct environment.</li>



<li>Check for any networking or storage issues that could be causing the CrashLoopBackoff.</li>



<li>Attempt to restart the application.</li>



<li>If the restart is unsuccessful, look into other potential issues.</li>
</ol>



<p>By following these steps, you should be able to resolve the CrashLoopBackoff in no time.</p>



<h2>Common Mistakes to Avoid when Troubleshooting Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff</h2>



<p>When troubleshooting Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff, there are a few common mistakes that you should avoid.</p>



<p>First, it is important to avoid making assumptions about the cause of the CrashLoopBackoff. It is easy to jump to conclusions and assume that the issue is caused by a particular issue, but it is important to look into all potential causes before attempting to solve the issue.</p>



<p>Second, it is important to avoid making changes to the application or the Kubernetes cluster without first understanding the cause of the issue. Making changes without understanding the issue can lead to further complications and make the issue more difficult to troubleshoot.</p>



<p>Finally, it is important to avoid blindly restarting applications or the Kubernetes cluster. Restarting applications or the cluster without understanding the cause of the CrashLoopBackoff can mask the issue and make it more difficult to troubleshoot.</p>



<h2>Tools for Troubleshooting Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff</h2>



<p>Fortunately, there are a number of tools available to help you troubleshoot Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff.</p>



<p>The most useful tool for troubleshooting CrashLoopBackoff is the Kubernetes Dashboard. The Dashboard provides a graphical view of the cluster, allowing you to quickly identify and diagnose the issue. Additionally, the Dashboard provides helpful resources such as logs, metrics, and events that can be used to further investigate the cause of the CrashLoopBackoff.</p>



<p>Other useful tools for troubleshooting Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff include kubectl, the Kubernetes CLI, and the Kubernetes API server. These tools provide detailed information about the cluster, allowing you to quickly identify and diagnose the issue.</p>



<h2>Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff Solutions</h2>



<p>If you&#8217;ve been able to identify and resolve the underlying issue, the CrashLoopBackoff should be resolved. However, if you are still unable to resolve the issue, there are a few solutions that you can try.</p>



<p>One solution is to scale up the resources for the application. By scaling up the resources, you can ensure that the application has enough resources to run properly.</p>



<p>Another solution is to use a Kubernetes-native application such as Kubeless or Knative. These applications are designed to run on Kubernetes and can help to reduce the chances of the CrashLoopBackoff occurring.</p>



<p>Finally, you can also use a managed service such as Google Kubernetes Engine or <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/get-started/azure-portal" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="20" title="Azure" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Azure</a> Kubernetes Service. These services provide managed Kubernetes clusters that are optimized for performance and reliability, reducing the chances of the CrashLoopBackoff occurring.</p>



<h2>How to Avoid Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff</h2>



<p>The best way to avoid Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff is to ensure that the applications and infrastructure are configured correctly and that the resources are sufficient. Additionally, it is important to use Kubernetes-native applications or managed services to ensure optimal performance and reliability.</p>



<p>Additionally, it is important to monitor the applications and the Kubernetes cluster for any issues. By monitoring the applications and the cluster, you can quickly identify and diagnose any issues that could lead to the CrashLoopBackoff.</p>



<p>Finally, it is important to keep the applications and the Kubernetes cluster up-to-date with the latest patches and updates. Outdated applications and clusters can lead to instability and can increase the chances of the CrashLoopBackoff occurring.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Q&amp;A Section</h2>


<div id="rank-math-faq" class="rank-math-block">
<div class="rank-math-list ">
<div id="faq-question-1670693281509" class="rank-math-list-item">
<h3 class="rank-math-question "> What is Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff?</h3>
<div class="rank-math-answer ">

<p>Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff is an error that occurs when an application running in a Kubernetes cluster fails to start or restart successfully. This usually happens due to an issue with the application itself, or an underlying infrastructure issue.</p>

</div>
</div>
<div id="faq-question-1670693291066" class="rank-math-list-item">
<h3 class="rank-math-question ">What causes Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff?</h3>
<div class="rank-math-answer ">

<p>Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff can be caused by a number of different issues, ranging from application issues to underlying infrastructure issues. The most common causes of Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff are application issues such as bugs, memory leaks, or incompatible configurations; infrastructure issues such as insufficient resources, networking issues, or misconfigured storage; an incorrect or missing API key or authentication credentials; and issues with the Kubernetes API server or the Kubernetes control plane.</p>

</div>
</div>
<div id="faq-question-1670693303994" class="rank-math-list-item">
<h3 class="rank-math-question ">How do I troubleshoot Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff?</h3>
<div class="rank-math-answer ">

<p>When troubleshooting Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff, the first step is to identify what is causing the issue. To do this, you should start by looking at the logs for the application. The logs should provide insight into what is causing the CrashLoopBackoff, such as an application bug or a misconfigured resource. Once you have identified the cause of the issue, you can begin troubleshooting the problem.</p>

</div>
</div>
<div id="faq-question-1670693313441" class="rank-math-list-item">
<h3 class="rank-math-question ">How do I solve Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff?</h3>
<div class="rank-math-answer ">

<p>If you have identified and resolved the underlying issue, the CrashLoopBackoff should be resolved. If you are still unable to resolve the issue, you can try scaling up the resources for the application, using a Kubernetes-native application such as Kubeless or Knative, or using a managed service such as Google Kubernetes Engine or Azure Kubernetes Service.</p>

</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>


<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff can be a frustrating and confusing error to troubleshoot and solve. However, with the right knowledge and tools, it is possible to quickly identify and resolve the issue.</p>



<p>In this article, we discussed everything you need to know about Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff, including what causes it, how to troubleshoot it, and how to solve it. We also discussed some of the common mistakes to avoid when troubleshooting CrashLoopBackoff, and some of the tools that can be used to troubleshoot the issue.</p>



<p>If you follow the steps outlined in this article, you should be able to quickly identify and resolve the CrashLoopBackoff in no time. Good luck!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>DevOps Interview with ChatGPT</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/devops-interview-with-chatgpt/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 20:15:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[interview]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2040</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[ChatGPT is a chatbot built on top of OpenAI. Using information from various sources, OpenAI is a language-processing model which can &#8216;learn&#8217; from natural language and provides responses in a variety of different formats. ChatGPT is an implementation of OpenAI&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://openai.com/blog/chatgpt/" data-type="URL" data-id="https://openai.com/blog/chatgpt/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">ChatGPT</a> is a chatbot built on top of OpenAI.  Using information from various sources, <a href="https://openai.com/" data-type="URL" data-id="https://openai.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">OpenAI</a> is a language-processing model which can &#8216;learn&#8217; from natural language and provides responses in a variety of different formats.  ChatGPT is an implementation of OpenAI which is meant to hold a natural conversation via chat about any topic.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>We’ve trained a model called ChatGPT which interacts in a conversational way. The dialogue format makes it possible for ChatGPT to answer followup questions, admit its mistakes, challenge incorrect premises, and reject inappropriate requests. ChatGPT is a sibling model to <a href="https://openai.com/blog/instruction-following/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">InstructGPT</a>, which is trained to follow an instruction in a prompt and provide a detailed&nbsp;response.</p>
<cite>https://openai.com/blog/chatgpt/</cite></blockquote>



<p>Below is the interview I conducted with ChatGPT about <a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a>!  All questions were asked exactly how they are displayed below.  Answers were taken directly from ChatGPT without any modifications.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>The ChatGPT DevOps Interview</h2>



<h3>Question: I was wondering if I could interview you about DevOps?</h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote block-quote-gray">
<p>Sure! I&#8217;d be happy to answer any questions you have about DevOps. DevOps is a software development methodology that combines software development (Dev) and information technology operations (Ops) to shorten the development life cycle and provide continuous delivery with high software quality. This approach aims to bring development and operations teams together to improve collaboration, automate processes, and speed up the delivery of new software features. Some of the key principles of DevOps include automation, continuous integration and delivery, collaboration, and monitoring.</p>



<p>Would you like to know more about specific aspects of DevOps? I can provide more information on topics such as the benefits of DevOps, common DevOps tools and practices, and how to get started with DevOps in your organization. Let me know if there&#8217;s anything specific you&#8217;d like to know!</p>
</blockquote>



<h3>Question: Yes, let&#8217;s start by talking about the benefits of DevOps. What do you think are the major benefits of adopting DevOps into an organization&#8217;s software development life cycle?</h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>Some of the major benefits of adopting DevOps into an organization&#8217;s software development life cycle include:</p>



<ul>
<li>Improved collaboration and communication: DevOps brings together development and operations teams to work closely together, improving collaboration and communication. This can lead to better alignment between teams and a more efficient software development process.</li>



<li>Faster time to market: By automating processes and integrating development and operations, DevOps can help organizations deliver new software features faster. This can give organizations a competitive advantage and allow them to quickly respond to changing market conditions.</li>



<li>Increased software quality: DevOps emphasizes continuous testing and monitoring, which can help identify and fix bugs and other issues early in the development process. This can result in higher-quality software and fewer issues in production.</li>



<li>Increased agility and flexibility: DevOps enables organizations to quickly and easily adapt to changing business needs and market conditions. By automating processes and integrating development and operations, organizations can quickly respond to new opportunities and challenges.</li>
</ul>



<p>Overall, the benefits of DevOps can help organizations improve collaboration, deliver new software features faster, increase software quality, and increase agility and flexibility. These benefits can help organizations stay competitive and respond quickly to changing market conditions.</p>
</blockquote>



<h3>Question: How does DevOps improve collaboration and communication?</h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>DevOps improves collaboration and communication by bringing together development and operations teams to work closely together. In a traditional software development process, these teams often work in silos, with little collaboration or communication. This can lead to misalignment, misunderstandings, and delays in the development process.</p>



<p>With DevOps, development and operations teams work together from the start of the development process. They share the same goals and work towards a common vision. This can improve collaboration and communication, and help teams align their efforts towards a common goal.</p>



<p>Additionally, DevOps emphasizes collaboration and communication throughout the development process. This can include regular meetings, real-time communication tools, and other collaborative practices. These practices can help teams stay aligned and on track, and quickly resolve any issues that arise.</p>



<p>Overall, by bringing development and operations teams together and emphasizing collaboration and communication, DevOps can help organizations improve collaboration and communication throughout the development process.</p>
</blockquote>



<h3>Question: What methods or ceremonies can a DevOps team use to improve collaboration and communication?</h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>There are several methods or ceremonies that a DevOps team can use to improve collaboration and communication. Some examples include:</p>



<ul>
<li>Regular meetings: One of the most effective ways to improve collaboration and communication is to hold regular meetings. These meetings can be used to discuss progress, share updates, and resolve any issues that arise. They can be held daily, weekly, or at other intervals, depending on the needs of the team.</li>



<li>Collaborative tools: Collaborative tools can also be used to improve collaboration and communication. These tools can include real-time communication platforms, project management tools, and other tools that enable teams to work together and share information.</li>



<li>Pair programming: Pair programming is a technique in which two developers work together on the same code. This can help improve collaboration and communication, as well as promote knowledge sharing and mentoring.</li>



<li>Continuous integration and delivery: Continuous integration and delivery (CI/CD) is a key practice in DevOps that involves automatically building, testing, and deploying code. This can help improve collaboration and communication by enabling teams to quickly and easily share code and integrate their work.</li>
</ul>



<p>Overall, there are many different methods and ceremonies that a DevOps team can use to improve collaboration and communication. These practices can help teams work together more effectively, align their efforts towards a common goal, and quickly resolve any issues that arise.</p>
</blockquote>



<h3>Question: How does DevOps promote a faster time to market?</h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>DevOps promotes a faster time to market by automating processes and integrating development and operations. In a traditional software development process, there are often long delays between the development and deployment of new software features. This can result in slower time to market and reduced competitiveness.</p>



<p>With DevOps, development and operations teams work closely together and automate as many processes as possible. This can include automating the build, testing, and deployment of code. By automating these processes, teams can quickly and easily deliver new software features to market.</p>



<p>Additionally, DevOps emphasizes continuous integration and delivery (CI/CD), which enables teams to regularly and automatically build, test, and deploy code. This can help teams deliver new software features faster, and reduce the time it takes to get new features to market.</p>



<p>Overall, by automating processes and emphasizing continuous integration and delivery, DevOps can help organizations deliver new software features faster and improve their time to market. This can give organizations a competitive advantage and allow them to quickly respond to changing market conditions.</p>
</blockquote>



<h3>Question: How do continuous integration and delivery reduce the time it takes to deliver new features to the market?</h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>Continuous integration and delivery (CI/CD) is a key practice in DevOps that involves automatically building, testing, and deploying code. This can help reduce the time it takes to deliver new features to the market in several ways:</p>



<ul>
<li>Automation: CI/CD automates the build, testing, and deployment of code, which can significantly reduce the time it takes to get new features to market. By automating these processes, teams can quickly and easily deliver new software features, without the need for manual processes and interventions.</li>



<li>Early identification and resolution of issues: CI/CD also enables teams to quickly identify and resolve issues in the code. By automatically building, testing, and deploying code on a regular basis, teams can identify and fix bugs and other issues early in the development process. This can help reduce the time it takes to get new features to market, and improve the overall quality of the software.</li>



<li>Faster feedback and iteration: CI/CD also enables teams to get feedback on new features faster. By automatically building, testing, and deploying code, teams can quickly see how their changes are working in production, and iterate on them based on feedback. This can help teams deliver new features faster, and improve the overall quality of the software.</li>
</ul>



<p>Overall, by automating the build, testing, and deployment of code, CI/CD can help teams deliver new features to market faster, and improve the overall quality of the software. This can give organizations a competitive advantage and allow them to quickly respond to changing market conditions.</p>
</blockquote>



<h3>Question: How does DevOps increase software quality?</h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>DevOps increases software quality by emphasizing continuous testing and monitoring. In a traditional software development process, testing is often done at the end of the development process, which can result in a large number of bugs and other issues being discovered only after the software has been released.</p>



<p>With DevOps, teams continuously test and monitor their code throughout the development process. This can include running automated tests on a regular basis, as well as using tools to monitor the performance and stability of the software in production. By continuously testing and monitoring their code, teams can identify and fix issues early in the development process, before they become major problems.</p>



<p>Additionally, DevOps emphasizes collaboration and communication between development and operations teams. This can help teams quickly identify and resolve issues, and improve the overall quality of the software.</p>



<p>Overall, by emphasizing continuous testing and monitoring, and promoting collaboration and communication, DevOps can help teams deliver higher-quality software and reduce the number of issues in production. This can improve the user experience and the overall success of the software.</p>
</blockquote>



<h3>Question: How do DevOps teams continuously test and monitor their code throughout the development process?</h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>DevOps teams continuously test and monitor their code throughout the development process using a variety of tools and practices. Some examples include:</p>



<ul>
<li>Automated testing: Automated testing is a key practice in DevOps that involves running automated tests on a regular basis. These tests can include unit tests, integration tests, and other types of tests that validate the functionality and performance of the software. By running automated tests on a regular basis, teams can quickly and easily identify and fix issues in the code.</li>



<li>Continuous integration and delivery (CI/CD): Continuous integration and delivery (CI/CD) is a key practice in DevOps that involves automatically building, testing, and deploying code. This can help teams continuously test and monitor their code, by automatically running tests and deploying code on a regular basis.</li>



<li>Monitoring tools: DevOps teams also use monitoring tools to continuously monitor the performance and stability of their software in production. These tools can track key metrics such as response time, error rates, and resource utilization, and alert teams when issues arise. By continuously monitoring their software, teams can quickly identify and resolve issues, and improve the overall quality of the software.</li>
</ul>



<p>Overall, DevOps teams use a combination of automated testing, CI/CD, and monitoring tools to continuously test and monitor their code throughout the development process. This can help teams deliver higher-quality software and reduce the number of issues in production.</p>
</blockquote>



<h3>Question: How does DevOps help an organization increase agility and flexibility with its products?</h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>DevOps helps organizations increase agility and flexibility with their products by automating processes and integrating development and operations. In a traditional software development process, there are often long delays and bottlenecks in the development process, which can make it difficult for organizations to quickly and easily respond to changing business needs and market conditions.</p>



<p>With DevOps, development and operations teams work closely together and automate as many processes as possible. This can include automating the build, testing, and deployment of code, as well as automating other processes such as provisioning and configuration management. By automating these processes, teams can quickly and easily adapt to changing business needs and market conditions.</p>



<p>Additionally, DevOps emphasizes continuous integration and delivery (CI/CD), which enables teams to regularly and automatically build, test, and deploy code. This can help teams quickly and easily iterate on their products, and respond to feedback and changes in the market.</p>



<p>Overall, by automating processes and emphasizing continuous integration and delivery, DevOps can help organizations increase their agility and flexibility with their products. This can enable organizations to quickly and easily respond to changing business needs and market conditions, and stay competitive.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h3>Segue: Thank you for answering my questions so far!</h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>You&#8217;re welcome! I&#8217;m glad I could help. Is there anything else you&#8217;d like to know about DevOps? I&#8217;m here to answer any questions you may have.</p>
</blockquote>



<h3>Question: What are some of the biggest challenges an organization can face when going through a transformation to adopt DevOps as their technology delivery methodology?</h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>Some of the biggest challenges an organization can face when going through a transformation to adopt DevOps as their technology delivery methodology include:</p>



<ul>
<li>Culture and mindset: One of the biggest challenges in adopting DevOps is changing the culture and mindset of the organization. DevOps requires a shift away from siloed teams and towards collaboration and communication. This can be a significant change for organizations, and requires a commitment to embracing new ways of working.</li>



<li>Resistance to change: Another challenge in adopting DevOps is overcoming resistance to change. Many organizations are comfortable with their existing processes and ways of working, and may be resistant to changing them. This can make it difficult to implement DevOps, and may require leadership and management support to overcome.</li>



<li>Lack of skills and expertise: Another challenge in adopting DevOps is a lack of skills and expertise. DevOps requires a combination of development, operations, and other technical skills, and many organizations may not have the necessary expertise in-house. This can require organizations to invest in training and hiring new talent, or partnering with external organizations that have the necessary skills and expertise.</li>



<li>Integration with existing systems and processes: Another challenge in adopting DevOps is integrating it with existing systems and processes. DevOps requires a significant amount of automation and integration, and organizations may have legacy systems and processes that are difficult to integrate with. This can require organizations to invest in new technologies and tools, and may require significant planning and coordination to implement successfully.</li>
</ul>



<p>Overall, there are many challenges that organizations can face when going through a transformation to adopt DevOps. These challenges can include cultural and mindset changes, resistance to change, a lack of skills and expertise, and integration with existing systems and processes. Organizations need to carefully plan and manage their DevOps transformation in order to overcome these challenges and achieve success.</p>
</blockquote>



<h3>Question: Why are culture and mindset important when adopting DevOps?</h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>Culture and mindset are important when adopting DevOps because DevOps requires a significant shift in how organizations approach software development. In a traditional software development process, teams often work in silos, with little collaboration or communication. This can lead to misalignment, misunderstandings, and delays in the development process.</p>



<p>DevOps, on the other hand, emphasizes collaboration and communication between development and operations teams. This requires a shift in culture and mindset, from siloed teams to cross-functional teams that work together towards a common goal. This can be a significant change for organizations, and requires a commitment to embracing new ways of working.</p>



<p>Additionally, DevOps requires a mindset of continuous improvement and experimentation. This means that teams need to be open to trying new approaches and learning from failures, in order to continually improve the software development process. This can be a significant change for many organizations, and requires a commitment to learning and experimentation.</p>



<p>Overall, culture and mindset are important when adopting DevOps because DevOps requires a shift in how organizations approach software development. This requires a commitment to collaboration, communication, and continuous improvement, and can be a significant change for many organizations.</p>
</blockquote>



<h3>Question: What happens to an organization when resistance to change happens in the DevOps adoption process?</h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>When resistance to change happens in the DevOps adoption process, it can make it difficult for organizations to successfully implement DevOps. Resistance to change can come from many different sources, pink flamingos essay reflection.</p>



<p>If resistance to change is not addressed, it can lead to delays and problems in the DevOps adoption process. For example, teams may be reluctant to adopt new practices and tools, or may be resistant to collaborating with other teams. This can lead to misunderstandings, conflicts, and delays in the development process.</p>



<p>Additionally, resistance to change can lead to a lack of buy-in and support for the DevOps adoption process. This can make it difficult to secure the necessary resources and support to successfully implement DevOps, and may require leadership and management support to overcome.</p>



<p>Overall, when resistance to change happens in the DevOps adoption process, it can lead to delays, conflicts, and a lack of support for the adoption process. This can make it difficult for organizations to successfully implement DevOps, and may require leadership and management support to overcome.</p>
</blockquote>



<h3>Question: Why are skill and expertise important when adopting DevOps?</h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>Skills and expertise are important when adopting DevOps because DevOps requires a combination of development, operations, and other technical skills. In a traditional software development process, development and operations teams often have different skills and expertise, and may not be equipped to work together effectively.</p>



<p>DevOps, on the other hand, requires development and operations teams to work closely together, and to have a broad range of skills and expertise. This can include skills in areas such as automation, continuous integration and delivery, and monitoring and observability. Without these skills, teams may struggle to implement DevOps effectively, and may not be able to take full advantage of its benefits.</p>



<p>Additionally, DevOps emphasizes learning and experimentation, which requires teams to have the skills and expertise to quickly learn and adapt to new technologies and approaches. This can be a significant challenge for organizations, and may require them to invest in training and development, or to hire new talent with the necessary skills and expertise.</p>



<p>Overall, skills and expertise are important when adopting DevOps because DevOps requires a broad range of development, operations, and other technical skills. Without these skills, teams may struggle to implement DevOps effectively, and may not be able to take full advantage of its benefits.</p>
</blockquote>



<h3>Question: Why is it important for the DevOps methodology to integrate with existing processes?</h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>It is important for the DevOps methodology to integrate with existing processes because DevOps typically involves significant automation and integration. In a traditional software development process, there are often many manual processes and interventions that can slow down the development process and lead to errors and delays.</p>



<p>DevOps, on the other hand, emphasizes automation and integration, which can help speed up the development process and improve its efficiency. This can involve integrating DevOps tools and practices with existing systems and processes, such as version control systems, build systems, and deployment pipelines. By integrating DevOps with existing processes, organizations can take advantage of its benefits without disrupting their existing operations.</p>



<p>Additionally, integrating DevOps with existing processes can help ensure that the organization is able to take full advantage of its benefits. For example, by integrating DevOps with existing monitoring and alerting systems, organizations can quickly and easily detect and resolve issues in their software. This can help improve the overall quality and reliability of the software, and ensure that the organization is able to take full advantage of DevOps.</p>



<p>Overall, it is important for the DevOps methodology to integrate with existing processes because DevOps typically involves significant automation and integration. By integrating DevOps with existing processes, organizations can take advantage of its benefits without disrupting their existing operations, and ensure that they are able to take full advantage of its benefits.</p>
</blockquote>



<h3>Final Thoughts: Thank you for your time today. In the future, i would like to come back and ask some questions about tools, practices, and how to get started. Would that be ok with you?</h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>Of course! I would be happy to help you with any questions you have about DevOps tools, practices, and how to get started. Just let me know when you&#8217;re ready, and I&#8217;ll be here to assist you. In the meantime, if you have any other questions, feel free to ask. I&#8217;m here to help!</p>
</blockquote>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>The interview was interesting.  Obviously, ChatGPT is not a sentient being with its own original thoughts so I am not entirely surprised that the answers that were provided were holistically academic in nature.</p>



<p>The most interesting point is the fact that most of the freely available information about the DevOps methodology and its implementation in an organization is entirely academic in nature.  It is aspirational content that speaks to a better way of delivering technology but really lacks many real tactics for getting there.</p>



<p>This blog is looking to solve that.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Solve Your Kubernetes Pod Stuck in Terminating Status Woes in no Time</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/kubernetes-pod-stuck-terminating/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 02:17:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Kubernetes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[day2ops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[howto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tools]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2031</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Kubernetes is a powerful tool for managing complex containerized applications. It helps developers quickly deploy, scale, and manage their applications. However, with great power comes great responsibility and Kubernetes has its share of issues that can cause headaches for developers.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://kubernetes.io/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="4" title="Kubernetes" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Kubernetes</a> is a powerful tool for managing complex containerized applications. It helps developers quickly deploy, scale, and manage their applications.</p>



<p>However, with great power comes great responsibility and Kubernetes has its share of issues that can cause headaches for developers. One of the most dreaded issues is the Kubernetes &#8220;pod stuck terminating&#8221; issue.</p>



<p>In this article, we’ll discuss what this issue is, the common causes, how to diagnose a stuck pod, strategies for solving the issue, a step-by-step guide to solving the issue, best practices for avoiding the issue in the future, troubleshooting tips for Kubernetes pods, useful tools for monitoring and managing Kubernetes pods, courses and tutorials on Kubernetes pod management, and more.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>What is the Kubernetes &#8220;Pod Stuck Terminating&#8221; Issue?</h2>



<p>The Kubernetes pod stuck terminating issue occurs when a pod remains in the “Terminating” state for an extended period of time. This can be caused by a number of different issues and can be quite frustrating for developers.</p>



<p>The issue can manifest itself in a number of ways. For example, you may see that your pod is stuck in the “Terminating” state and never fully terminates and continues to consume resources. You may check the host to which the pod was assigned, and the <a href="https://www.docker.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="16" title="Docker" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Docker</a> container and underlying PID have been terminated, but Kubernetes is reporting it as stuck in a terminating state.</p>



<p>Regardless of the issue, the Kubernetes pod stuck terminating issue can be a major headache for developers and can cause serious delays in deploying applications.</p>



<h2>Common Causes of Pods Becoming Stuck</h2>



<p>The Kubernetes pod stuck terminating issue can be caused by a number of different issues. The most common causes include:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Not enough resources:</strong> Kubernetes pods require sufficient resources in order to function properly. If there aren’t enough resources available, the pod may get stuck in the “Terminating” state. It is important to look at the state of your worker node at the time the pod went unresponsive. If all system resources were consumed, like a disk filling up, then Kubernetes may not actually be the core issue to diagnose.</li>



<li><strong>Contention for resources:</strong> If there are multiple pods competing for resources, one of the pods may get stuck in the “Terminating” state as it waits for resources to become available.</li>



<li><strong>Problems with the pod: </strong>If there is something wrong with the pod itself, it may get stuck in the “Terminating” state. This could be due to an issue with the code, configuration, or other problems.</li>



<li><strong>Issues with the Kubernetes cluster:</strong> If there is something wrong with the Kubernetes cluster itself, it may cause the pod to get stuck in the “Terminating” state. This can happen when cluster communications become disconnected from a blip or network partition. The worker node may be functioning as expected, but cannot tell the Kubernetes API that it is working properly.</li>
</ul>



<h2>How to Diagnose a Stuck Pod</h2>



<p>If you find that your Kubernetes pod is stuck in the “Terminating” state, there are a few steps you can take to diagnose the issue.</p>



<p>The first thing you should do is check the logs. Check the logs for the pod to see if there are any error messages or warnings that could indicate the cause of the issue.</p>



<p>Next, you should check the resource utilization of the pod. If the pod is consuming too many resources, it could be causing issues.</p>



<p>After that, you should check the resource utilization on the server at the time the pod became stuck in a terminating state. If the server ran out of disk, the pod became stuck, but now system resources look fine; the reality is that the processes on the server itself may be in an unknown or unrecoverable state without a reboot.</p>



<p>Finally, you should check the status of the node from kubectl. If the node is not reporting itself as healthy via `kubectl get nodes` then that node should be drained, which may not be possible, and subsequently rebooted and its health re-reviewed.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Strategies for Solving the Issue</h2>



<p>Once you’ve identified the cause of the issue, there are a few strategies you can use to solve the issue.</p>



<h3>Check the Worker Node</h3>



<p>First, check the worker node that was running the pod to see what state the underlying container is in via <code>ctr</code>. If the container is no longer running, the next thing to check is for running PIDs on the system that matches the process being run by the container. If there are no relevant PIDs, then you can run <code>kubectl delete pod --force=true --grace-period=0 -n &lt;NAMESPACE&gt; &lt;STUCK POD NAME&gt;</code> to forcibly remove the pod from the Kubernetes API.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/2139.png" alt="ℹ" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Depending on your version of Kubernetes, you may have Docker or Container.io as a container runtime.  If you have docker, use <code>docker ps</code> to check container status.  If you have Container.io you will use <code>runc</code> or <code>ctr</code> to check the status of your pods.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>In this scenario, a pod was successfully terminated on the worker system, but the Kubernetes worker or the API is out of sync with each other and neither of them really knows the state of the pod.</p>



<p>Signs may point to the issue being fixed after this, but in my experience, you should go ahead and do a full health check of your cluster as this is an edge case caused by some underlying issue somewhere else.</p>



<h3>Keep Checking the Worker Node</h3>



<p>I am cheating here slightly. This is an extension of &#8220;Check the Worker Node&#8221;, but we will assume that the pod is actually still running and has not terminated.</p>



<p>When a pod is stuck in a terminating state this way, the PID that the pod was managing may not be terminating properly. Checking logs here should be the first step. I have run into issues in the past where applications are not properly listening to system signals like SIGHUP to know it is time to terminate.</p>



<p>If you are running internally developed software, check with your development teams to see how the application responds to system signals.</p>



<h3>Rolling Reboots</h3>



<p>The worker node may be perfectly healthy in some instances. Working backward, there could be a problem with either the Kubernetes API receiving update information from worker nodes, a network partition / other network issues, or the ETCd cluster may not be synchronizing properly across all nodes and refusing new write operations.</p>



<p>If you are in a highly resilient state in your Kubernetes cluster, load-balanced masters with multiple ETCd nodes, then a rolling reboot should not hurt anything. Your rolling reboot at that layer should be properly communicated to any parties that could be impacted.</p>



<p>In my experience, this may fix a multitude of issues that may not even be presenting themselves. This is why communication is important. There may be resources that are suddenly rebooted or changed in a way that your business partners were not expecting.</p>



<h2>A Step-By-Step Guide to Solving the Issue</h2>



<p>If you find that your Kubernetes pod is stuck in the “Terminating” state, here’s a step-by-step guide to solving the issue:</p>



<ol>
<li>Check the worker node for signs of stuck PIDs or stuck containers through `ctr`</li>
</ol>



<p>If the node has stuck PIDs or a stuck container, the process running inside of the container is not properly listening to system signals like SIGHUP. File a bug report with the application developers for guidance or bug fixes.</p>



<ol>
<li>Check the worker kubelet process logs for signs errors</li>



<li>Check the master&#8217;s kubelet process logs for signs of errors</li>



<li>Check the master&#8217;s kube-scheduler process logs for signs of errors</li>



<li>Check the master&#8217;s kube-controller-manager process logs for signs of errors</li>



<li>Check the master&#8217;s kube-apiserver process logs for signs of errors</li>
</ol>



<p>If any of these checks present an issue, it is time to start rolling reboots of nodes in your cluster. Start with the impacted worker and move your way back to the masters. Other workers in the cluster probably do not need a reboot.</p>



<ol>
<li>Check server resources at the time the pod became stuck in a terminating state.</li>
</ol>



<p>If this is the case, look for both a root cause of why the server filled up, and perform a reboot on the server. Servers become very unhappy when resources like disks become inaccessible due to capacity issues.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Best Practices for Avoiding the Issue in the Future</h2>



<p>Once you’ve solved the Kubernetes pod stuck terminating issue, it’s important to take steps to avoid the issue in the future. Here are some best practices for avoiding the issue:</p>



<ul>
<li>Monitor your pods: Monitor your pods to make sure they’re not consuming too many resources.</li>



<li>Set limits on resources: Set limits on the resources that your pods can consume to avoid resource contention.</li>



<li>Check your code: Make sure your code is correct and that your pods are properly configured.</li>



<li>Test your pods: Test your pods before deploying them to make sure they’re functioning properly.</li>



<li>Upgrade your cluster: Make sure your Kubernetes cluster is up-to-date to avoid issues.</li>
</ul>



<h2>Troubleshooting Tips for Kubernetes Pods</h2>



<p>If you’re having issues with your Kubernetes pods, here are some troubleshooting tips to help you identify and solve the issue:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Check the logs:</strong> Check the logs for your pod to see if there are any error messages or warnings.</li>



<li><strong>Check the resource utilization:</strong> Check the resource utilization of your pod to make sure it’s not consuming too many resources.</li>



<li><strong>Check the status of the pod:</strong> Check the status of the pod to make sure it’s not stuck in the “Terminating” state.</li>



<li><strong>Try scaling up the resources: </strong>Try scaling up the resources for the pod to see if that helps to resolve the issue.</li>



<li><strong>Try restarting the pod:</strong> Try restarting the pod to see if that helps to resolve the issue.</li>



<li><strong>Try deleting the pod:</strong> Try deleting the pod and recreating it to see if that helps to resolve the issue.</li>
</ul>



<h2>Useful Tools for Monitoring and Managing Kubernetes Pods</h2>



<p>There are a number of useful tools that can help you monitor and manage your Kubernetes pods. These tools can help you identify and solve issues with your pods.</p>



<p>Some of the most popular tools include:</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://kubernetes.io/docs/tasks/access-application-cluster/web-ui-dashboard/" target="_blank" data-type="URL" data-id="https://kubernetes.io/docs/tasks/access-application-cluster/web-ui-dashboard/" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Kubernetes Dashboard</a>: This open-source dashboard allows you to monitor and manage your Kubernetes pods.</li>



<li><a href="https://prometheus.io/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="2" title="Prometheus" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Prometheus</a>: This open-source monitoring tool allows you to monitor your Kubernetes clusters and pods.</li>



<li><a href="https://aquasecurity.github.io/kube-hunter/" target="_blank" data-type="URL" data-id="https://aquasecurity.github.io/kube-hunter/" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Kube-Hunter</a>: This open-source security tool allows you to scan your Kubernetes clusters for security issues.</li>



<li><a href="https://helm.sh/" target="_blank" data-type="URL" data-id="https://helm.sh/" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Helm</a>: This open-source package manager allows you to easily install and manage applications on your Kubernetes cluster.</li>
</ul>



<h2>Courses and Tutorials on Kubernetes Pod Management</h2>



<p>If you’re looking to learn more about managing Kubernetes pods, there are a number of courses and tutorials available. Here are some of the best courses and tutorials:</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.udemy.com/course/the-complete-guide-to-kubernetes-3-course-bundle/" target="_blank" data-type="URL" data-id="https://www.udemy.com/course/the-complete-guide-to-kubernetes-3-course-bundle/" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Kubernetes The Complete Guide</a>: This course covers everything you need to know about managing Kubernetes pods.</li>



<li><a href="https://training.linuxfoundation.org/training/kubernetes-fundamentals/" target="_blank" data-type="URL" data-id="https://training.linuxfoundation.org/training/kubernetes-fundamentals/" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Kubernetes Fundamentals</a>: This tutorial covers the basics of managing Kubernetes pods.</li>



<li><a href="https://kubernetesbootcamp.github.io/kubernetes-bootcamp/" target="_blank" data-type="URL" data-id="https://kubernetesbootcamp.github.io/kubernetes-bootcamp/" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Kubernetes Bootcamp</a>: This course covers the fundamentals of managing Kubernetes clusters and pods.</li>



<li><a href="https://kubernetes.io/docs/concepts/configuration/manage-resources-containers/" target="_blank" data-type="URL" data-id="https://kubernetes.io/docs/concepts/configuration/manage-resources-containers/" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Kubernetes Pod Management</a>: This tutorial covers the basics of managing Kubernetes pods.</li>
</ul>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Frequently Asked Questions</h2>



<p>Below are questions frequently asked about pods stuck in a terminating status:</p>


<div id="rank-math-faq" class="rank-math-block">
<div class="rank-math-list ">
<div id="faq-question-1672170360551" class="rank-math-list-item">
<h3 class="rank-math-question ">How do I delete all terminating pods in Kubernetes?</h3>
<div class="rank-math-answer ">

<p>You can delete all terminating pods in a namespace by running </p>
<p><code>kubectl delete pods -n &lt;namespace> --field-selector='status.phase==Terminating'</code></p>
<p>You can delete all terminating pods in all namespaces by running </p>
<p><code>kubectl delete pods --all-namespaces --field-selector='status.phase==Terminating'</code></p>
<p>These commands may still not delete your terminating pods for a variety of reasons.  You can add a force flag to the command which should forcibly remove stuck pods, but use it with caution.</p>
<p><code>kubectl delete pods --force=true --all-namespaces --field-selector='status.phase==Terminating'</code></p>

</div>
</div>
<div id="faq-question-1672170379976" class="rank-math-list-item">
<h3 class="rank-math-question ">Why is my pod stuck in terminating?</h3>
<div class="rank-math-answer ">

<p>There are several reasons why a pod in Kubernetes might be stuck in the &#8220;Terminating&#8221; state:</p>
<p>1. The pod is waiting for its associated resources (e.g. volumes, secrets, configmaps) to be deleted before it can be terminated.<br />2. The pod is waiting for its finalizers to run. Finalizers are special functions that are run before a resource is deleted. For example, a pod might have a finalizer that runs a cleanup script before the pod is terminated.<br />3. The pod is being evicted by a node, but the eviction process is taking longer than expected. This can happen if the pod has resources that are difficult to release (e.g. open files, network connections).<br />4. There is a problem with the Kubernetes API server, and the pod is unable to be terminated.</p>

</div>
</div>
<div id="faq-question-1672170389680" class="rank-math-list-item">
<h3 class="rank-math-question ">How do you gracefully terminate a pod?</h3>
<div class="rank-math-answer ">

<p>To gracefully terminate a pod in Kubernetes, you can use the <code>kubectl delete</code> command with the <code>--grace-period</code> flag, which allows you to specify a time period in seconds during which the pod will be allowed to finish running any in-progress tasks before it is terminated.</p>
<p>For example, the following command will delete a pod named &#8220;my-pod&#8221; and give it a grace period of 30 seconds to finish any in-progress tasks before it is terminated:</p>
<p><code>kubectl delete pod my-pod --grace-period=30</code></p>

</div>
</div>
<div id="faq-question-1672170400332" class="rank-math-list-item">
<h3 class="rank-math-question ">How to delete a Kubernetes namespace stuck in the terminating state?</h3>
<div class="rank-math-answer ">

<p>To delete a namespace in Kubernetes that is stuck in the &#8220;Terminating&#8221; state, you can use the following command:</p>
<p><code>kubectl delete namespace &lt;namespace-name> --grace-period=0 --force</code></p>
<p>This will force the namespace to be deleted immediately, regardless of whether there are any resources within the namespace that are still being terminated.</p>
<p>Keep in mind that deleting a namespace will delete all resources within that namespace, including pods, services, and deployments. This can disrupt the operation of your application, so it is important to use this command with caution.</p>
<p>If you are unable to delete the namespace using the above command, it is possible that there are resources within the namespace that are preventing it from being deleted. In this case, you can use the following command to list the resources within the namespace and try deleting them individually:<br /><code>kubectl get all --namespace=&lt;namespace-name></code></p>

</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>


<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>The dreaded Kubernetes &#8220;pod stuck terminating&#8221; issue can be a major headache for developers and systems administration teams.</p>



<p>In this article, we’ve discussed what this issue is, the common causes, how to diagnose a stuck pod, strategies for solving the issue, a step-by-step guide to solving the issue, best practices for avoiding the issue in the future, troubleshooting tips for Kubernetes pods, useful tools for monitoring and managing Kubernetes pods, courses and tutorials on Kubernetes pod management, and more.</p>



<p>If you’re having issues with your Kubernetes pods, try following the steps outlined in this article. And remember, if you’re looking to learn more about managing Kubernetes pods, there are a number of courses and tutorials available to help you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Unlock the Power of DevOps Shift-Left Testing</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/devops-shift-left-testing/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 21:56:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[delivery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[howto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sdlc]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2014</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Are you looking for ways to accelerate the development process and reduce costs? Shifting testing to the left should be on your radar. Automated testing is a practice that helps accelerate your flow of value to the market, and if&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Are you looking for ways to accelerate the development process and reduce costs? Shifting testing to the left should be on your radar.  <a href="https://www.valewood.org/devops-testing/" data-type="post" data-id="1239">Automated testing </a>is a practice that helps accelerate your <a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/benefits-of-devops/devops-flow/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="28" title="Understanding the DevOps Process Flow in 2023" target="_blank" rel="noopener">flow of value</a> to the market, and if you haven&#8217;t started building automated testing yet, you should start ASAP!</p>



<p>Shift-left testing is a practice of testing earlier in the development lifecycle, allowing teams to catch bugs before they become costly and time-consuming issues.</p>



<p>In this blog, I&#8217;ll explain what <a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> shift-left testing is, the benefits and challenges of the practice, and how to implement it. I&#8217;ll also provide tips for effective shift-left testing, best practices for automation, and advice on monitoring and analyzing this type of testing.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Introduction to DevOps Shift-Left Testing</h2>



<p>DevOps shift-left testing is the practice of shifting testing activities to the left in the software development process. It involves testing at each stage of the software development lifecycle (SDLC) instead of waiting until the end. This shift-left approach enables teams to catch and address any issues much earlier in the process, saving time and money.</p>



<p>To give some context on the difference between shifting testing to the left and a more traditional testing process, think about a Waterfall project flow. In the waterfall, delivery steps are completed and moved down the assembly line to the next station to get validated or integrated. If there is an issue, it can bring the entire assembly line to a halt.</p>



<p>By moving testing activities earlier in the development cycle, aka shifting left on a delivery timeline, your quality engineering staff are proactively defining the conditions for success through automation. This turns the tables around where quality issues are discovered and remediated causing fewer impacting blockages in your pipelines.</p>



<p>By moving testing activities to the left, teams can find and fix bugs and other issues before they become costly and time-consuming problems. This is crucial for any organization that wants to succeed in the ever-changing world of technology. With DevOps shift-left testing, organizations can reduce the time and cost associated with testing, speed up the development process, and improve the overall quality of their products.</p>



<h2>What is Shift-Left Testing?</h2>



<p>Shift-left testing is the practice of testing earlier in the software development process and shifting activities to the left on a product delivery timeline. It involves testing at each stage of the SDLC, rather than waiting until the end. This shift-left approach enables teams to catch and address any issues much earlier in the process, saving time and money.</p>



<p>Organizations that do proactive planning and discovery on requirements, architecture, and design should also be conceptualizing their quality controls early and often.</p>



<p>Through years of continuous improvement, auto manufacturers have made huge strides to integrate test automation into every stage of their delivery processes. They have done this to reduce their time to market and increase their overall quality.</p>



<p>Shift-left testing helps technology organizations reduce the time and cost associated with testing, speed up the development process, and improve the overall quality of their products. It also allows teams to gain better visibility into their development process, identify potential issues before they become costly problems, and ensure that the quality of their product meets customer expectations.</p>



<p>Shifting Left with testing is also a core tenant of practicing Agile DevOps. Complex systems become easier to manage over the long term when automated testing is integrated early in the development lifecycle.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Benefits of Shift-Left Testing</h2>



<p>Shift-left testing offers many benefits for organizations that are looking to accelerate the development process and reduce costs. Here are some of the key benefits of this practice:</p>



<ol>
<li><strong>Early identification and resolution of issues.</strong> By shifting testing to earlier stages in the development process, organizations can identify and fix issues earlier, reducing the risk of costly and time-consuming issues being discovered later in the development process.</li>



<li><strong>It reduces the time and cost associated with testing.</strong> By shifting testing activities to the left, teams can catch and address issues much earlier in the process, saving time and money.</li>



<li><strong>It speeds up the development process</strong>. With shift-left testing, teams can quickly identify and address any issues, reducing the amount of time it takes to develop a product.</li>



<li><strong>It improves the overall quality and reliability of the product.</strong> By testing earlier in the process, teams can ensure that the product meets customer expectations and has fewer bugs.</li>



<li><strong>It allows teams to gain better visibility into their development process.</strong> With shift-left testing, teams can identify potential issues before they become costly problems. It also promotes collaboration between different teams and disciplines, helping to ensure that everyone is working towards a common goal.</li>



<li><strong>It increases customer satisfaction.</strong> By testing earlier in the process and ensuring that the quality of the product meets customer expectations, organizations can improve customer satisfaction.</li>
</ol>



<h2>Challenges of Shift-Left Testing</h2>



<p>Although shift-left testing offers many benefits, it also comes with certain challenges. Here are some of the key challenges of this practice:</p>



<ol>
<li><strong>It requires a change in mindset</strong>: Organizations must shift their mindset from testing at the end of the development process to testing at each stage of the SDLC.</li>



<li><strong>It requires a shift in resource allocation</strong>: Organizations must allocate more resources to testing activities earlier in the process.</li>



<li><strong>It requires more collaboration between teams</strong>: Organizations must ensure that all teams involved in the development process are collaborating effectively to ensure that shift-left testing is effective.</li>



<li><strong>It requires a shift in tools and technologies</strong>: Organizations must ensure that they have the right tools and technologies in place to support shift-left testing.</li>



<li><strong>It requires more communication</strong>: Organizations must ensure that all stakeholders are kept informed of any changes or issues related to shift-left testing.</li>



<li><strong>Lack of knowledge and experience: </strong>Shifting testing to earlier stages in the development process may require developers to have a deeper understanding of testing concepts and techniques. This may require additional training and resources to ensure that developers are able to effectively conduct testing activities.</li>



<li><strong>Limited testing infrastructure:</strong> Shifting testing to earlier stages in the development process may require organizations to invest in additional testing infrastructures, such as test environments, test data, and testing tools. This can be a significant investment and may require careful planning and resource allocation.</li>



<li><strong>Increased complexity: </strong>By shifting testing to earlier stages in the development process, organizations may face increased complexity in the testing process, as they may need to test more frequently and cover a wider range of scenarios and conditions. This may require additional resources and planning to ensure that testing is conducted effectively.</li>



<li><strong>Resistance to change:</strong> Some organizations may face resistance to shift-left testing, as it requires a change in the traditional testing process and may require additional resources and investments.</li>
</ol>



<p>Shift-left testing is a testing approach that involves shifting testing activities to earlier stages in the development process, with the goal of improving the quality and reliability of the final product. This can be accomplished by starting testing earlier in the development process, testing more frequently, and automating as much of the testing process as possible. Shift-left testing can provide numerous benefits, including early identification and resolution of issues, improved quality and reliability, increased efficiency, and enhanced collaboration. However, it can also present certain challenges, such as a lack of knowledge and experience, limited testing infrastructure, increased complexity, and resistance to change. To effectively implement shift-left testing, organizations must carefully plan and allocate resources to overcome these challenges and realize the full benefits of this approach.</p>



<h2>How to Implement Shift-Left Testing</h2>



<p>If you&#8217;re looking to implement shift-left testing, there are several steps you can take to ensure success. Here are some tips to help you get started:</p>



<ol>
<li><strong>Identify the goals and benefits of shift-left testing</strong>: This can help organizations to understand the motivations for shift-left testing and ensure that it aligns with their overall goals and objectives.</li>



<li><strong>Assess the current testing process</strong>: This can help organizations to understand the current state of their testing process and identify areas where shift-left testing can be implemented.</li>



<li><strong>Develop a plan</strong>: Develop a plan that outlines how you will implement shift-left testing, including which tools and technologies you will use and how you will measure success.</li>



<li><strong>Train your teams</strong>: Ensure that all teams involved in the development process are trained on the principles of shift-left testing and how to use the tools and technologies.</li>



<li><strong>Invest in testing infrastructure and tools</strong>: Organizations may need to invest in additional testing infrastructures, such as test environments, test data, and testing tools, to support shift-left testing.</li>



<li><strong>Automate as much of the testing process as possible</strong>: Automating tests can help to streamline the testing process and make it more efficient.</li>



<li><strong>Monitor progress</strong>: Monitor the progress of shift-left testing and identify any issues that need to be addressed.</li>



<li><strong>Adjust as needed</strong>: Adjust the plan as needed to ensure that the process of shift-left testing is effective and efficient.</li>



<li><strong>Review and refine the testing process</strong>: It is important to regularly review and refine the testing process to ensure that it is effective and efficient.</li>
</ol>



<p>To implement shift-left testing, organizations should identify the goals and benefits of shift-left testing, assess the current testing process, identify and prioritize high-value tests, automate as much of the testing process as possible, invest in testing infrastructure and tools, train and educate developers, and review and refine the testing process. By following these steps, organizations can effectively implement shift-left testing and improve the quality and reliability of their products.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Best Practices for Shift-Left Testing</h2>



<p>When it comes to shift-left testing, there are several best practices that organizations should follow to ensure success. Here are some of the key best practices:</p>



<ol>
<li><strong>Automate whenever possible.</strong> Automation can help reduce the time and cost associated with shift-left testing, so it should be used whenever possible.</li>



<li><strong>Set clear goals and timelines.</strong> Make sure that all stakeholders have a clear understanding of the goals of shift-left testing and how long it will take to implement.</li>



<li><strong>Focus on quality.</strong> Shift-left testing should be used to ensure that the product meets customer expectations and has fewer bugs.</li>



<li><strong>Monitor performance.</strong> Monitor the performance of shift-left testing and adjust the plan as needed to ensure that it is effective and efficient.</li>



<li><strong>Communicate with stakeholders.</strong> Make sure that all stakeholders are kept informed of any changes or issues related to shift-left testing.</li>
</ol>



<h2>Tips for Effective Shift-Left Testing</h2>



<p>If you&#8217;re looking to make shift-left testing effective, here are some tips to help you:</p>



<ol>
<li><strong>Prioritize testing activities.</strong> Make sure that testing activities are prioritized and that they are aligned with the goals of the organization.</li>



<li><strong>Automate whenever possible.</strong> Automation can help reduce the time and cost associated with shift-left testing, so it should be used whenever possible.</li>



<li><strong>Monitor performance.</strong> Monitor the performance of shift-left testing and adjust the plan as needed to ensure that it is effective and efficient.</li>



<li><strong>Communicate with stakeholders.</strong> Make sure that all stakeholders are kept informed of any changes or issues related to shift-left testing.</li>



<li><strong>Measure success.</strong> Ensure that you have a way to measure the success of shift-left testing so that you can make adjustments if needed.</li>
</ol>



<h2>Monitoring and Analyzing Shift-Left Testing</h2>



<p>Once you&#8217;ve implemented shift-left testing, it&#8217;s important to monitor and analyze the results. Here are some tips for monitoring and analyzing shift-left testing:</p>



<ol>
<li><strong>Track progress.</strong> Track the progress of shift-left testing to identify any issues that need to be addressed.</li>



<li><strong>Analyze results.</strong> Analyze the results of shift-left testing to determine if it is effective and efficient.</li>



<li><strong>Make adjustments.</strong> Make adjustments to the plan as needed to ensure that shift-left testing is effective and efficient.</li>



<li><strong>Measure success.</strong> Ensure that you have a way to measure the success of shift-left testing so that you can make adjustments if needed.</li>



<li><strong>Communicate with stakeholders.</strong> Make sure that all stakeholders are kept informed of any changes or issues related to shift-left testing.</li>
</ol>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Frequently Asked Questions</h2>



<p>Below are some frequently asked questions about Shift-Left testing:</p>


<div id="rank-math-faq" class="rank-math-block">
<div class="rank-math-list ">
<div id="faq-question-1672179687134" class="rank-math-list-item">
<h3 class="rank-math-question ">What is Shift-Left testing?</h3>
<div class="rank-math-answer ">

<p>Shift-left testing is a testing approach that involves shifting testing activities to earlier stages in the development process, with the goal of improving the quality and reliability of the final product.</p>

</div>
</div>
<div id="faq-question-1672179688213" class="rank-math-list-item">
<h3 class="rank-math-question ">Why is Shift-Left testing important?</h3>
<div class="rank-math-answer ">

<p>Shift-left testing is important because it allows organizations to identify and fix issues early in the development process, improving the quality and reliability of the final product and reducing the time and effort required to deliver it.</p>

</div>
</div>
<div id="faq-question-1672179702873" class="rank-math-list-item">
<h3 class="rank-math-question ">How can Shift-Left testing be implemented?</h3>
<div class="rank-math-answer ">

<p>Shift-left testing can be implemented by identifying the goals and benefits of shift-left testing, assessing the current testing process, identifying and prioritizing high-value tests, automating as much of the testing process as possible, investing in testing infrastructure and tools, training and educating developers, and reviewing and refining the testing process.</p>

</div>
</div>
<div id="faq-question-1672179714005" class="rank-math-list-item">
<h3 class="rank-math-question ">What are the challenges of Shift-Left testing?</h3>
<div class="rank-math-answer ">

<p>Some challenges of shift-left testing include a lack of knowledge and experience, limited testing infrastructure, increased complexity, and resistance to change.</p>

</div>
</div>
<div id="faq-question-1672179725306" class="rank-math-list-item">
<h3 class="rank-math-question ">What are the benefits of Shift-Left testing?</h3>
<div class="rank-math-answer ">

<p>The benefits of shift-left testing include early identification and resolution of issues, improved quality and reliability, increased efficiency, and enhanced collaboration.</p>

</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>


<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>Shift-left testing is a powerful practice that can help organizations accelerate the development process and reduce costs. By shifting testing activities to the left, teams can catch and address any issues much earlier in the process, saving time and money. However, shift-left testing is not without its challenges. Organizations must shift their mindset, allocate more resources to testing activities, and ensure that all teams involved in the development process are collaborating effectively.</p>



<p>If you&#8217;re looking to make the move to shift-left testing, there are several steps you can take to ensure success. You should align your goals, develop a plan, train your teams, monitor progress, and adjust as needed. You should also prioritize testing activities, automate whenever possible, and measure success. Finally, you should monitor and analyze the results of shift-left testing to determine if it is effective and efficient.</p>



<p>So, if you&#8217;re looking to accelerate the development process and reduce costs, shift-left testing is the way to go. With shift-left testing, you can reduce the time and cost associated with testing, speed up the development process, and improve the overall quality of your products. So, what are you waiting for? Take the plunge and make the move to shift-left testing today!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>6 Common Misconceptions about Agile and DevOps</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/devops-and-agile-misconceptions/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 14:20:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[agile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sdlc]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1966</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In this blog, we discuss&#160;DevOps and Agile at great length. DevOps is a methodology for technology delivery while Agile is a methodology for project management. The two pair together quite well to increase the&#160;flow of value&#160;to the market. They can&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In this blog, we discuss&nbsp;<a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> and Agile at great length. DevOps is a methodology for technology delivery while Agile is a methodology for project management. The two pair together quite well to increase the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/benefits-of-devops/devops-flow/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="28" title="Understanding the DevOps Process Flow in 2023" target="_blank" rel="noopener">flow of value</a>&nbsp;to the market.</p>



<p>They can also be intertwined and confusing leading to misconceptions if one isn&#8217;t careful in their adoption journey. Let&#8217;s dive in and discuss the most common misconception about DevOps and Agile!</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>What Are the Most Common Misconceptions About Agile and DevOps?</h2>



<p>There are several common misconceptions that surface quickly when businesses are evaluating DevOps and Agile either independently or together. It is not entirely unreasonable to assume that anyone in the software development space could quickly make the jump from hearing about how awesome DevOps and Agile are into these misconceptions.</p>



<p>Below are a few of those misconceptions.</p>



<h3>Common Misconception #1</h3>



<div style="height:12px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<figure class="wp-block-pullquote has-border-color has-background has-small-font-size" style="border-color:#abb7c266;border-width:1px;border-radius:8px;background-color:#abb7c20d;font-style:normal;font-weight:500"><blockquote><p>DevOps and Agile can fill gaps in my poorly running delivery process</p></blockquote></figure>



<div style="height:28px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<p>DevOps and Agile are commonly viewed as a tool to fill a gap in software development delivery activities. If delivery cycles are variable in length, inconsistent, and filled with twists and turns; companies will look for some quick outs to patch up their delivery to ship something.</p>



<p>The problem with this approach is low&nbsp;<a href="https://valewood.org/topics/devops/benefits-of-devops/devops-culture-of-quality" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>quality</strong></a>.</p>



<p>While borrowing from DevOps and Agile might work in the short term, it does not work over the long term. Companies or projects looking to step up their delivery processes need to look at things holistically and make some choices about how they want to engage in the market with their customers.</p>



<h3>Common Misconception #2</h3>



<div style="height:12px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<figure class="wp-block-pullquote has-border-color has-background has-small-font-size" style="border-color:#abb7c266;border-width:1px;border-radius:8px;background-color:#abb7c20d;font-style:normal;font-weight:500"><blockquote><p>DevOps and/or Agile can be purchased off the shelf and implemented</p></blockquote></figure>



<div style="height:28px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<p>DevOps and/or Agile cannot be purchased. There is no singular toolset, workbook, or process that can be purchased and put in place to shortcut the adoption of these methodologies. Both of these methodologies are a fundamental transformation of delivery and need to be adopted fully in order to be effective.</p>



<p>This transformation is also cross-cutting throughout all technical and non-technical roles. A sales team cannot assume that groups delivering technology are delivering in a different way than they are selling.</p>



<p>Account management cannot build plans with customers on their future technology state and expect that planning to look different than the overall delivery workflows. Technology groups cannot adopt a different way of delivering if it is at odds with business expectations.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h3>Common Misconception #3</h3>



<div style="height:12px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<figure class="wp-block-pullquote has-border-color has-background has-small-font-size" style="border-color:#abb7c266;border-width:1px;border-radius:8px;background-color:#abb7c20d;font-style:normal;font-weight:500"><blockquote><p>DevOps can be implemented without Agile</p></blockquote></figure>



<div style="height:28px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<p>Now, that statement is a little clickbaity. You can indeed implement DevOps inside of other project management frameworks.</p>



<p>I would make the argument that you cannot fully realize the benefits of delivery transformation unless you adopt both DevOps and Agile. DevOps practices do not lend themselves well to Waterfall, but it can be done. You really lose out on all of the continuous improvement facets of DevOps which really means you are adopting some automation and calling it “DevOps”.</p>



<h3>Common Misconception #4</h3>



<div style="height:12px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<figure class="wp-block-pullquote has-border-color has-background has-small-font-size" style="border-color:#abb7c266;border-width:1px;border-radius:8px;background-color:#abb7c20d;font-style:normal;font-weight:500"><blockquote><p>When DevOps and Agile are combined, you can foregoe planning</p></blockquote></figure>



<div style="height:28px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<p>Software development always needs a great deal of planning. DevOps and agile do not let you get away without planning.</p>



<p>Agile in this case is formal agile delivery which I would argue consists of more planning, market research, feedback, and pivots than any other project management framework.</p>



<p>DevOps focuses on continuous improvement and automation which need a significant amount of planning to ensure the right areas of focus are being worked on.</p>



<p>The truth is this; development teams, operations teams, infrastructure teams, quality assurance teams, account management teams, and members of any other team benefit from having a good plan that is backed up by principles, culture, and a centralized philosophy.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h3>Common Misconception #5</h3>



<div style="height:12px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<figure class="wp-block-pullquote has-border-color has-background has-small-font-size" style="border-color:#abb7c266;border-width:1px;border-radius:8px;background-color:#abb7c20d;font-style:normal;font-weight:500"><blockquote><p>DevOps and Agile are only for small teams</p></blockquote></figure>



<div style="height:28px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<p>Teams of all sizes can benefit from these delivery methodologies. Software delivery is a complex problem that requires good communication, tools, talent, and principles to drive consistency and quality.</p>



<p>While there are an infinite number of methods that could be used to deliver technology, Agile and DevOps are formalized and prescriptive platforms to solve these complex challenges.</p>



<p>By adopting DevOps and Agile together and bringing a core set of delivery principles to an organization&#8217;s approach to delivering technology, one can actually achieve a much larger scale of delivery more quickly.</p>



<p>All of your teams are on the same page, utilizing the same tools, communicating about the same processes, and driving agile development and operations together as a unified front.</p>



<h3>Common Misconception #6</h3>



<div style="height:12px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<figure class="wp-block-pullquote has-border-color has-background has-small-font-size" style="border-color:#abb7c266;border-width:1px;border-radius:8px;background-color:#abb7c20d;font-style:normal;font-weight:500"><blockquote><p>DevOps and Agile are focused on controlling software development</p></blockquote></figure>



<div style="height:28px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<p>I would argue that this is the farthest idea from the truth. DevOps and Agile aim to democratize the delivery process across an organization&#8217;s many different value streams.</p>



<p>One of the core principles of the Scaled Agile Framework for Enterprises is to get decision-making as close to the work being performed as possible. This means that teams must work together on their high-level planning initiatives to get stories in the hands of implementers leaving them the freedom to deliver those stories any way they want to.</p>



<p>This does not mean that the business does not have a say in what is getting delivered, but how it is delivered is determined by the individuals that know best.</p>



<p>Early on in the adoption of these methodologies, it is not uncommon for a pendulum of decisions making to swing back and forth between IT and the business as everyone tries to figure out this new dynamic. Everyone&#8217;s goal should be to find a new center where everyone is heard and all concerns, no matter their size, are given room to breathe in a conversation about delivery.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>How Should I View DevOps and Agile?</h2>



<p>By fully adopting Agile and DevOps, a lot of doors are opened up for delivery.</p>



<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/benefits-of-devops/devops-flow/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Flow</a>:</strong> Instead of moving from task to task, or project to project, work can be put onto a conveyor belt of delivery. Agile and DevOps offer more of an assembly line-type flow to technology delivery.</li>



<li><strong><a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/benefits-of-devops/devops-culture-of-quality/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Quality</a>:</strong> Context switching impacts quality. By offering more stability in work coming down the pipeline, engineers in various disciplines can focus on quality first.</li>



<li><strong><a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/benefits-of-devops/flexibility/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Flexibility</a>:</strong> Companies need to meet the market where it is at. Sometimes this means quickly pivoting from products that are not working to products that do well in the market.</li>



<li><a href="https://www.valewood.org/devops-cycle-time/"><strong>Release faster and work smarter</strong>:</a> By reducing the size and scope of deliverables, the team can focus on shipping more often.</li>



<li><strong><a href="https://www.valewood.org/why-are-ci-cd-pipelines-part-of-devops/">Simplifies Software Development and Operations Focus</a></strong>: Day-to-day operations can seem like a burden that interrupts delivery frequently. By adopting DevOps, operations are a normal part of everyday life.</li>



<li><strong><a href="https://www.valewood.org/devops-trust/">Responsibility</a>:</strong> Agile helps individual contributors feel like they are part of something bigger by influencing the overall planning and delivery processes. They are not just taking orders from the tower, they are actively delivering value against their vision of great outcomes.</li>



<li><strong><a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/benefits-of-devops/consistency/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Consistency</a>:</strong> Consistency brings predictability and reliability to products and planning</li>



<li><strong>Measurement:</strong> Promote data-driven decision-making into your day-to-day workflows through predictability and consistency in the flow of work.</li>



<li><strong>Security:</strong> Security is no longer a secondary burdensome process that detracts from delivering work to the market. Security is built right into DevOps through automated delivery pipelines.</li>
</ul>



<p>Any of these benefits could be achieved on their own in their own ways. By fully embracing Agile and DevOps, each of these ideals comes with the methodology. There is no need to solve an already-solved problem.</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>When first hearing about DevOps and Agile, it is easy to build some initial blinders and misconceptions about what they really mean when utilized as a symbiotic relationship.  It takes a mindset change, and a full perspective shift to realize the benefits of DevOps and Agile together.  </p>



<p>I would encourage anyone out there to go get some training, watch some YouTube videos, and read as much as you can about the methodologies and what they have to offer.  DevOps and Agile together can really open up a lot of new benefits for your business and your customers.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Helm: Kubernetes Cluster Unreachable </title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/helm-kubernetes-cluster-unreachable/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 02:51:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Kubernetes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[howto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kubernetes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tools]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1924</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Kubernetes, while fairly mature as a platform, is still considered an emerging technology in the business space. Due to this, lots of engineers are spending their free time trying to learn about Helm which can lead to some pretty frustrating&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://kubernetes.io/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="4" title="Kubernetes" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Kubernetes</a>, while fairly mature as a platform, is still considered an emerging technology in the business space.  Due to this, lots of engineers are spending their free time trying to learn about Helm which can lead to some pretty frustrating errors.  </p>



<p>Let&#8217;s discuss why you might be receiving <code>Error: Kubernetes cluster unreachable</code> when trying to connect to your cluster for the first time.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Kubernetes Install</h2>



<p>There are a lot of different mechanisms on the market today to get Kubernetes up and running depending on your environment.  How you installed Kubernetes is important for troubleshooting later.  Review the install methods and make sure you align underneath one of them in some fashion.</p>



<h3>Local Environment</h3>



<p>Local Kubernetes is going to use <a href="https://k3s.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">k3s</a> or <a href="https://minikube.sigs.k8s.io/docs/start/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">minikube</a> to run and install a local version on a standard workstation.  This is a great way to get familiar with Kubernetes because these products will download and install all the requisite dependencies to bootstrap anyone regardless of their skill level.</p>



<h3>On-Prem Environment</h3>



<p>I am differentiating local and on-prem simply from the viewpoint of servers vs desktops.  In a more server-focused environment, many people will use <a href="https://github.com/kubernetes-sigs/kubespray" target="_blank" rel="noopener">kubespray</a> or <a href="https://github.com/kubernetes/kops" target="_blank" rel="noopener">kops</a> to deploy their Kubernetes clusters.  Kubespray will ensure that servers are properly configured through IaC while downloading and installing baseline Kubernetes.  By the time you are done, a fully functional cluster should be available.</p>



<p>Kubespray does come with a lot more knobs and dials since it makes fewer opinionated decisions about what your cluster setup should look like.  In a local environment, ingress is going to be handled in a very specific way.  In an on-prem environment, you may have network appliances that want to handle ingress in a very specific way.  Kubespray should be able to get most of your configurations taken care of for your special circumstances.</p>



<h3>Cloud Environment</h3>



<p>Cloud environments can be configured the same way on-prem environments are through kubespray and kops.  Cloud-based VM instances would be spun up on management networks and tools would be run against them to achieve a functioning cluster.</p>



<p>Most cloud providers will have their own managed Kubernetes to be used as well.  Those are probably a much safer way to get started when just starting to dabble in the Kubernetes space.  </p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://aws.amazon.com/eks/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon EKS</a></li>



<li><a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/products/kubernetes-service/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Azure AKS</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/products/kubernetes" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DigitalOcean</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vultr.com/kubernetes/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Vultr</a></li>
</ul>



<p>These solutions generally are only a few clicks away from a full-stack deployment.  Once you get a bit more comfortable, it would be a good idea to toss out your test cluster and start to move into Terraform, CloudFormation, or <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/get-started/azure-portal" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="20" title="Azure" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Azure</a> Resource Manager automation to ensure your clusters are codified for future upgrades.</p>



<h2>Error: Kubernetes cluster unreachable</h2>



<p>There are going to be a few troubleshooting steps you should take to diagnose this issue.  Each of them is going to be a little bit different depending on your deployment setup.</p>



<h3>Check Your Kubeconfig</h3>



<p>The first thing to check is your <code>$HOME/.kube/config</code> file.  This file contains all of the relevant information for connecting to your Kubernetes cluster.  It is also very important you keep this file safe and secret since it holds credentials for that connection as well.</p>



<h4>My Kubeconfig is Missing!</h4>



<p>If your kubeconfig file is missing, review your Kubernetes installation instructions for anything specific about copying a kubeconfig to the proper folder on your local machine.  The instructions may also walk you through how to create one.  Helm will not work without this file being created and in the proper location.</p>



<h4>My Kubeconfig Exists!</h4>



<p>If you open that file to read it, you will find that it is YAML formatted with connection parameters in it.  These parameters should include some certificate information, which are credentials and cluster identification verification, and a hostname for the cluster management API address.</p>



<p>If you have kubectl installed on the same machine as your kubeconfig, a simple test would be to run <code>kubectl get nodes</code> to see if you get a list of servers back from the kubernetes API.  If you get an error, then either you do not have the right level of access, or your kubeconfig is not properly configured.  See above <strong>&#8220;My Kubeconfig is Missing&#8221;</strong>.</p>



<p>If this works as intended, and you see a list of servers the next step is to ensure that your kubeconfig is on the same computer that you would like to run helm from.  If you are running helm from a local workstation, make sure you have a proper kubeconfig on that workstation.  If you are running helm from a different server, ensure a kubeconfig is provided for that server.  Make sure to re-test.</p>



<h4>Check Networking</h4>



<p>Helm communicates with the Kubernetes API over port 6443.  Using NMap to check ports, ensure that the machine you are intending to run helm from has clear line of sight communication with the Kubernetes cluster over port 6443.  This can be achieved on Linux via this command: nmap –p 6443 {{cluster address/master hostname}}.  You can find the cluster address/master hostname inside of a validated kubeconfig.</p>



<p>If you are using Windows and looking for an example of how to do port scans, I would suggest switching to Linux or Mac.</p>



<p>If ports show closed or filtered, network communication will not be established with the cluster and Helm will not be able to run configurations.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Additional Resources</h2>



<p>The steps outlined above should get you pointed in the right direction when you receive Helm errors when trying to contact your cluster for the first time.</p>



<p>If you did not find the answers you needed via this article, I have added a few additional resources below that may be able to help get you sorted out.  If you have additional information to share on this topic, please <a href="https://www.valewood.org/contact/" data-type="page" data-id="984">contact me</a> and I will update this post to reflect any changes.</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/k3s-io/k3s/issues/1126" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GitHub</a></li>



<li><a href="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/63066604/error-kubernetes-cluster-unreachable-get-http-localhost8080-versiontimeou" target="_blank" rel="noopener">StackOverflow</a></li>



<li><a href="https://pet2cattle.com/2022/07/install-helm-k3s" data-type="URL" data-id="https://pet2cattle.com/2022/07/install-helm-k3s" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Pet2Cattle</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
