<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>A DevOps Blog</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.valewood.org/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.valewood.org/</link>
	<description>Occasionally a developer makes an Ops!</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 22:30:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.valewood.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/A-DevOoops-1-e1660773390219.png</url>
	<title>A DevOps Blog</title>
	<link>https://www.valewood.org/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Unlock the Power of DevOps Shift-Left Testing</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/devops-shift-left-testing/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 21:56:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[delivery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[howto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sdlc]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2014</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Are you looking for ways to accelerate the development process and reduce costs? Shifting testing to the left should be on your radar. Automated testing is a practice that helps accelerate your flow of value to the market, and if&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Are you looking for ways to accelerate the development process and reduce costs? Shifting testing to the left should be on your radar.  <a href="https://www.valewood.org/devops-testing/" data-type="post" data-id="1239">Automated testing </a>is a practice that helps accelerate your <a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/benefits-of-devops/devops-flow/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="28" title="Understanding the DevOps Process Flow in 2022" target="_blank" rel="noopener">flow of value</a> to the market, and if you haven&#8217;t started building automated testing yet, you should start ASAP!</p>



<p>Shift-left testing is a practice of testing earlier in the development lifecycle, allowing teams to catch bugs before they become costly and time-consuming issues.</p>



<p>In this blog, I&#8217;ll explain what <a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> shift-left testing is, the benefits and challenges of the practice, and how to implement it. I&#8217;ll also provide tips for effective shift-left testing, best practices for automation, and advice on monitoring and analyzing this type of testing.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Introduction to DevOps Shift-Left Testing</h2>



<p>DevOps shift-left testing is the practice of shifting testing activities to the left in the software development process. It involves testing at each stage of the software development lifecycle (SDLC) instead of waiting until the end. This shift-left approach enables teams to catch and address any issues much earlier in the process, saving time and money.</p>



<p>To give some context on the difference between shifting testing to the left and a more traditional testing process, think about a Waterfall project flow. In the waterfall, delivery steps are completed and moved down the assembly line to the next station to get validated or integrated. If there is an issue, it can bring the entire assembly line to a halt.</p>



<p>By moving testing activities earlier in the development cycle, aka shifting left on a delivery timeline, your quality engineering staff are proactively defining the conditions for success through automation. This turns the tables around where quality issues are discovered and remediated causing fewer impacting blockages in your pipelines.</p>



<p>By moving testing activities to the left, teams can find and fix bugs and other issues before they become costly and time-consuming problems. This is crucial for any organization that wants to succeed in the ever-changing world of technology. With DevOps shift-left testing, organizations can reduce the time and cost associated with testing, speed up the development process, and improve the overall quality of their products.</p>



<h2>What is Shift-Left Testing?</h2>



<p>Shift-left testing is the practice of testing earlier in the software development process and shifting activities to the left on a product delivery timeline. It involves testing at each stage of the SDLC, rather than waiting until the end. This shift-left approach enables teams to catch and address any issues much earlier in the process, saving time and money.</p>



<p>Organizations that do proactive planning and discovery on requirements, architecture, and design should also be conceptualizing their quality controls early and often.</p>



<p>Through years of continuous improvement, auto manufacturers have made huge strides to integrate test automation into every stage of their delivery processes. They have done this to reduce their time to market and increase their overall quality.</p>



<p>Shift-left testing helps technology organizations reduce the time and cost associated with testing, speed up the development process, and improve the overall quality of their products. It also allows teams to gain better visibility into their development process, identify potential issues before they become costly problems, and ensure that the quality of their product meets customer expectations.</p>



<p>Shifting Left with testing is also a core tenant of practicing Agile DevOps. Complex systems become easier to manage over the long term when automated testing is integrated early in the development lifecycle.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Benefits of Shift-Left Testing</h2>



<p>Shift-left testing offers many benefits for organizations that are looking to accelerate the development process and reduce costs. Here are some of the key benefits of this practice:</p>



<ol>
<li>It reduces the time and cost associated with testing. By shifting testing activities to the left, teams can catch and address issues much earlier in the process, saving time and money.</li>



<li>It speeds up the development process. With shift-left testing, teams can quickly identify and address any issues, reducing the amount of time it takes to develop a product.</li>



<li>It improves the overall quality of the product. By testing earlier in the process, teams can ensure that the product meets customer expectations and has fewer bugs.</li>



<li>It allows teams to gain better visibility into their development process. With shift-left testing, teams can identify potential issues before they become costly problems.</li>



<li>It increases customer satisfaction. By testing earlier in the process and ensuring that the quality of the product meets customer expectations, organizations can improve customer satisfaction.</li>
</ol>



<h2>Challenges of Shift-Left Testing</h2>



<p>Although shift-left testing offers many benefits, it also comes with certain challenges. Here are some of the key challenges of this practice:</p>



<ol>
<li>It requires a change in mindset. Organizations must shift their mindset from testing at the end of the development process to testing at each stage of the SDLC.</li>



<li>It requires a shift in resource allocation. Organizations must allocate more resources to testing activities earlier in the process.</li>



<li>It requires more collaboration between teams. Organizations must ensure that all teams involved in the development process are collaborating effectively to ensure that shift-left testing is effective.</li>



<li>It requires a shift in tools and technologies. Organizations must ensure that they have the right tools and technologies in place to support shift-left testing.</li>



<li>It requires more communication. Organizations must ensure that all stakeholders are kept informed of any changes or issues related to shift-left testing.</li>
</ol>



<h2>How to Implement Shift-Left Testing</h2>



<p>If you&#8217;re looking to implement shift-left testing, there are several steps you can take to ensure success. Here are some tips to help you get started:</p>



<ol>
<li>Align your goals. Before you begin, make sure that all stakeholders have a clear understanding of the goals of shift-left testing and how it will benefit the organization.</li>



<li>Develop a plan. Develop a plan that outlines how you will implement shift-left testing, including which tools and technologies you will use and how you will measure success.</li>



<li>Train your teams. Ensure that all teams involved in the development process are trained on the principles of shift-left testing and how to use the tools and technologies.</li>



<li>Monitor progress. Monitor the progress of shift-left testing and identify any issues that need to be addressed.</li>



<li>Adjust as needed. Adjust the plan as needed to ensure that the process of shift-left testing is effective and efficient.</li>
</ol>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Best Practices for Shift-Left Testing</h2>



<p>When it comes to shift-left testing, there are several best practices that organizations should follow to ensure success. Here are some of the key best practices:</p>



<ol>
<li>Automate whenever possible. Automation can help reduce the time and cost associated with shift-left testing, so it should be used whenever possible.</li>



<li>Set clear goals and timelines. Make sure that all stakeholders have a clear understanding of the goals of shift-left testing and how long it will take to implement.</li>



<li>Focus on quality. Shift-left testing should be used to ensure that the product meets customer expectations and has fewer bugs.</li>



<li>Monitor performance. Monitor the performance of shift-left testing and adjust the plan as needed to ensure that it is effective and efficient.</li>



<li>Communicate with stakeholders. Make sure that all stakeholders are kept informed of any changes or issues related to shift-left testing.</li>
</ol>



<h2>Automation of Shift-Left Testing</h2>



<p>Automation is a key component of shift-left testing. Automation can help reduce the time and cost associated with testing, and it can also help teams identify and address any issues much earlier in the process. Here are some tips for automating shift-left testing:</p>



<ol>
<li>Use the right tools and technologies. Make sure that you have the right tools and technologies in place to support shift-left testing.</li>



<li>Identify which tasks to automate. Identify which tasks can be automated and which tasks require manual testing.</li>



<li>Monitor progress. Monitor the progress of automation and adjust the plan as needed to ensure that it is effective and efficient.</li>



<li>Test the automation. Make sure to test the automation to ensure that it is working as expected.</li>



<li>Communicate with stakeholders. Make sure that all stakeholders are kept informed of any changes or issues related to automation.</li>
</ol>



<h2>Tips for Effective Shift-Left Testing</h2>



<p>If you&#8217;re looking to make shift-left testing effective, here are some tips to help you:</p>



<ol>
<li>Prioritize testing activities. Make sure that testing activities are prioritized and that they are aligned with the goals of the organization.</li>



<li>Automate whenever possible. Automation can help reduce the time and cost associated with shift-left testing, so it should be used whenever possible.</li>



<li>Monitor performance. Monitor the performance of shift-left testing and adjust the plan as needed to ensure that it is effective and efficient.</li>



<li>Communicate with stakeholders. Make sure that all stakeholders are kept informed of any changes or issues related to shift-left testing.</li>



<li>Measure success. Ensure that you have a way to measure the success of shift-left testing so that you can make adjustments if needed.</li>
</ol>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Monitoring and Analyzing Shift-Left Testing</h2>



<p>Once you&#8217;ve implemented shift-left testing, it&#8217;s important to monitor and analyze the results. Here are some tips for monitoring and analyzing shift-left testing:</p>



<ol>
<li>Track progress. Track the progress of shift-left testing to identify any issues that need to be addressed.</li>



<li>Analyze results. Analyze the results of shift-left testing to determine if it is effective and efficient.</li>



<li>Make adjustments. Make adjustments to the plan as needed to ensure that shift-left testing is effective and efficient.</li>



<li>Measure success. Ensure that you have a way to measure the success of shift-left testing so that you can make adjustments if needed.</li>



<li>Communicate with stakeholders. Make sure that all stakeholders are kept informed of any changes or issues related to shift-left testing.</li>
</ol>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>Shift-left testing is a powerful practice that can help organizations accelerate the development process and reduce costs. By shifting testing activities to the left, teams can catch and address any issues much earlier in the process, saving time and money. However, shift-left testing is not without its challenges. Organizations must shift their mindset, allocate more resources to testing activities, and ensure that all teams involved in the development process are collaborating effectively.</p>



<p>If you&#8217;re looking to make the move to shift-left testing, there are several steps you can take to ensure success. You should align your goals, develop a plan, train your teams, monitor progress, and adjust as needed. You should also prioritize testing activities, automate whenever possible, and measure success. Finally, you should monitor and analyze the results of shift-left testing to determine if it is effective and efficient.</p>



<p>So, if you&#8217;re looking to accelerate the development process and reduce costs, shift-left testing is the way to go. With shift-left testing, you can reduce the time and cost associated with testing, speed up the development process, and improve the overall quality of your products. So, what are you waiting for? Take the plunge and make the move to shift-left testing today!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>6 Common Misconceptions about Agile and DevOps</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/devops-and-agile-misconceptions/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 14:20:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[agile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sdlc]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1966</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In this blog, we discuss&#160;DevOps and Agile at great length. DevOps is a methodology for technology delivery while Agile is a methodology for project management. The two pair together quite well to increase the&#160;flow of value&#160;to the market. They can&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In this blog, we discuss&nbsp;<a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> and Agile at great length. DevOps is a methodology for technology delivery while Agile is a methodology for project management. The two pair together quite well to increase the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/benefits-of-devops/devops-flow/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="28" title="Understanding the DevOps Process Flow in 2022" target="_blank" rel="noopener">flow of value</a>&nbsp;to the market.</p>



<p>They can also be intertwined and confusing leading to misconceptions if one isn&#8217;t careful in their adoption journey. Let&#8217;s dive in and discuss the most common misconception about DevOps and Agile!</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>What Are the Most Common Misconceptions About Agile and DevOps?</h2>



<p>There are several common misconceptions that surface quickly when businesses are evaluating DevOps and Agile either independently or together. It is not entirely unreasonable to assume that anyone in the software development space could quickly make the jump from hearing about how awesome DevOps and Agile are into these misconceptions.</p>



<p>Below are a few of those misconceptions.</p>



<h3>Common Misconception #1</h3>



<div style="height:12px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<figure class="wp-block-pullquote has-border-color has-background has-small-font-size" style="border-color:#abb7c266;border-width:1px;border-radius:8px;background-color:#abb7c20d;font-style:normal;font-weight:500"><blockquote><p>DevOps and Agile can fill gaps in my poorly running delivery process</p></blockquote></figure>



<div style="height:28px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<p>DevOps and Agile are commonly viewed as a tool to fill a gap in software development delivery activities. If delivery cycles are variable in length, inconsistent, and filled with twists and turns; companies will look for some quick outs to patch up their delivery to ship something.</p>



<p>The problem with this approach is low&nbsp;<a href="https://valewood.org/topics/devops/benefits-of-devops/devops-culture-of-quality" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>quality</strong></a>.</p>



<p>While borrowing from DevOps and Agile might work in the short term, it does not work over the long term. Companies or projects looking to step up their delivery processes need to look at things holistically and make some choices about how they want to engage in the market with their customers.</p>



<h3>Common Misconception #2</h3>



<div style="height:12px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<figure class="wp-block-pullquote has-border-color has-background has-small-font-size" style="border-color:#abb7c266;border-width:1px;border-radius:8px;background-color:#abb7c20d;font-style:normal;font-weight:500"><blockquote><p>DevOps and/or Agile can be purchased off the shelf and implemented</p></blockquote></figure>



<div style="height:28px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<p>DevOps and/or Agile cannot be purchased. There is no singular toolset, workbook, or process that can be purchased and put in place to shortcut the adoption of these methodologies. Both of these methodologies are a fundamental transformation of delivery and need to be adopted fully in order to be effective.</p>



<p>This transformation is also cross-cutting throughout all technical and non-technical roles. A sales team cannot assume that groups delivering technology are delivering in a different way than they are selling.</p>



<p>Account management cannot build plans with customers on their future technology state and expect that planning to look different than the overall delivery workflows. Technology groups cannot adopt a different way of delivering if it is at odds with business expectations.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h3>Common Misconception #3</h3>



<div style="height:12px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<figure class="wp-block-pullquote has-border-color has-background has-small-font-size" style="border-color:#abb7c266;border-width:1px;border-radius:8px;background-color:#abb7c20d;font-style:normal;font-weight:500"><blockquote><p>DevOps can be implemented without Agile</p></blockquote></figure>



<div style="height:28px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<p>Now, that statement is a little clickbaity. You can indeed implement DevOps inside of other project management frameworks.</p>



<p>I would make the argument that you cannot fully realize the benefits of delivery transformation unless you adopt both DevOps and Agile. DevOps practices do not lend themselves well to Waterfall, but it can be done. You really lose out on all of the continuous improvement facets of DevOps which really means you are adopting some automation and calling it “DevOps”.</p>



<h3>Common Misconception #4</h3>



<div style="height:12px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<figure class="wp-block-pullquote has-border-color has-background has-small-font-size" style="border-color:#abb7c266;border-width:1px;border-radius:8px;background-color:#abb7c20d;font-style:normal;font-weight:500"><blockquote><p>When DevOps and Agile are combined, you can foregoe planning</p></blockquote></figure>



<div style="height:28px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<p>Software development always needs a great deal of planning. DevOps and agile do not let you get away without planning.</p>



<p>Agile in this case is formal agile delivery which I would argue consists of more planning, market research, feedback, and pivots than any other project management framework.</p>



<p>DevOps focuses on continuous improvement and automation which need a significant amount of planning to ensure the right areas of focus are being worked on.</p>



<p>The truth is this; development teams, operations teams, infrastructure teams, quality assurance teams, account management teams, and members of any other team benefit from having a good plan that is backed up by principles, culture, and a centralized philosophy.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h3>Common Misconception #5</h3>



<div style="height:12px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<figure class="wp-block-pullquote has-border-color has-background has-small-font-size" style="border-color:#abb7c266;border-width:1px;border-radius:8px;background-color:#abb7c20d;font-style:normal;font-weight:500"><blockquote><p>DevOps and Agile are only for small teams</p></blockquote></figure>



<div style="height:28px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<p>Teams of all sizes can benefit from these delivery methodologies. Software delivery is a complex problem that requires good communication, tools, talent, and principles to drive consistency and quality.</p>



<p>While there are an infinite number of methods that could be used to deliver technology, Agile and DevOps are formalized and prescriptive platforms to solve these complex challenges.</p>



<p>By adopting DevOps and Agile together and bringing a core set of delivery principles to an organization&#8217;s approach to delivering technology, one can actually achieve a much larger scale of delivery more quickly.</p>



<p>All of your teams are on the same page, utilizing the same tools, communicating about the same processes, and driving agile development and operations together as a unified front.</p>



<h3>Common Misconception #6</h3>



<div style="height:12px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<figure class="wp-block-pullquote has-border-color has-background has-small-font-size" style="border-color:#abb7c266;border-width:1px;border-radius:8px;background-color:#abb7c20d;font-style:normal;font-weight:500"><blockquote><p>DevOps and Agile are focused on controlling software development</p></blockquote></figure>



<div style="height:28px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<p>I would argue that this is the farthest idea from the truth. DevOps and Agile aim to democratize the delivery process across an organization&#8217;s many different value streams.</p>



<p>One of the core principles of the Scaled Agile Framework for Enterprises is to get decision-making as close to the work being performed as possible. This means that teams must work together on their high-level planning initiatives to get stories in the hands of implementers leaving them the freedom to deliver those stories any way they want to.</p>



<p>This does not mean that the business does not have a say in what is getting delivered, but how it is delivered is determined by the individuals that know best.</p>



<p>Early on in the adoption of these methodologies, it is not uncommon for a pendulum of decisions making to swing back and forth between IT and the business as everyone tries to figure out this new dynamic. Everyone&#8217;s goal should be to find a new center where everyone is heard and all concerns, no matter their size, are given room to breathe in a conversation about delivery.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>How Should I View DevOps and Agile?</h2>



<p>By fully adopting Agile and DevOps, a lot of doors are opened up for delivery.</p>



<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/benefits-of-devops/devops-flow/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Flow</a>:</strong> Instead of moving from task to task, or project to project, work can be put onto a conveyor belt of delivery. Agile and DevOps offer more of an assembly line-type flow to technology delivery.</li>



<li><strong><a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/benefits-of-devops/devops-culture-of-quality/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Quality</a>:</strong> Context switching impacts quality. By offering more stability in work coming down the pipeline, engineers in various disciplines can focus on quality first.</li>



<li><strong><a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/benefits-of-devops/flexibility/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Flexibility</a>:</strong> Companies need to meet the market where it is at. Sometimes this means quickly pivoting from products that are not working to products that do well in the market.</li>



<li><a href="https://www.valewood.org/devops-cycle-time/"><strong>Release faster and work smarter</strong>:</a> By reducing the size and scope of deliverables, the team can focus on shipping more often.</li>



<li><strong><a href="https://www.valewood.org/why-are-ci-cd-pipelines-part-of-devops/">Simplifies Software Development and Operations Focus</a></strong>: Day-to-day operations can seem like a burden that interrupts delivery frequently. By adopting DevOps, operations are a normal part of everyday life.</li>



<li><strong><a href="https://www.valewood.org/devops-trust/">Responsibility</a>:</strong> Agile helps individual contributors feel like they are part of something bigger by influencing the overall planning and delivery processes. They are not just taking orders from the tower, they are actively delivering value against their vision of great outcomes.</li>



<li><strong><a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/benefits-of-devops/consistency/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Consistency</a>:</strong> Consistency brings predictability and reliability to products and planning</li>



<li><strong>Measurement:</strong> Promote data-driven decision-making into your day-to-day workflows through predictability and consistency in the flow of work.</li>



<li><strong>Security:</strong> Security is no longer a secondary burdensome process that detracts from delivering work to the market. Security is built right into DevOps through automated delivery pipelines.</li>
</ul>



<p>Any of these benefits could be achieved on their own in their own ways. By fully embracing Agile and DevOps, each of these ideals comes with the methodology. There is no need to solve an already-solved problem.</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>When first hearing about DevOps and Agile, it is easy to build some initial blinders and misconceptions about what they really mean when utilized as a symbiotic relationship.  It takes a mindset change, and a full perspective shift to realize the benefits of DevOps and Agile together.  </p>



<p>I would encourage anyone out there to go get some training, watch some YouTube videos, and read as much as you can about the methodologies and what they have to offer.  DevOps and Agile together can really open up a lot of new benefits for your business and your customers.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Helm: Kubernetes Cluster Unreachable </title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/helm-kubernetes-cluster-unreachable/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 02:51:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Kubernetes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[howto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kubernetes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tools]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1924</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Kubernetes, while fairly mature as a platform, is still considered an emerging technology in the business space. Due to this, lots of engineers are spending their free time trying to learn about Helm which can lead to some pretty frustrating&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://kubernetes.io/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="4" title="Kubernetes" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Kubernetes</a>, while fairly mature as a platform, is still considered an emerging technology in the business space.  Due to this, lots of engineers are spending their free time trying to learn about Helm which can lead to some pretty frustrating errors.  </p>



<p>Let&#8217;s discuss why you might be receiving <code>Error: Kubernetes cluster unreachable</code> when trying to connect to your cluster for the first time.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Kubernetes Install</h2>



<p>There are a lot of different mechanisms on the market today to get Kubernetes up and running depending on your environment.  How you installed Kubernetes is important for troubleshooting later.  Review the install methods and make sure you align underneath one of them in some fashion.</p>



<h3>Local Environment</h3>



<p>Local Kubernetes is going to use <a href="https://k3s.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">k3s</a> or <a href="https://minikube.sigs.k8s.io/docs/start/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">minikube</a> to run and install a local version on a standard workstation.  This is a great way to get familiar with Kubernetes because these products will download and install all the requisite dependencies to bootstrap anyone regardless of their skill level.</p>



<h3>On-Prem Environment</h3>



<p>I am differentiating local and on-prem simply from the viewpoint of servers vs desktops.  In a more server-focused environment, many people will use <a href="https://github.com/kubernetes-sigs/kubespray" target="_blank" rel="noopener">kubespray</a> or <a href="https://github.com/kubernetes/kops" target="_blank" rel="noopener">kops</a> to deploy their Kubernetes clusters.  Kubespray will ensure that servers are properly configured through IaC while downloading and installing baseline Kubernetes.  By the time you are done, a fully functional cluster should be available.</p>



<p>Kubespray does come with a lot more knobs and dials since it makes fewer opinionated decisions about what your cluster setup should look like.  In a local environment, ingress is going to be handled in a very specific way.  In an on-prem environment, you may have network appliances that want to handle ingress in a very specific way.  Kubespray should be able to get most of your configurations taken care of for your special circumstances.</p>



<h3>Cloud Environment</h3>



<p>Cloud environments can be configured the same way on-prem environments are through kubespray and kops.  Cloud-based VM instances would be spun up on management networks and tools would be run against them to achieve a functioning cluster.</p>



<p>Most cloud providers will have their own managed Kubernetes to be used as well.  Those are probably a much safer way to get started when just starting to dabble in the Kubernetes space.  </p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://aws.amazon.com/eks/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon EKS</a></li>



<li><a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/products/kubernetes-service/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Azure AKS</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/products/kubernetes" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DigitalOcean</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vultr.com/kubernetes/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Vultr</a></li>
</ul>



<p>These solutions generally are only a few clicks away from a full-stack deployment.  Once you get a bit more comfortable, it would be a good idea to toss out your test cluster and start to move into Terraform, CloudFormation, or <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/get-started/azure-portal" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="20" title="Azure" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Azure</a> Resource Manager automation to ensure your clusters are codified for future upgrades.</p>



<h2>Error: Kubernetes cluster unreachable</h2>



<p>There are going to be a few troubleshooting steps you should take to diagnose this issue.  Each of them is going to be a little bit different depending on your deployment setup.</p>



<h3>Check Your Kubeconfig</h3>



<p>The first thing to check is your <code>$HOME/.kube/config</code> file.  This file contains all of the relevant information for connecting to your Kubernetes cluster.  It is also very important you keep this file safe and secret since it holds credentials for that connection as well.</p>



<h4>My Kubeconfig is Missing!</h4>



<p>If your kubeconfig file is missing, review your Kubernetes installation instructions for anything specific about copying a kubeconfig to the proper folder on your local machine.  The instructions may also walk you through how to create one.  Helm will not work without this file being created and in the proper location.</p>



<h4>My Kubeconfig Exists!</h4>



<p>If you open that file to read it, you will find that it is YAML formatted with connection parameters in it.  These parameters should include some certificate information, which are credentials and cluster identification verification, and a hostname for the cluster management API address.</p>



<p>If you have kubectl installed on the same machine as your kubeconfig, a simple test would be to run <code>kubectl get nodes</code> to see if you get a list of servers back from the kubernetes API.  If you get an error, then either you do not have the right level of access, or your kubeconfig is not properly configured.  See above <strong>&#8220;My Kubeconfig is Missing&#8221;</strong>.</p>



<p>If this works as intended, and you see a list of servers the next step is to ensure that your kubeconfig is on the same computer that you would like to run helm from.  If you are running helm from a local workstation, make sure you have a proper kubeconfig on that workstation.  If you are running helm from a different server, ensure a kubeconfig is provided for that server.  Make sure to re-test.</p>



<h4>Check Networking</h4>



<p>Helm communicates with the Kubernetes API over port 6443.  Using NMap to check ports, ensure that the machine you are intending to run helm from has clear line of sight communication with the Kubernetes cluster over port 6443.  This can be achieved on Linux via this command: nmap –p 6443 {{cluster address/master hostname}}.  You can find the cluster address/master hostname inside of a validated kubeconfig.</p>



<p>If you are using Windows and looking for an example of how to do port scans, I would suggest switching to Linux or Mac.</p>



<p>If ports show closed or filtered, network communication will not be established with the cluster and Helm will not be able to run configurations.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Additional Resources</h2>



<p>The steps outlined above should get you pointed in the right direction when you receive Helm errors when trying to contact your cluster for the first time.</p>



<p>If you did not find the answers you needed via this article, I have added a few additional resources below that may be able to help get you sorted out.  If you have additional information to share on this topic, please <a href="https://www.valewood.org/contact/" data-type="page" data-id="984">contact me</a> and I will update this post to reflect any changes.</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/k3s-io/k3s/issues/1126" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GitHub</a></li>



<li><a href="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/63066604/error-kubernetes-cluster-unreachable-get-http-localhost8080-versiontimeou" target="_blank" rel="noopener">StackOverflow</a></li>



<li><a href="https://pet2cattle.com/2022/07/install-helm-k3s" data-type="URL" data-id="https://pet2cattle.com/2022/07/install-helm-k3s" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Pet2Cattle</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>DevOps Roll-up: November 2022</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/devops-roll-up-novembers-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 22:08:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[roll-up]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1909</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Below is a list of DevOps articles/sites that I discovered over the past month and found interesting. Linux Troubleshooting This is an interesting tool that people can use to test out their Linux troubleshooting skills in a capture-the-flag-style event. Here&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Below is a list of <a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> articles/sites that I discovered over the past month and found interesting.</p>



<h2>Linux Troubleshooting</h2>



<p>This is an interesting tool that people can use to test out their Linux troubleshooting skills in a capture-the-flag-style event.</p>



<p>Here is what the developer has to say about their SadServers:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>There is a collection of scenarios, a description of what&#8217;s wrong, and a test to check if the issue has been solved. Servers are spun up on the spot, users get an &#8220;SSH&#8221; shell via a browser window to an ephemeral server (destroyed after the allotted time for solving the challenge) and then they can try and solve the problem.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Check it out with the link below if you are looking to up your server administration game!</p>



<p><a href="https://github.com/fduran/sadservers" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://github.com/fduran/sadservers</a></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity is-style-wide"/>



<p></p>



<h2>DevOps and Software Engineering Job Board</h2>



<p>This is a job board that is centralizing DevOps and Software Engineering jobs on a single board.  I am a big fan of boards like this because they are more targeted and promote more realistic expectations for jobs you might be looking for.</p>



<p><a href="https://software-engineer-jobs.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://software-engineer-jobs.com/</a></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity is-style-wide"/>



<p></p>



<h2>Golang Network Bus</h2>



<p>An event bus is a core component in a microservices-based architecture.  Application A (in control of Domain A) will register an event on the event bus every time a data change needs to be synchronized by downstream systems.  Application B (which needs to reference data from Domain A) will then be able to store its own local copy of Domain A&#8217;s data to reduce dependencies on an external system.</p>



<p>I love seeing projects like this get introduced into the ecosystem.  Many times, we are relying on highly scaleable systems with a massive amount of configurable knobs and dials to achieve relatively simple tasks.  Tools like this are a great way to get your feet wet and dive into a new architecture without all of the extensive overhead of enterprise tools.</p>



<p><a href="https://github.com/kamalshkeir/kbus" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://github.com/kamalshkeir/kbus</a></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity is-style-wide"/>



<p></p>



<h2>Searchable Asset Directory</h2>



<p>Resmo bills itself as:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>Complete visibility and security for modern teams</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Centralized asset inventory management is a huge deal in DevOps.  By scanning your assets, you can understand what is out of compliance and subsequently investigate where errors may be happening in automation to allow for that noncompliance.  Without this kind of visibility, changes will go unchecked which makes quality suffer.</p>



<p>Another nice feature of a CAIM product like this is; they are a great Single Point of Truth system.  I have utilized these in the past as an API-driven data repository to feed other downstream automation systems with data they need to accomplish their tasks.</p>



<p>Check them out below!</p>



<p><a href="https://www.resmo.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://www.resmo.com/</a></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity is-style-wide"/>



<p></p>



<h2>Kustomize</h2>



<p>Kustomize is a great way to keep your configuration files declarative and free of messy variables and if statements.  Configure your application how you would like and then provide specific override files for different environments.  The video below will teach you how to make production ready <a href="https://kubernetes.io/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="4" title="Kubernetes" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Kubernetes</a> manifests.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Kustomize: The Best Way to Manage Your Kubernetes Configs" width="1170" height="658" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/spCdNeNCuFU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity is-style-wide"/>



<p></p>



<h2>Steampunk Spotter</h2>



<p>Steampunk Spotter is an <a href="https://www.ansible.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="7" title="Ansible">Ansible</a> tool for Development, Quality Assurance, and Operations teams purpose-built to cut down on the management burden of keeping playbooks current.  With built-in upgrade assistance, syntax checking, module assistance, vulnerability identification, and much more!  </p>



<p>If you are interested in super charging your Ansible automation, check them out below!</p>



<p><a href="https://steampunk.si/spotter/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://steampunk.si/spotter/</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/spCdNeNCuFU" medium="video" width="1280" height="720">
			<media:player url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/spCdNeNCuFU" />
			<media:title type="plain">Kustomize: The Best Way to Manage Your Kubernetes Configs</media:title>
			<media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Kustomize is a way to customize your Kubernetes manifests files.  In this video I go over everything you you need to know about the theory of Kustomize as we...]]></media:description>
			<media:thumbnail url="/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/devops-rollup-november.jpg" />
			<media:rating scheme="urn:simple">nonadult</media:rating>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Which Term Accurately Describes Agile and DevOps?</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/which-term-describes-devops-and-agile/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 22:20:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops consistency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opinion]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1796</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[DevOps is a culture and methodology that an organization can prescribe to aid in velocity, consistency, stability, and flow of value to the market. Often confused with &#8220;automation&#8221; being the only benefit of DevOps, the core principles behind DevOps offer&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> is a culture and methodology that an organization can prescribe to aid in velocity, consistency, stability, and <a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/benefits-of-devops/devops-flow/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="28" title="Understanding the DevOps Process Flow in 2022" target="_blank" rel="noopener">flow of value</a> to the market.  Often confused with &#8220;automation&#8221; being the only benefit of DevOps, the core principles behind DevOps offer a common set of ideals that a team can align under and strive to achieve.</p>



<p>Big A Agile is a project management methodology that pairs well with DevOps to aid in rationalizing work delivery against a set of guardrails.  Agile also provides prescriptive visibility to work being performed ensuring engineers are not being overloaded by overwhelming business priorities.</p>



<p>With those descriptions out of the way, what term best describes both Agile and DevOps?</p>



<h2>Consistency</h2>



<p>The goal of any organization going through change is to drive consistency in delivery.  Without consistency, a technology group cannot adapt to change and a business cannot meet the market where it is at.  </p>



<p>By driving consistency, a business gets predictability which is powerful when scoping and planning new work.  By understanding real velocity, not aspirational velocity, a business can invest in its people and products to grow at a more sustainable rate.</p>



<p>By driving consistency, technologists get the predictability that they need to make sound and rational decisions about how to approach work.  When working against an unpredictable cycle, technology groups will quickly get overwhelmed by the rate of change and produce solutions that do not meet the demands of the market.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Why Consistency Matters and How it Influences Velocity</h2>



<p>Consistency is important for a couple of factors.  First, individual contributors like their jobs and are not really interested in consistent interruptions or unplanned requests.  While some people may look at those facets as an everyday part of doing business, they can be avoided if mitigation steps are put in place.</p>



<p>When people are constantly interrupted quality suffers.  There is no way around that.  Technology is complex and people need time to focus and go through their problem-solving routines.</p>



<p>Second, inconsistency in delivery has impacts on customers and their delivery.  In technology, you are generally not just working on your system.  There are consumers of your systems who have expectations of either utilization or integration.  By being inconsistent in delivery, you cannot manage the expectations of your consumers.</p>



<p>Lastly, a lack of consistency means that you will never really understand your velocity.  Velocity is important because it tells you how much of X you can get by spending Y.  Think about it like auto manufacturing, they could turn the manufacturing dials up to 11 in their facilities but then you will end up with cars with 3 wheels or loose nuts and bolts.</p>



<p>A trap that we fall into frequently is confusing aspirational velocity with real velocity.  Aspirational velocity is the speed that someone thinks something should get delivered.  Real velocity is a measurement of what can be delivered at a given speed.</p>



<h3>Real Velocity vs Aspirational Velocity</h3>



<p>Aspirational velocity is when a leader says &#8220;We need this product to launch by X date!&#8221;.  We have either all been in that position or will be in that position sometime in our careers.</p>



<p>Without proper support, investment, and foresight in planning; aspirational velocity will almost always end with sub-standard products that greatly increase the future cost to the business.  Leaning harder on anyone in the delivery space always leads to decisions that are short-sighted toward a narrow goal.</p>



<p>I believe aspirational velocity is firmly rooted in the idea of needing to &#8220;take a shot&#8221;.  Checks are constantly being written that others are expected to cash.  Sometimes this works out and I would say can be necessary for a startup or green field project.  Any organization looking to grow over time should be looking for its tipping point when aspirational velocity needs to transition into real velocity to offer a more reliable work environment for their employees.</p>



<p>Real velocity is based on the idea that you are going to make hard choices about which work is important to feed into a model where delivery is consistent.  When more work needs to be done than can be achieved by the current velocity, hard choices will be made to cut work, increase staff, defer work, or invest in current technology to increase velocity.  </p>



<p>Any business should have a firm goal of understanding its real velocity and do everything in its power to tamp down or extinguish aspirational velocity.</p>



<h2>DevOps and Agile are Closely Related</h2>



<p>I have another article that describes how DevOps and Agile are related to each other.  Primarily, Agile is about lean work being performed against targets and goals with frequent demos of the work being completed to influence pivots.  Agile was in need of a technology delivery methodology that could help realize the fundamental mission of Agile. </p>



<p>You can read more about how <a href="https://www.valewood.org/devops-and-agile/" data-type="post" data-id="1264">DevOps and Agile are related here!</a></p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Runners Up</h2>



<p>This question is also asked on a few official exams.  I want to make sure that my perspective on DevOps does not overshadow exams that do not have as much wiggle room in their answers.</p>



<h3>Brainly.in</h3>



<p><a href="https://brainly.in/" data-type="URL" data-id="https://brainly.in/question/36271184" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Brainly</a> answers the question like this:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>Agile is refers to an interative approuch which focuses on collaboration, costumer feedback,and small rapid releases,DevOps is considered a practice bringing development and operations teams together.</p>
<cite>https://brainly.in/question/36271184</cite></blockquote>



<p>The problem is, I don&#8217;t think this answer refers to a specific term.  We can look at this and assume that they are looking at Agile and DevOps as two holistically different approaches which are getting merged together instead of looking for commonality between the project management methodology and the technology delivery methodology.</p>



<p>While this may sound really good on a test, there are real business influences that come from each of the facets that they list in their answer.</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Collaboration</strong>: Greater collaboration brings more of a hive-mind approach to problem-solving.  Too much collaboration on very large problems can bring analysis paralysis.  By breaking problems down into tiny and lean releases, everyone can stay more focused on achieving goals instead of trying to eat an entire elephant all at once.</li>



<li><strong>Customer Feedback</strong>: Agile focused on getting valuable work products out to the market quickly to reduce investment risk.  Getting feedback from customers is a great way to manage risk and pivot quickly if needed. </li>



<li><strong>Small Rapid Releases</strong>: To further the idea of managing risk, lessening the size of your releases helps you containerize risk into much smaller units.  If something isn&#8217;t working as expected, or the market shifts drastically, it is far less painful to throw that work out and pivot to something more palatable.  Additionally, the risk is lowered on incremental improvements to new features for existing functionality since the introduced change should not pose as great of an impact on an already healthy ecosystem.  This is something <a href="https://blog.cloudflare.com/october-2021-facebook-outage/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Facebook</a> could learn a thing or two about.</li>



<li><strong>Bringing DevOps and Operations Teams Together</strong>: This is the typical textbook definition of DevOps.  The reality is, DevOps and Agile are about breaking down silos and creating fully cross-functional teams who are able to fully deliver work in a highly efficient and lean way.  DevOps and Agile help drive decision-making down as close to the work being performed as possible while offering up a management framework to transparently keep other interested parties informed while work is being completed and shipped.</li>
</ul>



<p>As you can see, there are a lot of nuances packed into each one of those bullet points.</p>



<h3>Intellipaat.com </h3>



<p><a href="https://intellipaat.com/" data-type="URL" data-id="https://intellipaat.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Intellipatt</a> answers the question like this</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>A set of values and principles. Because both follow a set of principles and offer the value that is similar.</p>
<cite>https://intellipaat.com/community/74027/which-term-accurately-describes-agile-and-devops</cite></blockquote>



<p>I believe that this answer is a primarily business-focused answer looking to understand the idea of value in the market.  While it is not an incorrect way to look at things, I do not believe it is the most important way to look at DevOps and Agile.  </p>



<p>Value is a byproduct of DevOps and Agile.  The real benefit to DevOps and Agile is the consistent way that said value gets delivered to the market.  This means that you can calculate and quantify value through data-driven decision-making.  You are also able to manage market expectations and take potentially larger leaps to satisfy your customers.</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>The key to any technology product&#8217;s success is consistency.  DevOps and Agile offer consistency while remaining flexible and focused on common non-functional requirements like reliability and stability.  Other facets of Agile and DevOps like value are byproducts of a team or teams of teams who fully embrace the complementary delivery methodologies.</p>



<p>How would you boil DevOps and Agile down to a single term?  <a href="https://www.valewood.org/contact/" data-type="page" data-id="984">Contact me</a> and let me know!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why DevOps is Boring in 2022?</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/more-like-boringops/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 18:04:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[delivery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1786</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[DevOps is a hot topic in the technology world. It&#8217;s no longer just an isolated set of tools and processes which promise an automated future, it’s an entire culture that’s infiltrating every facet of software development. This post will try&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> is a hot topic in the technology world. It&#8217;s no longer just an isolated set of tools and processes which promise an automated future, it’s an entire culture that’s infiltrating every facet of software development.</p>



<p>This post will try to explain why the DevOps methodology itself is not boring.  We will also try to explain why a feeling of boredom stems from properly implemented tools and processes. We also dive into how you can make DevOps more exciting while keeping your sanity intact.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>What Does DevOps Mean?</h2>



<p>The term DevOps, or “development operations,” first appeared in the tech world in the early 2000s. It was a term used to describe a certain type of organization that was responsible for the entire application and software development lifecycle, from ideation to production.</p>



<p>Teams would be responsible for both the development and operations workflows, providing a more efficient way of working. As DevOps has grown in popularity, it has expanded beyond just operations teams.</p>



<p>Now, people are interested in speeding up their software development process using the term DevOps to describe the combined usage of infrastructure automation tools and best practices for team collaboration and communication.</p>



<p>There are two main components within DevOps that drive the culture. They are infrastructure as code and automated delivery. IaC is really just a way of organizing your code and infrastructure so that it is easily reproducible and shareable. Automated delivery is a method for automatically deploying applications and configurations without human intervention.</p>



<p>With the increase in automation, engineers may find themselves wondering when the next exciting change event may present itself. They may also wonder if they are automating themselves out of a job.</p>



<p>As a basis for understanding DevOps, you must understand that this practice exists to remove the excitement of a chaotic technology delivery process. DevOps is meant to be boring by nature.</p>



<p>As a side effect of DevOps being stable and consistent, organizations must look for other ways to keep their software engineers and DevOps engineers engaged through other means of excitement.</p>



<h2>Why is DevOps Boring?</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Why DevOps is Boring in 2022" width="1170" height="658" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bP5nWWFV2gg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p>As companies begin implementing modern DevOps practices, some people may notice a lull in excitement. The tools, processes, and overall culture of DevOps may feel exciting at first but quickly turn into monotony. Why?</p>



<p>DevOps becomes boring because people approach it as a checklist. They focus on the tools and processes and completely ignore the culture and mindset that lies behind the methodology.</p>



<p>These people don’t understand why they are implementing certain tools or why they are following specific processes. They are just doing it because they read an article that said their company should be adopting DevOps, or they read a book that talked about the “predictable <a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/benefits-of-devops/devops-flow/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="28" title="Understanding the DevOps Process Flow in 2022" target="_blank" rel="noopener">flow of value</a>”.</p>



<p>What makes DevOps exciting is the culture behind it. The practices and tools are just the means of achieving a certain culture. If you try to implement DevOps but don’t adopt the correct mindset and culture behind it, then you are going to end up with a boring and ineffective implementation.</p>



<h3>Fewer Natural Learning and Growth Opportunities</h3>



<p>A stable DevOps lifecycle will inherently bring a lower number of emerging technologies and opportunities to integrate emerging technologies. Sure, early on in DevOps adoption, the emerging tech will be all the rage, but that will subside as stability and consistency are driven into the pipeline.</p>



<p>Since continuous improvement is a fundamental principle of DevOps, teams should be encouraged to do some data-driven analysis looking for opportunities to become more efficient in their delivery cycles.</p>



<p>Pivots can also be made within the team. Someone who is primarily focused on ops should be put in a position to both share what they are doing and also be presented with opportunities to look at other fields like coding or security. This is true for all specialties that make up a function DevOps team.</p>



<h3>Comfort in Previous Success</h3>



<p>All too often, I see companies in the industry falling back on the comfort of their successes as an excuse to not rapidly evolve. DevOps should be putting companies in a position where pivots are much easier to pull off. Secondarily keeping a DNA of being lean and nimble should be a focus of any company.</p>



<p>Any company sitting back on its heels thinking it can keep doing what they are doing forever is going to be consumed by its competitors operating at a different level. Break that cycle by listening to the opportunities being presented by your DevOps Engineers and your Software Engineers to keep DevOps from becoming boring and your company from stagnating.</p>



<h3>Never Being Complete or Finished</h3>



<p>When completing a project, a person can get a huge dopamine rush along with a personal sense of accomplishment. DevOps doesn’t really offer that in large quantities. Work is much more methodical, incremental, and bite-sized meaning a team’s ability to celebrate a big win is less frequent.</p>



<p>If you want to truly adopt a culture of continuous improvement, you need to make sure that your team is constantly learning and improving their knowledge. This means your team should be continually looking for new books, podcasts, and ways that they can expand their skill set, improve their knowledge, and learn new things.</p>



<p>When DevOps is paired with Agile, those opportunities are even more spread apart. Everyone on the team is incrementally feeding their work into a larger integrated system. Resources may be assigned to a larger initiative for only a short period of time before being rolled off to another set of work.</p>



<h3>DevOps Engineers are a Figment of your Imagination</h3>



<p>A DevOps Engineer does not exist. They are not real. Yetis are more real than DevOps Engineers are.</p>



<p>DevOps is a methodology and a culture that does not require a role engineer it. There are many engineering practices that compose a full team practicing DevOps. Confusion about what someone is really intended to be working on will leave those individuals to fend for themselves and miss out on a healthy team dynamic.</p>



<p>When culture is suffering in a team practicing DevOps it can become boring or worse extremely frustrating. There is not a shared vision or goal that team is trying to achieve. This means that the work being performed is being done in isolation and under-appreciated. Let’s face it, we are not doing our jobs for our own health, we do them to contribute to something bigger than ourselves.</p>



<h3>The Hype Train</h3>



<p>I see a lot of posts on <a target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.reddit.com/">Reddit</a> which have individuals from different disciplines looking to make the jump from their current career path over to DevOps. Most of what I read leads me to believe that they are being sold a bill of goods which just isn’t reality.</p>



<p>While I do believe that problem-solving in a space fully embracing DevOps is more complex than in any more traditional space, I do not believe that most companies are embracing DevOps fully. This means that job applicants are applying for and landing DevOps positions that are not actually meeting the spirit of DevOps. Organizations are generally looking for a little bit of help automating some manual processes but stop short of full adoption.</p>



<p>This will lead engineers to be as bored at this new shiny DevOps role as they were in their former system administration role.</p>



<h3>Running out of People to Blame</h3>



<p>Office politics can be entertaining to some. In a fully functioning DevOps culture, everything is treated as code, tested in code, operations happen in code, and releases are automated all of which remove a lot of formal human interaction in the daily development and release cycle.</p>



<p>Game of Thrones was not popular because Joffrey methodically picked apart Rob Stark and his armies. GoT was popular because of the drama, suspense, twists, and turns. Now, the office should not be a Game of Thrones style drama, but; DevOps is very good at transitioning from a culture full of interpersonal conflict into a blameless culture focused purely on technology which can be boring.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>What Are Some Examples of Engineers Boredom Executing DevOps?</h2>



<p>Below are some examples of different roles and how they can become bored with their job when DevOps is being practically utilized for its processes but not viewed as a persistent growth opportunity.</p>



<h3>Debbie Developer has a Case of the Mondays</h3>



<p>Debbie became a software engineer because of her love for puzzles. Solving complex scenarios and producing elegant maintainable code is her passion.</p>



<p>Early on in the DevOps adoption process, she was jazzed that there was a whole host of new problems to solve when transforming a traditional set of build jobs into something that could support CI/CD.</p>



<p>As time has progressed, she is feeling less fulfilled in her day-to-day job. The kinds of work she is performing have become far less complex and much smaller. There is almost no coordination between members of her team since she can just push code at will and let automation take over to push it into production.</p>



<p>It is the same daily slog over and over and over again.</p>



<h3>Simon the Systems Administrator is Running Out of Work To Do</h3>



<p>Servers create themselves. Simon doesn&#8217;t need to log into the <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="14" title="AWS" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">AWS</a> console anymore to check anything because the platform is completely self-service.</p>



<p>When adopting DevOps, systems administrators will often find themselves developing a lot of code around system configurations. This works well because in their specific domain, they want consistency and operational efficiency.</p>



<p>Over time, Simon&#8217;s work has been extremely helpful in level-setting expectations around solid delivery patterns. But what is next for Simon? There does not appear to be any new or related systems on the horizon for Simon to continue to grow his skills. Growth has stagnated and there really isn&#8217;t a path forward for Simon to earn a senior systems administrator position.</p>



<h3>Quintin Feels Like Their Role as a Quality Assurance Engineer is Monotonous</h3>



<p>Developers are writing their own unit, functional, and integration acceptance tests. Quintin is left building some visual testing to be added to the delivery pipeline.</p>



<p>Quality assurance engineers are the glue that holds a development community together. They are well-versed in requirements and testing and they are constantly working with their developer counterparts to ensure their work will be accepted by customers.</p>



<p>DevOps can take away this sense of community in the development process. Individuals are responsible for contributing their own tests while they write code. As tests are passed, the code moves its way into production.</p>



<p>DevOps has effectively worked Quintin out of a job.</p>



<h3>Connie the Cloud Engineer is Struggling to Provide Value</h3>



<p>DevOps pipelines will consist of application code, test automation, system automation, and infrastructure automation (cloud or on-prem). Once developed, engineers will shift focus to day 2 operations. Once day 2 operations are tackled, what&#8217;s left?</p>



<p>Connie felt value and excitement in the early days of DevOps, but is now isolated away from the rest of the team because systems have been stabilized, security is second nature, and AWS is effectively running itself.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>5 Tips to Make DevOps Exciting Again!</h2>



<p>We’ve covered why DevOps can become tedious, but what can you do about it? If you want to make DevOps exciting again, then you have to understand why it is exciting in the first place!</p>



<p>The reason DevOps is exciting for most companies is because of the focus on drastically improving your software development process. It’s a way of improving communication, collaboration, and the overall quality of your software. It’s a way of adopting a culture of automation.</p>



<p>Automation is important in DevOps because it directly impacts the speed of your software release cycles. It can also help improve the overall quality of your software as well as your organization.</p>



<p>Automation is a core component of DevOps. When you make automation a core part of your development process, you are able to reduce the number of repetitive tasks your organization has to perform. This means you can put less focus on manual tasks, and more focus on things that actually improve your software and the company as a whole.</p>



<h3>Provide Growth Opportunities</h3>



<p>Some companies confuse growth with “opportunities to become a manager”. Most of the really good engineers and architects that I have met will “manage” a project because they want to see it succeed not because they want to be a manager.</p>



<p>Providing opportunities for growth in knowledge, automation, systems, development, operations, platforms, consulting, or any other area that your services or products may not be fully taking advantage of today.</p>



<p>As an example, if you have an awesome set of pipelines that obfuscate some of the complexities of doing automated delivery, challenge your team to package that up and white-label it. Have them use those packages to consult with other teams in your organization to level their automation skills up.</p>



<h3>Inject Failures</h3>



<p>We are always focused on delivering key projects, functionality, or needs of the business. With a narrow view of the world being delivered first, that does not leave a lot of room to poke at the softer edges of your products.</p>



<p>Introduce automated failure models like a chaos monkey. Start with planned times and have your chaos monkey start to take down some low criticality services and review the characteristics of what that means. There may be impacts in areas that you were not expecting.</p>



<p>This provides an opportunity to add some advanced troubleshooting to an area that the DevOps methodology took away through its inherent consistency and stability.</p>



<h3>Incorporate User Feedback Into DevOps Processes</h3>



<p>User feedback is important to any business because it allows you to understand your customers and discover ways to improve your product. However, user feedback is hard to come by because customers don’t usually interact with businesses on a consistent basis.</p>



<p>In order to incorporate user feedback into your software development lifecycle, you need to be able to get consistent feedback from customers. There are two main ways to do this:</p>



<ul>
<li>Use survey tools to let customers provide feedback on your product, team, and company.</li>



<li>Let customers interact with your team using live chat tools.</li>
</ul>



<p>Both of these tools are easy to implement and can help you get useful and consistent feedback from customers. Feedback is also a great way to breathe some excitement into an otherwise stagnant work environment.</p>



<h3>Be Realistic with Expectations</h3>



<p>As I stated above, DevOps Engineers are not real. Business leaders need to come to grips with this fact and be very realistic with expectations around roles and work assignments. If you are looking to shortcut full DevOps adoption by hiring some DevOps engineers as a gap fill, you will not be able to provide an exciting environment that keeps your technology groups engaged.</p>



<h3>Celebrate Completion</h3>



<p>Get your teams together to do some good old-fashioned team building. Wins are wins no matter how big or small they are. Recognize your team’s accomplishments because they deserve to be recognized.</p>



<p>The methodical pace of DevOps and Agile do not lend themselves to recognizing big wins or the sheer volume of work that it really takes to get to those wins. Team leads should focus on bringing their teams back to the center by recapping how much success they have had knowing their work is never done.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>DevOps is not boring. It is an exciting change in the way that organizations approach software development. However, it is only exciting if you fully commit to the culture of DevOps and all the benefits it has to offer.</p>



<p>If you just implement the tools and processes without the culture and mindset, then you are only doing half the work and missing out on the benefits of the fully implemented DevOps culture.</p>



<p>If you want to make DevOps exciting again, you must ensure that you are fully committed to the culture. Only then will you be able to make the most of everything that DevOps has to offer.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bP5nWWFV2gg" medium="video" width="1280" height="720">
			<media:player url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bP5nWWFV2gg" />
			<media:title type="plain">Why DevOps is Boring in 2022</media:title>
			<media:description type="html"><![CDATA[DevOps is a hot topic in the technology world. It’s no longer just an isolated set of tools and processes which promise an automated future, it’s an entire c...]]></media:description>
			<media:thumbnail url="/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/devops-boring.jpg" />
			<media:rating scheme="urn:simple">nonadult</media:rating>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>DevOps Cycle Times: The Difference Between Good and Bad Performance</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/devops-cycle-time/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 14:12:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops cycle time]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sdlc]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1700</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The performance of the DevOps cycle is a crucial measure of your success. If it’s good, you are on track to meet your objectives; if it’s bad, you need to make some changes. The DevOps cycle performance has three main&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The performance of the <a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> cycle is a crucial measure of your success. If it’s good, you are on track to meet your objectives; if it’s bad, you need to make some changes. The DevOps cycle performance has three main factors: lead time, cycle time, and throughput.</p>



<p>You can use these metrics to inform your team about where there may be issues in your process that need addressing. Each of these factors indicates a different part of the DevOps cycle:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Lead time</strong> refers to the total length of time from when an order is placed until it is sent out for delivery.</li>



<li><strong>Cycle time</strong> is how long it takes from when a new version of code is checked in to when it becomes available for production users. It measures how much time elapses between every phase of production and points out potential bottlenecks in your process.</li>



<li><strong>Throughput</strong> measures how many units are produced within a specific timeframe (e.g., the number of orders per hour).</li>
</ul>



<p>When monitoring the performance of these metrics, it is important to keep them balanced across all three categories; if one value falls too low or high, adjustments may need to be made.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Lead Time</h2>



<p>The lead time is the length of time it takes from when an order is placed until it is sent out for delivery. To improve this, you can look at two aspects of your process: Shipping and Demand management.</p>



<p>If shipping is taking a long time, check that your team is following a strict process for shipping that is as streamlined as possible. This way, it will be much easier to track and make improvements. If demand management is the issue, you might need to review your sales strategy.</p>



<p>How many orders are being placed per day is the first thing to look at. If demand is low, you can consider ways to increase it, such as marketing campaigns. If orders are high, you might have trouble meeting them due to the length of time it takes to process them. If it is taking a long time to fulfill orders, you can use a kanban board to track them and make sure they don’t get stuck in the process.</p>



<h2>Cycle Time</h2>



<p>Cycle time is the time it takes from when a new version of code is checked in to when that code becomes available for production users. It measures how much time elapses between every phase of production and points out potential bottlenecks in your process.</p>



<p>To improve this, you can look at two aspects of your process: Code deployment and Testing. If it is taking a long time to deploy code, check the tools you are using; they may not be working as efficiently as they could. If testing is taking too long, you might need to add more resources to your testing team.</p>



<h2>Throughput</h2>



<p>Throughput is the number of units produced within a specific timeframe. If throughput is low, you may have too high a lead time for your cycle time. This can be corrected by improving your shipping process or by reducing the time it takes to produce the product.</p>



<p>If throughput is high, you may have too low a cycle time for your lead time. This can be corrected by reducing the time it takes to produce the product or by increasing the time it takes to send it out.</p>



<h2>Continuous Improvement Strategies</h2>



<p>There are several strategies you can employ to improve the efficiency of your DevOps cycle, including:</p>



<ul>
<li>Reducing the time it takes to complete all processes, such as testing and deployment.</li>



<li>Reallocating employees to where they are needed most, such as adding more people to your testing team if testing is taking too long.</li>



<li>Streamlining processes, such as using a kanban board to improve visibility and reduce bottlenecks.</li>



<li>Improving software quality, such as using automated tests and code reviews to catch issues early.</li>



<li>Improving your customer experience, such as tracking customer complaints and addressing them promptly.</li>
</ul>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>The performance of the DevOps cycle is a crucial measure of your success. If it’s good, you are on track to meet your objectives; if it’s bad, you need to make some changes. The DevOps cycle performance has three main factors: lead time, cycle time, and throughput.</p>



<p>You can use these metrics to inform your team about where there may be issues in your process that need addressing. Each of these factors indicates a different part of the DevOps cycle:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Lead time </strong>refers to the total length of time from when an order is placed until it is sent out for delivery.</li>



<li><strong>Cycle time</strong> is how long it takes from when a new version of code is checked in to when it becomes available for production users. It measures how much time elapses between every phase of production and points out potential bottlenecks in your process.</li>



<li><strong>Throughput</strong> measures how many units are produced within a specific timeframe (e.g., the number of orders per hour).</li>
</ul>



<p>When monitoring the performance of these metrics, it is important to keep them balanced across all three categories; if one value falls too low or high, adjustments may need to be made.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Importance of Constant Monitoring and Feedback</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/devops-monitoring/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2022 20:39:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[day2ops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops monitoring and feedback]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tools]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1674</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[DevOps is an approach to software development and operation, where teams are able to collaborate more effectively and accelerate software releases from development to production. As a result, organizations can release new features faster and with higher quality. The need&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> is an approach to software development and operation, where teams are able to collaborate more effectively and accelerate software releases from development to production. As a result, organizations can release new features faster and with higher quality.</p>



<p>The need for speed and collaboration across departments is what’s driving many organizations toward DevOps. But it’s not just about faster software releases; it’s about releasing higher quality software faster by enabling the people who build and support applications (known as operators) to react to changing conditions quickly, proactively, and directly.</p>



<p>In this blog post, we will discuss why monitoring and feedback are critical in accelerating your path toward DevOps while maintaining your company’s high standards for quality.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Why is Monitoring so Important in a DevOps Environment?</h2>



<p>All organizations should be monitoring their software and the underlying infrastructure on which their applications run. But when you’re implementing a DevOps approach, monitoring becomes even more important because it provides visibility into the application environment and alerts when things are not running as expected.</p>



<p>With a traditional software development lifecycle, engineers would build the application, test it, and then push it out to a staging server environment where operations professionals would monitor it to make sure it’s up and running. When the app was determined to be good to go, the operations team would then push it out to production.</p>



<p>In a DevOps environment, the handoff between development and operations happens much more frequently. In some cases, developers may be responsible for deploying to production or at the very least, testing their code on staging servers before operations engineers deploy it to production.</p>



<p>With the rapid releases that happen to production in a DevOps environment, small changes can have large impacts on the reliability and stability of applications.  By building monitoring and observability directly into a delivery pipeline, the parties responsible for shipping code are the same parties responsible for making sure that the code is operating as expected.  </p>



<p> DevOps advocates for smaller more frequent releases meaning drift can happen over time.  Features that performed well several months ago may have gotten incrementally worse over time.  Observability helps identify these issues and ensures that future work is scheduled to adequately remediate issues from organic growth before they turn into production outages.</p>



<h3>The Importance of Monitoring in a DevOps Environment</h3>



<p>As we’ve discussed, there are many benefits to implementing a DevOps model versus a traditional software development lifecycle. But what exactly does monitoring have to do with DevOps? It’s no coincidence that monitoring is one of the core components of DevOps.</p>



<p>The mere act of monitoring software, infrastructure, and network performance is the important first step in taking advantage of the benefits of DevOps. And when you’re monitoring, you’re also able to analyze and gain insight into your current state based on real-time data.</p>



<p>While companies are in the process of implementing a DevOps approach, monitoring becomes even more important as it can help you identify potential bottlenecks in your software delivery pipeline.</p>



<h2>Benefits of Monitoring in a DevOps Environment</h2>



<ul>
<li><strong>Increased insight into the current state: </strong>Monitoring gives you the ability to see and understand the current state of your applications, network, and infrastructure. Without monitoring, you would have no visibility into the current state, which makes it more difficult to identify issues and resolve them.</li>



<li><strong>Sensitivity to application issues: </strong>When you’re monitoring, you’re able to quickly detect issues, both big and small, that disrupt the flow of your business. This includes issues such as a website or app outage, poor performance, increased latency, security issues, and more.</li>



<li><strong>Ability to resolve issues quickly: </strong>When monitoring is part of your software delivery pipeline and you’re able to recognize and resolve issues quickly, you’re able to decrease the amount of time it takes to restore normal operations.</li>



<li><strong>Predictability: </strong>Monitoring also gives you the ability to predict what will happen next, which can be helpful when planning for upcoming events such as conferences or holidays. By understanding the current state, you can predict what might happen next and prepare for it.</li>
</ul>



<h2>Monitor Constantly to Understand the Current State Continuously</h2>



<h3>Machine Data</h3>



<p>Data points that are generated and collected by application and infrastructure monitoring tools are known as machine data. Machine data is a fantastic source of data to understand the current state of your applications. Machine data is generated and collected at the application level, which gives you an accurate representation of what is happening in your environment.</p>



<h3>Human-Generated Data</h3>



<p>As you’re monitoring, you also capture human-generated data, which is data that is entered into the system manually. For example, if you receive a ticket about a performance issue, this would be recorded as human-generated data. Although human-generated data is not as accurate as machine data, it gives insight into what is happening in the application environment.</p>



<h2>Monitor Constantly to Understand Why Something Happened</h2>



<p>Monitoring gives you the ability to understand why something happened, which can be beneficial when it comes to debugging issues and resolving them quickly.</p>



<h3>Application Logs</h3>



<p>Application logs are a fantastic source of why something happened because they show a timeline of events. This can help you identify bottlenecks in your application, when various events occur, when errors are thrown, and much more.</p>



<h3>Tracing</h3>



<p>Tracing is another source of why something happened. Tracing is a way to visualize the path that packets take as they move through the network. This can be helpful if you notice something in the application logs, but you’re not sure where the problem is.</p>



<h2>Monitor Constantly to Predict What Will Happen Next</h2>



<p>Monitoring gives you the ability to predict what will happen next by giving you insight into the current state as well as why certain things happened. This can be helpful when planning for upcoming events such as conferences or holidays.</p>



<h3>Application Performance</h3>



<p>By understanding the current state, you can predict what will happen next with application performance. This can help you proactively prepare for upcoming events that require a heavier lift, such as sales or Black Friday events.</p>



<h3>System Performance</h3>



<p>There are several cardinal sins when it comes to system monitoring.</p>



<ul>
<li>Running out of disk space</li>



<li>Memory swapping to disk</li>



<li>Connectivity issues</li>



<li>CPU being pegged at 100% constantly</li>
</ul>



<p>Any of these issues (along with dozens of other cardinal sins) are the types of issues that don&#8217;t get forgiven often when they show up in an RCA.  By doing trend analysis on systems, capacity can more readily be predicted and proper measures can be taken before the only corrective action is to buy more hardware.</p>



<h3>Storage Performance</h3>



<p>Systems like databases, email servers, or any system which is trying to serve up real-time data in milliseconds are going to be sensitive to storage anomalies.  Disk fails, redundant paths are taken offline for maintenance, patching happens, and each of these events has the possibility of drastically changing the operating state of an application.  Consistently monitoring to ensure you are staying well away from your upper bounds will keep the focus off one of the most integral and sensitive parts of any ecosystem.</p>



<h3>Network Performance</h3>



<p>Monitoring also allows you to understand the current state of network performance. This can help you predict what will happen next by allowing you to proactively prepare for higher levels of network traffic.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>Monitoring is one of the core components of DevOps and is the important first step in taking advantage of the benefits of DevOps. By implementing a DevOps approach, monitoring becomes even more important because it provides visibility into the application environment and alerts when things are not running as expected.</p>



<p>Machine data is a fantastic source of data to understand the current state of your applications. Monitoring also gives you the ability to understand why something happened, which can help you debug issues and predict what will happen next.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Achieve Rapid Application Delivery with DevOps</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/devops-rapid-delivery/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greer Shepherd]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2022 20:19:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sdlc]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1668</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[DevOps has become a powerful set of tools, processes, and cultural norms for improving the deployment and operation of the software. As businesses grow more reliant on software applications, DevOps becomes even more important as it aids in accelerating the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> has become a powerful set of tools, processes, and cultural norms for improving the deployment and operation of the software. As businesses grow more reliant on software applications, DevOps becomes even more important as it aids in accelerating the delivery of new features to production.</p>



<p>Instead of relying on lengthy manual processes and manual testing stages to release updates, DevOps helps you streamline your release process so you can get new features out faster with higher quality and consistency.</p>



<p>The success of any organization relies on its ability to scale quickly and efficiently react to market demands. The demand for fast-paced change has forced many companies to reevaluate their current operational strategies. In response, organizations are now adopting a new culture for developing software and continuous integration processes that support rapid application development and application delivery cycles.</p>



<p>Let&#8217;s explore rapid application delivery and how it can have a meaningful impact on your business!</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>What is Rapid Application Delivery?</h2>



<p>Rapid application delivery is the practice of producing, testing, and deploying applications quickly from ideation to implementation &#8211; usually within days or even hours, rather than months or even years.</p>



<p>To stay competitive in the market, businesses need to get valuable technology into the market more quickly than their competitors.  Your business may be amazing at executing quality deliverables with an amazing user experience.  If those products are shipped to the market slowly, your competitors have an edge to capture the market faster if they are delivering products with the same quality and amazing user experience more quickly.</p>



<p>Organizations that are able to rapidly deliver new applications can respond more quickly to market conditions and customer needs, and therefore retain a competitive advantage.</p>



<p>I also believe that the barriers to entry on delivery have gotten far more complex over the past several years.  With major incidents like Log4J still looming in the shadows, end users and B2B relationships are requiring more scrutiny over deliverables than they ever have in the past.  </p>



<p>Some individuals may look at this increased scrutiny as a speed bump in the release process but I always encourage companies to embrace this increased scrutiny as a marketable way to show their products have a leg up on their competition.  The reality of the situation is, it can only be a competitive advantage if it is rolled directly into a rapid application delivery cycle.</p>



<h2>Why is Application Delivery Speed Important?</h2>



<p>Fast delivery of new applications is critical to keeping up with customer expectations and staying ahead of competitors. In today&#8217;s business environment, customers want goods and services faster than ever before. Consumers expect to be able to click a button and have their goods delivered to their doorsteps in just a few days.</p>



<p>Rapid application delivery means you can meet these expectations of speed and customer service in a highly competitive environment. If you’re able to bring a new product or service to market quickly, you can generate greater revenue and market share than if your offerings are delayed by months or even longer.</p>



<p>Speed is a major factor in customer decision-making. Moreover, if you’re behind the curve, you’ll most likely be out-competed by other companies that are able to get products or services to market quicker than you. If you’re slower than your competitors, you could lose market share and customers, which could damage your brand and profitability.</p>



<h2>Benefits of Rapid Delivery</h2>



<p>If you’re able to deliver apps quickly, you’ll see benefits in many areas, including the following:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Higher Revenue:</strong> If you’re able to get products or services to market faster, you’ll be able to generate more revenue than if your offerings are delayed by months or years.</li>



<li><strong>Increased Brand Awareness: </strong>If you’re able to get products or services to market faster, you’ll be able to increase brand awareness, which can help you to grow your customer base.</li>



<li><strong>Improved Customer Engagement:</strong> More rapid app delivery means increased customer engagement, which leads to greater customer retention.</li>



<li><strong>Reduced Costs:</strong> By accelerating the software development process and cutting out unnecessary steps, you can reduce costs.</li>
</ul>



<h2>How to Achieve Rapid Application Delivery in the Enterprise</h2>



<p>There are many steps you can take to achieve rapid application delivery in your organization, including the following:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Identify the Business Problem:</strong> Before you do anything else, you have to identify the business problem that you’re trying to solve. What is the company trying to accomplish? Once you know what business problem you’re trying to solve, you can create an application backlog.</li>



<li><strong>Create an Effective Solution: </strong>You must then create an effective solution that will meet the needs of the business problem you’re trying to solve. You can achieve this by using a collaborative approach to software development in order to build an application with input from all stakeholders.</li>



<li><strong>Test the Solution:</strong> The next step is to test the solution to ensure that it will solve the business problem in the way that you intended. You can do this by using <a href="https://www.valewood.org/devops-testing/" data-type="post" data-id="1239">automated testing</a> and continuous integration/continuous delivery (CI/CD) to maximize quality control and minimize the time to release.</li>
</ul>



<p>Adopting DevOps and Agile delivery methodologies account for each of the rapid application delivery considerations holistically.  These two concepts are wrapped up in a clever industry buzzword: <a href="https://www.techtarget.com/searchcio/definition/IT-transformation" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">IT Transformation</a>.</p>



<p>IT Transformation is a full assessment of information technology systems with the intent of increasing efficiency, delivery speed to market, stability, and cost to remain competitive in a digital market.  IT Transformation is not only for Exchange and document storage servers.</p>



<p>While it might be a tough pill to swallow, taking a step back and fully reassessing delivery and emulating organizations that do it very well is the key to success.  Some of these problems are solved problems that are not looking for the next creative solution.</p>



<h2>Why is my Application Delivery Slow?</h2>



<p>Naturally, over time, businesses will add process after process to application delivery cycles as a result of incidents or outages.  While well-intentioned at the time, the organic growth of these processes can lead to a dramatic downturn in both productivity and delivery of valuable products.  </p>



<ul>
<li>Manual Testing</li>



<li>Dependency Management Hell</li>



<li>Custom vs 3rd Party Integrations</li>



<li>Lack of Visibility</li>



<li>Overbearing Visibility</li>



<li>The work environment does not meet the needs of employees</li>



<li>Poor Communication</li>



<li>Misaligned Expectations</li>



<li>Outdated Technology</li>



<li>Too Much Parallel Work In-Progress</li>
</ul>



<p>I believe that the first step is always a recognition that there must be a better way to deliver.  After that, any changes made to this space are going to vary company by company depending on their appetite for risk.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>The Benefits of DevOps in Software Development</h2>



<p>DevOps is often used to describe the relationship between software development and operations that have evolved over the last couple of years. The term was first used in The Phoenix Project, a novel about bringing together IT and business leaders to fix a failing production system. It’s an abbreviation of “software development” and “operations”.</p>



<p>Its main goal is to get better collaboration between IT departments and software development teams. The DevOps movement gained momentum in the 2010s, as organizations looked for ways to improve application deployment and management while meeting growing customer demands.</p>



<p>The software development process includes several stages, like planning, designing, and testing the product. In an Agile project, these stages happen in very short iterations, and organizations work in a continuous flow. DevOps is the way of organizing work at scale and is about breaking down silos between teams and finding ways for them to work more closely together.</p>



<p>Rapid application development is also an early cornerstone in any kind of digital transformation.</p>



<h2>Continuous Integration in DevOps</h2>



<p>The ability to test new code is a key component for DevOps to work effectively. Continuous integration (CI) is the practice of integrating new code with existing code on a frequent basis. CI triggers the creation of new versions of software after every new code deployment.</p>



<p>Modules are integrated with other modules based on their dependency relationships. By using automated CI tools, developers can continuously test code against a production-like environment while they are responsible for writing code.</p>



<h2>Continuous Delivery in DevOps</h2>



<p>Organizations that have embraced CI are now looking to accelerate the deployment process further by implementing continuous delivery (CD). CD can be described as the automation of the entire delivery process. It includes automating the build and test process, setting up the necessary infrastructure, and using a deployment tool to deploy new application versions to production.</p>



<h2>Continuous Testing in DevOps</h2>



<p>Finally, continuous testing is the practice of the entire software development and testing team executing automated tests together. It is achieved through the use of CI tools that allow the team to run tests against the code and infrastructure in a single console.</p>



<p>By adopting CI/CD and embracing a DevOps culture, companies can reduce the time it takes to deliver new features to customers by 50 percent, according to research by CA Technologies.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>As businesses grow more reliant on software applications, DevOps becomes even more important as it aids in accelerating the delivery of new features to production. The adoption of DevOps can significantly reduce the time it takes to deliver new features to customers by automating the build, test, and deployment processes. By accelerating the deployment process, DevOps helps organizations meet growing customer demands while reducing risk.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>7 Tips for Landing a DevOps Position Without a Degree</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/devops-without-education/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greer Shepherd]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 21:28:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops resource]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1645</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[DevOps is hot right now. The demand for professionals with the skills to bridge the gap between software development and information technology operations is growing significantly. It’s not difficult to understand why. DevOps is a methodology that optimizes processes, removes&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> is hot right now. The demand for professionals with the skills to bridge the gap between software development and information technology operations is growing significantly.</p>



<p>It’s not difficult to understand why. DevOps is a methodology that optimizes processes, removes barriers, and improves collaboration between software developers and information technology (IT) operations teams. Because of its benefits, it’s becoming an increasingly attractive option for IT professionals who want to stand out from the crowd.</p>



<p>In this blog post, you will learn about the types of roles available in DevOps, how you can land your first DevOps job, and what you need to succeed in your new role as a DevOps engineer or specialist.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>What Is DevOps?</h2>



<p>DevOps is short for &#8220;software development operations.&#8221; It describes a set of best practices related to transforming the relationship between software developers and information technology (IT) operations personnel.</p>



<p>DevOps aims to improve collaboration, increase efficiency, and reduce waste. This organizational transformation is commonly referred to as cultural transformation.</p>



<p>Achieving cultural transformation requires employees in both departments to change their perspectives and expectations of each other. This is why DevOps is often seen as an ongoing journey, not a destination. DevOps is often associated with agile software development methodologies, such as Kanban, Scrum, and others.</p>



<h2>What do DevOps Engineers do Day to Day?</h2>



<p>A day in the life of DevOps engineers is not all that different than a day in any other technology career. A DevOps Engineer&#8217;s primary responsibility is centered around the health of the systems under their supervision. Those activities will include:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Look for anomalies:</strong> Despite our best efforts trying to completely cover a system in monitoring and visibility, sometimes things go bump in the night. These things could be reported by end users or other business units. Anytime something like that shows up, a DevOps Engineer should chase those anomalies down to something actionable.</li>



<li><strong>Review new releases:</strong> Just because you have an awesome pipeline that utilizes GitOps to move code directly from commit to production does not mean that you should trust your technology stack. Take time daily to review what has been making its way out to production to both understand the changes, but also suggest improvements.</li>



<li><strong>Review observability:</strong> Metrics and monitoring don&#8217;t do any good if nobody is looking at them. Anyone from systems administration through product owners should be reviewing these frequently looking for trends. Real-world usage of a system will always be different than what we thought it was going to be in the engineering phase and we should be validating, disproving, or augmenting our base assertions through data-driven decision-making.</li>



<li><strong>Manage risks:</strong> Successful systems grow over time. DevOps engineers should be looking at a complete ecosystem to help promote long-term health and manage risk. There is no free lunch and growing capacity means that costs will also be going up. Helping the team understand this relationship and educating the product owners of the business on investment opportunities is a critical activity that cannot be overlooked.</li>



<li><strong>Communicate with the team: </strong>Being in constant communication with your team is one of the core principles of DevOps. Since work units are broken down much farther than normal, rapid change is constantly being introduced. By promoting good synchronous and asynchronous communication patterns, teams will stay informed about what is important and urgent along with ensuring everyone is able to consume less urgent current events at their leisure.</li>



<li><strong>Watch industry trends:</strong> Because of the speed that a DevOps team brings to the industry, trends and patterns are changing faster than ever. When looking to become a DevOps engineer, you should be ready to keep your RSS feeds hot and ready to consume.</li>



<li><strong>Log new tickets: </strong>As you are doing your daily surveys of systems, undoubtedly you will run across either existing issues or issues that are sure to crop up in the near future. To help promote good planning, ensure that you are logging tickets into your ticket management system to ensure those issues do not get lost.</li>



<li><strong>Develop the skills you need:</strong> DevOps engineers are lifelong learners. The specific practices of cloud, data, <a href="https://www.valewood.org/do-devops-engineers-need-a-coding-background/" data-type="post" data-id="326">coding</a>, Linux, programming, <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="14" title="AWS" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">AWS</a>, culture, web, <a href="https://kubernetes.io/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="4" title="Kubernetes" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Kubernetes</a>, tools, etc. are constantly being changed to promote more fluid delivery models. Take time to sit back and absorb new concepts and techniques to help level up your career and your team.</li>



<li><strong>Promote continuous improvement:</strong> Any tech company that is not embracing a culture of continuous improvement will quickly be outperformed by companies that do. By taking a little bit of time out of your day to focus on improving something that needs attention, you are contributing to a cleaner and safer technology product!</li>



<li><strong>Have some fun:</strong> DevOps doesn&#8217;t need to be a grind. Make it a point to leave work behind and have some fun with your team.</li>
</ul>



<p>As you can see, DevOps Engineers have a lot of responsibility for running and maintaining technology.</p>



<h2>Types of Jobs in DevOps</h2>



<p>DevOps is a methodology that requires several different disciplines to fully adopt and become proficient in. In my opinion, I don&#8217;t think anyone technical should be asking &#8220;Can I become a DevOps Engineer?&#8221; because you are more than likely already qualified to be one! Let&#8217;s look at a few different roles in DevOps to see how the market is segmenting labor in this space.</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Software Engineer:</strong> Software engineers are responsible for building software products and services against a set of requirements. This role usually has some kind of computer science background, but some of the best developers and engineers I have met started their careers with no formal degree.</li>



<li><strong>Operations Engineer:</strong> Responsible for managing the lifecycle of technology ensuring the stability and reliability of systems. Anyone with a passion for learning technology and growing in the tech space should be searching the job market for entry-level operations jobs.</li>



<li><strong>Quality Assurance:</strong> Responsible for validating the quality of software being developed through automated testing. Also responsible for making testing available to an entire DevOps team.</li>



<li><strong>DevOps Engineer:</strong> Let’s start with the basics. If you’re looking to work as a DevOps engineer, you’ll need to be able to understand and work with code, have an excellent knowledge of server environments, and be able to think on the fly and find solutions to new problems.</li>



<li><strong>DevOps Engineer Manager:</strong> In this capacity, you’ll need to be able to work with both technical and non-technical staff. You’ll be responsible for ensuring that the team is working effectively and efficiently. So, it goes without saying that you’ll need strong communication skills.</li>



<li><strong>DevOps Architect:</strong> A DevOps architect is responsible for designing and implementing the organization’s software delivery system. This is often a challenging role that requires a great deal of experience, knowledge and a strong understanding of organizational needs.</li>



<li><strong>DevOps Manager:</strong> As a DevOps manager, you’ll be responsible for overseeing the entire DevOps process, including hiring, training, and managing staff. You’ll need to be able to understand and communicate the needs of multiple stakeholders. You’ll also need to be able to manage the entire lifecycle of products, from development to delivery and ongoing maintenance.</li>
</ul>



<p>As you can see, normal everyday engineering roles can join a DevOps team. Don&#8217;t immediately exclude yourself because you have not been a DevOps engineer in the past. Most of us have started out in software engineering or system operations roles anyway.</p>



<h2>How to Land a DevOps Job Without a Degree</h2>



<p>In today’s job market, it is not enough to just have a good education and experience from your previous job. You must also know how to write a resume that highlights your skills and experience in a way that shows you as the best candidate for the job.</p>



<p>This can be done by taking some time to research and learn about the particular industry you are interested in working in, as well as the company and the specific role you want to apply for.</p>



<p>When you have this information in hand, you can then create a resume that places your skills, experience, and values at the top of the list. This will make it easy for hiring managers to see what makes you different than other candidates and more likely to be hired.</p>



<p>With these things in mind, it is important to keep your resume updated as new jobs become available. You should also stay on top of employment trends so that you are ready when opportunities arise. By doing this, you will increase your chances of landing an interview and ultimately getting hired.</p>



<p>Here are a few additional steps you can take to increase your odds of landing a DevOps Engineering position:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Research the role you want</strong>: Blindly showing up to a job interview for a DevOps position is not going to go well. Take some time to learn and understand the DevOps methodology and what it is trying to accomplish. Any of the technical skills needed can be acquired on the job so do let that be a limiting factor.</li>



<li><strong>Network</strong>: The single best way to land a job in DevOps without a degree is to network, network, network. It’s one of the most effective ways to find out about new opportunities, learn about the industry, and connect with people who can help you advance your career.</li>



<li><strong>Identify Your Skills</strong>: Before you can network effectively, you need to know what your skills are. Doing this will help you identify which organizations are best for you, as well as identify skill gaps. Furthermore, it will help you understand how to position yourself as the best candidate for a given role.</li>



<li><strong>Join a DevOps Community:</strong> DevOps communities, like meetup groups and online forums, are excellent ways to find out about new opportunities and connect with people who can help you advance your career.</li>



<li><strong>Create an Online Portfolio:</strong> Online portfolios can be incredibly powerful tools for job seekers without a degree. You should include examples of your work and information about your projects and roles.</li>



<li><strong>Network with Employers</strong>: When you’re networking with employers, don’t sell yourself short. Be sure to highlight your skills, background, and experience.</li>
</ul>



<p>Regardless of your experience in development and operations, if you have any kind of tech experience, you should be looking to land a job in the DevOps engineering space. Entry-level positions are generally going to be a bit more focused on operations.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>3 Steps to Landing Any Job You Want</h2>



<p>If you’re looking to find a job, landing any kind of position is a big deal. You can start by proactively searching for the positions you want, or by going through a recruiter or headhunter if they have a specific role you’re interested in.</p>



<p>When you land a new job, you have to be prepared for all kinds of situations. You might have to move across the country if the company has an office there, and you may also have to learn new skills or take on new responsibilities.</p>



<p>Making yourself ready for these situations can help you land any kind of job. For example, you could build up your résumé and online presence by completing online courses or volunteering at local organizations. This will show that you are ready for a new position and will also make it easier to find work once you are ready.</p>



<p>Another option is to join professional organizations like Toastmasters or other networking groups where you can meet people who can help you land a new job. Just remember: Landing any kind of job takes time, so be prepared by taking steps now that will make it easier in the future!</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Define What You Want</strong>: Before you embark on your job search, you need to make an honest assessment of what you want. Do you want a full-time position, or will a contract position work for you? How many hours do you want to work per week? What is your salary range? These are just a few of the questions you’ll need to answer.</li>



<li><strong>Identify Your Strengths: </strong>Once you’ve identified what you want, you need to assess what you have to offer. What are your strengths? What are your weaknesses? This will help you identify which employers will be best for you.</li>



<li><strong>Write a Great Resume</strong>: Once you’ve assessed your skills and talents, you need to translate them into action for your resume. This is your first opportunity to impress a prospective employer.</li>
</ul>



<h2>Why do Employers Value Degrees?</h2>



<p>In the job market, it is no secret that you will very frequently see X level of degree or equivalent experience. I have noticed that this will generally disenfranchise individuals who are in the tech space from searching for a job at a particular company.</p>



<p>As a hiring manager, I am generally looking for individuals who have an aptitude and are lifelong learners for any of the jobs I am looking to fill. People who are passionate about quality delivery, consistency, and passionate about personal development are always great candidates. When looking for a new job, make sure you focus on those key areas about yourself to really wow a future employer.</p>



<p>Employers are also interested in standardized skills in software development, computer science, cloud, systems administration, etc. When someone graduates from higher education in the United States, there is a general sense that those individuals have learned and developed themselves enough to be effective from day 1, which is rarely the case in my experience.</p>



<p>A Junior DevOps engineer position can be filled by anyone who is passionate about automation, CI/CD, cloud, programming, Linux, AWS, and other technical spaces regardless of their background. The key is to do your research and understand the goals of what DevOps is trying to accomplish and make sure you are ready for interview questions about the DevOps Methodology.</p>



<p>When I am evaluating candidates, I bank on people first, not their skills. Even someone who may appear weak in a particular technology may be an incredible person that I want to work with. Some companies take the far more brutal leger-based approach on this. By only interviewing candidates who have a college degree, they are able to defer some of the cost of training. I would argue that is not a company that I want to work for.</p>



<p>There is an old saying, &#8220;Nobody ever gets fired for choosing IBM&#8221;. This translates into, if you are choosing the best, there is no reason for anyone to second guess your decisions. A degree has a similar stigma behind it. If a hiring manager is betting on someone with a degree, they probably won&#8217;t regret their decision. As a candidate, you just need to make sure you give a prospective employer a reason to bet on you.</p>



<p><strong>TLDR;</strong> Standardized skills, training, problem-solving, and risk mitigation.</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>If you want a job as a DevOps Engineer, you’ll need to be prepared to show what you have to offer and sell yourself to prospective employers. Remember, though, that there are many different types of jobs in DevOps.</p>



<p>So, before you start your search, it’s important to understand what you are looking for and how to stand out in a competitive hiring landscape. If you want a job in DevOps, you’ll need to be prepared to show what you have to offer and sell yourself to prospective employers.</p>



<p>Remember, though, that there are many different types of jobs in DevOps: DevOps engineer, architect, engineer manager, and manager. Target what you want to be doing, and start applying. You are probably more qualified than you initially thought!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
