<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>A DevOps Blog</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.valewood.org/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.valewood.org/</link>
	<description>Occasionally a developer makes an Ops!</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 01:26:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.valewood.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/A-DevOoops-1-e1660773390219.png</url>
	<title>A DevOps Blog</title>
	<link>https://www.valewood.org/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>How to Modify VMWare ESXi Guest Files with Ansible</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/ansible-modify-vmware-esxi-guest-file/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 01:25:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ansible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[howto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tools]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1232</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This post will help anyone who is attempting to use ansible to modify files on VMs running on ESXI via automation when Practicing DevOps. This method assumes that you have cloned out a machine, but do not yet have network&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>This post will help anyone who is attempting to use <a href="https://www.ansible.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="7" title="Ansible">ansible</a> to modify files on VMs running on ESXI via automation when <a href="https://www.valewood.org/practicing-devops/">Practicing DevOps</a>.  This method assumes that you have cloned out a machine, but do not yet have network access to that machine meaning you would need to utilize native ESXi methods to get communication setup.  </p>



<p>I use methods like this in my home lab to help stay current with new trends in <a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="Demystifying the DevOps Methodology and How You Can Leverage it for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> Not everyone is going to be fortunate enough to have cloud playgrounds to test out new things, and home labs are a great way to make a one-time investment in your future.</p>



<p>The code for the project can be found <a href="https://github.com/gwagner/ansible-examples/tree/main/modify-vmware-esxi-guest-file" target="_blank" data-type="URL" data-id="https://github.com/gwagner/ansible-examples/tree/main/modify-vmware-esxi-guest-file" rel="noreferrer noopener">here</a>!</p>


<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
</p>



<h2>Prerequisites</h2>



<p>This article is going to assume that you already have VMWare running in a home lab somewhere. This also assumes that you have some familiarity with VMware and networking.</p>



<p>This post will also assume that you have already installed a baseline OS running open-vm-tools. <a href="https://www.packer.io/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="17" title="Packer" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Packer</a><a href="https://www.packer.io/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"></a> is a good tool to use to automate your baseline operating system installation to create a reusable disk image.</p>



<p>You may also want to read <a href="https://www.valewood.org/ansible-create-vmware-esxi-vm/" data-type="post" data-id="1213">this post</a> to get a good feeling about how to automate cloning images when vSphere or Center are not available solutions.</p>



<h2>The Playbook</h2>



<p>Below is the full code to copy SSH keys to a newly cloned machine, and set an IP address with a NetworkManager restart.</p>



<p>The general idea is to run <code>ansible-playbook modify-vmware-esxi-guest-file.yaml -i inventory.yaml</code> from your command line.  The playbook will then connect to ESXi and create a .ssh folder on your fresh machine.  It will then copy your local <code>/home/user/.ssh/id_rsa.pub</code> file to the remote machine.  Finally, it will run <code>/bin/nmcli </code>commands to get a static IP address set on the VM.</p>



<p>A majority of this playbook is also setup with <code>delegate_to: localhost</code>. This means that the computer running the ansible script will also execute anything with the defined <code><code>delegate_to</code>: localhost</code>. Since the remote machine from inventory exists but is not yet able to be connected to <code><code>delegate_to</code>: localhost</code> is necessary of you would immediately receive an ansible connection error.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>---
- name: Modify VMWare ESXi VM File
  hosts: all
  gather_facts: false
  tasks:
    - include_vars: config.yaml
      delegate_to: localhost

    - include_vars: creds.yaml # Remember, this should be in a vault
      delegate_to: localhost   # These creds are for example use only

    - name: Create .ssh folder
      community.vmware.vmware_guest_file_operation:
        validate_certs: false
        hostname: "{{ vmware_host }}"
        username: "{{ vmware_user }}"
        password: "{{ vmware_password }}"
        datacenter: ha-datacenter
        vm_id: "{{ vmware.name }}"
        vm_username: "{{ centos_template_user }}"
        vm_password: "{{ centos_template_password }}"
        directory:
          path: "/home/user/.ssh/"
          operation: create
          recurse: no
      delegate_to: localhost

    - name: Copy RSA to VM
      community.vmware.vmware_guest_file_operation:
        validate_certs: false
        hostname: "{{ vmware_host }}"
        username: "{{ vmware_user }}"
        password: "{{ vmware_password }}"
        datacenter: ha-datacenter
        vm_id: "{{ vmware.name }}"
        vm_username: "{{ centos_template_user }}"
        vm_password: "{{ centos_template_password }}"
        copy:
          src: "/home/user/.ssh/id_rsa.pub"
          dest: "/home/user/.ssh/authorized_keys"
          overwrite: yes
      delegate_to: localhost

    - name: Run command inside a virtual machine
      community.vmware.vmware_vm_shell:
        hostname: "{{ vmware_host }}"
        username: "{{ vmware_user }}"
        password: "{{ vmware_password }}"
        datacenter: ha-datacenter
        vm_id: "{{ vmware.name }}"
        vm_username: "{{ centos_template_user }}"
        vm_password: "{{ centos_template_password }}"
        vm_shell: "{{ item.shell }}"
        vm_shell_args: "{{ item.args }}"
      loop:
        - { shell: "/bin/nmcli", args: "connection modify ens192 IPv4.ignore-auto-dns yes" }
        - { shell: "/bin/nmcli", args: "connection modify ens192 IPv4.address \"{{ vmware.ip_address }}/24\"" }
        - { shell: "/bin/nmcli", args: "connection modify ens192 IPv4.gateway \"{{ vmware.gateway_address }}\"" }
        - { shell: "/bin/nmcli", args: "connection modify ens192 IPv4.dns \"{{ vmware.dns_address }}\"" }
        - { shell: "/bin/nmcli", args: "connection modify ens192 IPv4.method manual" }
        - { shell: "/bin/systemctl", args: "NetworkManager restart" }
      delegate_to: localhost

</code></pre>



<h2>Task By Task Breakdown</h2>



<p>To not rehash details I have gone through in other articles, you can find a breakdown of the inventory, credentials, and config in <a href="https://www.valewood.org/ansible-create-vmware-esxi-vm/#penci-A-Task-By-Task-Breakdown" data-type="URL" data-id="/ansible-create-vmware-esxi-vm/#penci-A-Task-By-Task-Breakdown">this post.</a></p>



<p>The first step of this playbook is to create a users .ssh folder so an authorized_keys file can be created.  The playbook makes an assumption that your user is named&#8230; user, but that could be modified and turned into a configuration parameter pretty quickly.  I will break down each of the config parameters below:</p>



<ul><li>validate_certs is set to false because most of us are not going to be using trusted 3rd party certs in our VMware environment. If you are doing this in a professional environment, ensure you have valid certs installed and leave validate_certs set to the default of true.</li><li>validate_certs should also be set to false if you are connecting to your VMWare server via IP address since your cert will not match an IP address.</li><li>vmware_user and vmware_password should be set to a user that has SSH access to your VMWare server. I would not recommend that you do this in any sort of production environment, but it is perfectly fine for a home lab.</li><li>datacenter is set to ha-datacenter. This is the default name of a “datacenter” in ESXi. There is no reason to change this.</li><li>vm_id is either the exact case-sensitive name of the virtual machine being configured.  If you created your machine using ansible, then make sure you map the name you gave it here via variables.</li><li>vm_username and vm_password is in reference to the user you setup when creating your template or disk image.  ESXi needs this to effectively run an interactive login to the server to perform your commands.</li><li>directory is signifying that our action is going to be taken on a directory.  In the next task you will see that we use the copy key instead of directory but we are utilizing the exact same module.</li><li>directory.path is the path on the ESXi guests that you want to take action on.</li><li>directory.operation denotes what we want to have happen.  In this case, we are going to create a directory.</li><li>directory.recurse tells ansible if it should send a command that recursively creates directories.  If your default user is not named user, you would end up with a /home/user/.ssh directory that will be fairly useless.</li></ul>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>    - name: Create .ssh folder
      community.vmware.vmware_guest_file_operation:
        validate_certs: false
        hostname: "{{ vmware_host }}"
        username: "{{ vmware_user }}"
        password: "{{ vmware_password }}"
        datacenter: ha-datacenter
        vm_id: "{{ vmware.name }}"
        vm_username: "{{ centos_template_user }}"
        vm_password: "{{ centos_template_password }}"
        directory:
          path: "/home/user/.ssh/"
          operation: create
          recurse: no
      delegate_to: localhost</code></pre>



<p>This next task does a copy of a file from the machine you executed the ansible playbook from onto the ESXi guest that we are configuring.  In the interest of brevity, I am not going to rehash the duplicate keys from above.  Here are the specific keys of interest in this task:</p>



<ul><li>copy denotes that we want to copy a file.  The file needs to exist on your source system and will be copied to the ESXi guest.</li><li>copy.src is the path to the source file.  As you can see, we are targeting the public key here.</li><li>copy.dest is the full path to the destination.   As you can see we are targeting an authorized_keys file as the destination.  This could be dangerous if that file already exists as it will be overwritten.</li><li>copy.overwrite ensures that we will clobber whatever exists on the destination system with the file from our source system.</li></ul>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>    - name: Copy RSA to VM
      community.vmware.vmware_guest_file_operation:
        validate_certs: false
        hostname: "{{ vmware_host }}"
        username: "{{ vmware_user }}"
        password: "{{ vmware_password }}"
        datacenter: ha-datacenter
        vm_id: "{{ vmware.name }}"
        vm_username: "{{ centos_template_user }}"
        vm_password: "{{ centos_template_password }}"
        copy:
          src: "/home/user/.ssh/id_rsa.pub"
          dest: "/home/user/.ssh/authorized_keys"
          overwrite: yes
      delegate_to: localhost</code></pre>


<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
</p>



<p>This last task is composed a bit differently.  Effectively it is being used to run a series of nmcli commands along with a single systemctl command to set a static IP address for this machine.  I have this task composed this way to clean up ansible code.  This could be written as six fully independent tasks in ansible, but remember to stay DRY and don&#8217;t repeat yourself.  Here is a breakdown of the specific keys of interest:</p>



<ul><li>vm_shell represents the exact path to the command that is going to be run on the ESXi guest.  Do not include command arguments in this field, the documentation specifically states that it wants a full path to an executable.</li><li>vm_shell_args represents the arguments to the vm_shell command.  </li><li>loop controls how the task will loop through the data defined underneath.  I have the keys setup as dictionary objects so that we get both shell executables and arguments from the loop.</li></ul>



<pre class="wp-block-code"><code>    - name: Run command inside a virtual machine
      community.vmware.vmware_vm_shell:
        hostname: "{{ vmware_host }}"
        username: "{{ vmware_user }}"
        password: "{{ vmware_password }}"
        datacenter: ha-datacenter
        vm_id: "{{ vmware.name }}"
        vm_username: "{{ centos_template_user }}"
        vm_password: "{{ centos_template_password }}"
        vm_shell: "{{ item.shell }}"
        vm_shell_args: "{{ item.args }}"
      loop:
        - { shell: "/bin/nmcli", args: "connection modify ens192 IPv4.ignore-auto-dns yes" }
        - { shell: "/bin/nmcli", args: "connection modify ens192 IPv4.address \"{{ vmware.ip_address }}/24\"" }
        - { shell: "/bin/nmcli", args: "connection modify ens192 IPv4.gateway \"{{ vmware.gateway_address }}\"" }
        - { shell: "/bin/nmcli", args: "connection modify ens192 IPv4.dns \"{{ vmware.dns_address }}\"" }
        - { shell: "/bin/nmcli", args: "connection modify ens192 IPv4.method manual" }
        - { shell: "/bin/systemctl", args: "NetworkManager restart" }
      delegate_to: localhost</code></pre>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>As you can see, with a fairly concise set of steps, you can level up your DevOps automation game by rapidly configuring virtual machines in your home lab.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>PurpleUrchin Crypto Mining with Free GitHub Actions</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/purpleurchin-crypto-mining/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 02:26:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1225</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sysdig Threat Research Team has discovered PURPLEURCHIN, an elaborate crypto mining operation taking advantage of automated CI/CD services. Attackers have used millions of free compute cycles through services such as GitHub Actions, Heroku, and others, to run the operation. What&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://sysdig.com/blog/massive-cryptomining-operation-github-actions/" data-type="URL" data-id="https://sysdig.com/blog/massive-cryptomining-operation-github-actions/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sysdig Threat Research Team</a> has discovered PURPLEURCHIN, an elaborate crypto mining operation taking advantage of automated CI/CD services. Attackers have used millions of free compute cycles through services such as <a href="https://www.github.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="6" title="Github" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">GitHub</a> Actions, Heroku, and others, to run the operation.</p>



<p>What does this mean to the <a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="Demystifying the DevOps Methodology and How You Can Leverage it for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> community?</p>


<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
</p>



<h2>A Basic Breakdown of the Attack</h2>



<p>The attack started with some images on DockerHub being updated and automated scanning catching those images.  From there, it appears that free-tier GitHub accounts were created which allow for 2000 minutes per month of runtime.  Repositories are then created and a <code>github-actions.yaml</code> workflow is created in those repositories.  Containers are then started which run the mining operations.  Ports are also opened up to serve as command and control.</p>



<p>To get the full details of the attack, which is extremely fascinating, I would look into the article that I have linked at the top of this post.  There is a ton of depth and work around to combat the systems of control that GitHub has in place to protect its infrastructure from attack.</p>



<h2>What is the Threat of a Poorly Secured Code Repository?</h2>



<p>Supply chain attacks have become commonplace in software development.  Companies are constantly chasing CVEs from packages that are either not being well maintained by the community or are being maintained but companies are not allocating enough funding to keep their software in line with community updates.  </p>



<p>The most pronounced threat in recent memory was <a href="https://nvd.nist.gov/vuln/detail/CVE-2021-44228" data-type="URL" data-id="https://nvd.nist.gov/vuln/detail/CVE-2021-44228" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Log4j remote code execution bug</a> found in versions below 2.16.  This allowed attackers to craft a simple attack that was able to quickly run arbitrary code that could have real consequences.</p>



<p>Companies all over the planet rushed to update their code bases.  You can find massive Reddit threads that were discussing their companies&#8217; responses to the issue.  I would imagine, even with all of the industry hype, this vulnerability still exists in the wild and is still being exploited.</p>



<p>How can something like this be avoided in the future?  People familiar with DevOps automation will quickly reply by adding more automation to their environments and building systems.  While I completely agree with this response, if automation is added irresponsibly the threat landscape you are looking at will broaden very quickly.</p>



<p>In high school, I was enrolled in vocational education where I learned how to build a shed.  It was a pretty awesome experience and I learned a lot.  The shop teacher in charge of running the class and keeping the students safe was generally opposed to using power tools to aid in our learning.  When approached as to why his response was simply this; &#8220;power tools are just going to ensure that you kids screw something up faster than with hand tools&#8221;.</p>



<p>When adding automation to an environment, especially in concert with code repositories and build systems, you are opening yourself up to a lot of risks that need to be mitigated.  If your pipelines are fully automated from commit through production, then all it takes is one simple push before disaster strikes.</p>



<p>Tom Scott from &#8220;Things You Might Not Know&#8221; does a pretty good theoretical exercise about how quickly things can go wrong in a scenario like this.  I have added the video below.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Single Point of Failure: The (Fictional) Day Google Forgot To Check Passwords" width="1170" height="658" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/y4GB_NDU43Q?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div><figcaption>Single Point of Failure: The (Fictional) Day Google Forgot To Check Passwords</figcaption></figure>



<h2>How Does this Impact the Average Company?</h2>



<p>PURPLEURCHIN appears to be a fairly sophisticated vehicle to utilize free compute resources to mine cryptocurrency.  On its face, a group is just trying to make a buck.</p>



<p>On its face, it does not seem very threatening.  This kind of attack really shows not only the creativity of attackers today, but it highlights how complex a company&#8217;s technology stack has gotten, and how easy it is to hide inside of it.  </p>



<p>Here are some questions that you can ask yourself to understand your level of visibility:</p>



<ul><li>Would you know if all of the code that made it into production on your next release was intentionally put there by good actors?</li><li>Would you know if your servers are only running what you intended for them to be running?</li><li>Could a sidecar process be spun up by a bad actor and would anybody notice?</li><li>Does your automated testing stack take environmental considerations into account when passing a build?</li><li>Do you know what versions of 3rd party dependencies are running in your environment?</li><li>Would you know if a 3rd party dependency has been compromised?</li><li>Could you quickly replace a compromised dependency to ensure business continuity?</li></ul>



<p>Now, these questions may seem like a little bit of fear-mongering, and that is intentional.  There are solutions for every single one of these already-solved problems on the market.  In my experience, companies are not always going that extra mile to ensure that they are protected from threat actors.</p>



<p>The factors that compound all of this are speed and automation.  I don&#8217;t think anybody will dispute the argument that the technology space moves extremely quickly.  On top of that, businesses must ship and release software at the pace of the market to remain competitive.  Because of that speed, automation is generally employed as a stop-gap to maintain a consistent pace.  Businesses have the possibility of leaving themselves exposed if those automated tools are not held to a higher standard than the software they are developing.</p>


<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>PURPLEURCHIN serves as another reminder about the time and attention we need to pay to our supply chain and automated tool stacks.  While this particular attack does not constitute immediate concern for the technology community holistically like Log4J did, it serves as a great reminder that technology hygiene is as important as shipping valuable technology solutions to the market.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/y4GB_NDU43Q" medium="video" width="1280" height="720">
			<media:player url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/y4GB_NDU43Q" />
			<media:title type="plain">Single Point of Failure: The (Fictional) Day Google Forgot To Check Passwords</media:title>
			<media:description type="html"><![CDATA[http://tomscott.com/ - @tomscott - I spin a (fictional) tale of the day that Google accidentally opened everything. Performed at GeekyConf, with thanks to Bet...]]></media:description>
			<media:thumbnail url="/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/devops-purpleurchin.jpg" />
			<media:rating scheme="urn:simple">nonadult</media:rating>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How To Create ESXi VM With Ansible</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/ansible-create-vmware-esxi-vm/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 03:28:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ansible]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1213</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This post will help anyone who is attempting to use Ansible to create new VMs with automation when Practicing DevOps. I use this in my home lab to help stay current with new trends in DevOps. Not everyone is going&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>This post will help anyone who is attempting to use <a href="https://www.ansible.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="7" title="Ansible">Ansible</a> to create new VMs with automation when <a href="https://www.valewood.org/practicing-devops/" data-type="post" data-id="14">Practicing DevOps</a>.  I use this in my home lab to help stay current with new trends in <a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="Demystifying the DevOps Methodology and How You Can Leverage it for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a>.  Not everyone is going to be fortunate enough to have cloud playgrounds to test out new things, and home labs are a great way to make a one-time investment in your future.</p>



<p>The code for the project can be found <a href="https://github.com/gwagner/ansible-examples/tree/main/create-vmware-esxi-vm" data-type="URL" data-id="https://github.com/gwagner/ansible-examples/tree/main/create-vmware-esxi-vm" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>!</p>


<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
</p>



<h2>Prerequisites</h2>



<p>This article is going to assume that you already have VMWare running in a home lab somewhere.  This also assumes that you have some familiarity with VMware and networking.</p>



<p>This post will also assume that you have already installed a baseline OS.  <a href="https://www.packer.io/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="17" title="Packer" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Packer</a> is a good tool to use to automate your baseline operating system installation to create a reusable disk image.</p>



<h2>The Playbook</h2>



<p>Below is the full code to deploy a virtual machine from a disk image.  </p>



<p>The general idea is to run <code>ansible-playbook create-vmware-esxi-vm.yaml -i inventory.yaml</code> from your command line.  The playbook will then check to see if a machine exists.  If set to destructive, it will then delete any machine with the same name, copy an existing disk image, set some machine specifics like IP address, and then power on your machine.</p>



<p>VMWare vSphere makes this a fairly novel activity via the use of templates.  A standalone ESXi node does not have the benefit of templates which is why things get a bit more complex in this space.</p>



<p>A majority of this playbook is also setup with <code>delegate_to: localhost</code>.  This means that the computer running the ansible script will also execute anything with the defined <code><code>delegate_to</code>: localhost</code>.  The remote machine from inventory does not yet exist, which means; if <code><code>delegate_to</code>: localhost</code> was not set, you would immediately receive an ansible connection error.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>---
- name: Create VMWare ESXi VM
  hosts: all
  gather_facts: false
  vars:
    destructive: false
  tasks:
    - include_vars: config.yaml
      delegate_to: localhost

    - include_vars: creds.yaml # Remember, this should be in a vault
      delegate_to: localhost   # These creds are for example use only

    - name: Check if virtual machine exists
      community.vmware.vmware_guest_info:
        validate_certs: false
        hostname: "{{ vmware_host }}"
        username: "{{ vmware_user }}"
        password: "{{ vmware_password }}"
        datacenter: "ha-datacenter"
        name: "{{ vmware.name }}"
      delegate_to: localhost
      ignore_errors: true
      throttle: 1
      register: vmware_validate_guest
      when: destructive is not defined or not destructive

    - set_fact:
        destructive: yes
      when: |
        vmware_validate_guest is defined and (
          (vmware_validate_guest.skipped is defined and not vmware_validate_guest.skipped) 
          or (vmware_validate_guest.failed is defined and vmware_validate_guest.failed == True)
        )

    - name: Add vmware as a host
      add_host:
        hostname: "{{ vmware_host }}"
        ansible_ssh_host: "{{ vmware_host }}"
        ansible_user: "{{ vmware_user }}"
        ansible_ssh_pass: "{{ vmware_password }}"
      when: destructive

    - set_fact:
        num_cpu_cores_per_socket: "{{ vmware.num_cpus | int / 2 }}"

    - name: Remove virtual machine from inventory
      community.vmware.vmware_guest:
        validate_certs: false
        hostname: "{{ vmware_host }}"
        username: "{{ vmware_user }}"
        password: "{{ vmware_password }}"
        name: "{{ vmware.name }}"
        state: absent
        force: True
      delegate_to: localhost
      throttle: 1
      when: destructive

    - name: Delete VM Folders
      ansible.builtin.file:
        path: "{{storage_path}}/{{ vmware.name }}/"
        state: absent
      delegate_to: "{{ vmware_host }}"
      when: destructive
      throttle: 5

    - name: Create a virtual machine on vmware
      community.vmware.vmware_guest:
        validate_certs: false
        hostname: "{{ vmware_host }}"
        username: "{{ vmware_user }}"
        password: "{{ vmware_password }}"
        folder: /vm/
        name: "{{ vmware.name }}"
        state: poweredoff
        guest_id: "{{ vmware.guest_id }}"    
        disk: "{{ vmware.disks }}"
        datastore: "{{ datastore_name }}"
        hardware:
          boot_firmware: efi
          memory_mb: "{{ vmware.memory_mb }}"
          num_cpus: "{{ vmware.num_cpus }}"
          num_cpu_cores_per_socket: "{{ num_cpu_cores_per_socket | int }}"
          scsi: paravirtual
        networks:
        - name: "{{ vmware.port_group }}"
          connect: yes
          mac: "{{ vmware.mac_address  }}"
          ip: "{{ vmware.ip_address }}"
          netmask: "{{ vmware.netmask }}"
          device_type: vmxnet3
          type: static
      delegate_to: localhost
      register: deploy_vm
      throttle: 5
      when: destructive

    - name: Copy boot disk VMDK Files
      ansible.builtin.command: "{{ item }}"
      delegate_to: "{{ vmware_host }}"
      loop:
        - vmkfstools -i "{{storage_path}}/{{ image_name }}/{{ image_name }}.vmdk" "{{storage_path}}/{{ vmware.name }}/{{ image_name }}.vmdk" -d thin
      when: destructive
      throttle: 3

    - name: Add boot disks to virtual machine
      community.vmware.vmware_guest_disk:
        validate_certs: false
        hostname: "{{ vmware_host }}"
        username: "{{ vmware_user }}"
        password: "{{ vmware_password }}"
        name: "{{ vmware.name }}"
        datacenter: ha-datacenter
        disk:
          - filename: "&#091;{{datastore_name}}] {{ vmware.name }}/{{ image_name }}.vmdk"
            scsi_type: 'paravirtual'
            scsi_controller: 0
            unit_number: 1
      delegate_to: localhost
      register: disk_facts
      when: destructive
      throttle: 5

    - name: Power on virtual machine
      community.vmware.vmware_guest:
        validate_certs: false
        hostname: "{{ vmware_host }}"
        username: "{{ vmware_user }}"
        password: "{{ vmware_password }}"
        name: "{{ vmware.name }}"
        state: poweredon
        wait_for_ip_address: yes
      delegate_to: localhost
      register: deploy_vm
      when: destructive</code></pre>



<h2>A Task By Task Breakdown</h2>



<p>First, we should look at the inventory.</p>



<p>This example has only one example host defined in it under a group called example.  You are able to define as many hosts in inventory that you would like.  </p>



<p>The structure of the vars defined under example-01.valewood.lab are there to provide everything the playbook needs in order to provision a server in ESXi.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>---
all:
  hosts:
  children:
    example:
      hosts:
        example-01.valewood.lab:
          ip: 192.168.1.10 
          ansible_host: 192.168.1.10
          vmware:
            ip_address: 192.168.1.10
            gateway_address: 192.168.1.1
            dns_address: 192.168.1.1
            netmask: 255.255.255.0
            mac_address: "00:16:3E:A0:06:43"
            memory_mb: 8192
            name: example-01
            num_cpus: 4
            port_group: Example-App
            guest_id: centos64Guest
            disks: &#091;]</code></pre>



<p>Below is the code that reads in configurations and credentials.  These are broken up into 2 different files because credentials should always be encrypted and never stored in plaintext.  </p>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>    - include_vars: config.yaml
      delegate_to: localhost

    - include_vars: creds.yaml # Remember, this should be in a vault
      delegate_to: localhost   # These creds are for example use only</code></pre>



<p>The next step is to check to see if a VM exists in VMWare or not with the same name.  This is a crucial step to ensure that duplicate names are not used in VMWare.  Here are some key notes about additional configurations:</p>



<ul><li>validate_certs is set to false because most of us are not going to be using trusted 3rd party certs in our VMware environment.  If you are doing this in a professional environment, ensure you have valid certs installed and leave validate_certs set to the default of true.</li><li>validate_certs should also be set to false if you are connecting to your VMWare server via IP address since your cert will not match an IP address.</li><li>vmware_user and vmware_password should be set to a user that has SSH access to your VMWare server.  I would not recommend that you do this in any sort of production environment, but it is perfectly fine for a home lab.</li><li>datacenter is set to ha-datacenter.  This is the default name of a &#8220;datacenter&#8221; in ESXi.  There is no reason to change this.</li><li>throttle is set to 1 to provide time to ctrl+c IF you happen to run your playbook by mistake against many machines at once.</li><li>destructive is a variable that can be set which tells this playbook to not destroy and rebuild machines if they already exist.  By default, the destructive variable it is not defined which means a check will be performed.</li></ul>



<pre class="wp-block-code"><code>    - name: Check if virtual machine exists
      community.vmware.vmware_guest_info:
        validate_certs: false 
        hostname: "{{ vmware_host }}"
        username: "{{ vmware_user }}"
        password: "{{ vmware_password }}"
        datacenter: "ha-datacenter"
        name: "{{ vmware.name }}"
      delegate_to: localhost
      ignore_errors: true
      throttle: 1
      register: vmware_validate_guest
      when: destructive is not defined or not destructive</code></pre>



<p>The next block of code will set the <code>destructive</code> variable to true IF we did the validation check from the previous block.  The validation check in the previous block will not run if <code>destructive</code> is set to true.  This acts as a one-way gate.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>    - set_fact:
        destructive: yes
      when: |
        vmware_validate_guest is defined and (
          (vmware_validate_guest.skipped is defined and not vmware_validate_guest.skipped) 
          or (vmware_validate_guest.failed is defined and vmware_validate_guest.failed == True)
        )</code></pre>



<p>Things get a little bit tricky here, but I will explain the rationale behind this next block.  Your inventory file only has virtual machines defined in it, but for ansible remote connections to work properly, a host must be in inventory.  To get around this, in the middle of this playbook run, we call add_host which has an explicit delegate_to statement so that it runs on localhost.</p>



<p>The reason this is tricky is because of the way that ansible does variable expansion.  One would think that a single host is being added to the inventory, but what is really happening in a playbook?  Ansible is expanding variable scope out to each individual machine in the inventory.  This means that add_host is actually being added in the context of each host in the inventory.  If you have 10 hosts defined in inventory, add_host adds variables for your VMWare host for each inventory host.</p>



<p>TLDR; each host in inventory now has the ability to utilize a <code>delegate_to: {{ vmware_host }}</code> statement as part of their tasks.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>    - name: Add vmware as a host
      add_host:
        hostname: "{{ vmware_host }}"
        ansible_ssh_host: "{{ vmware_host }}"
        ansible_user: "{{ vmware_user }}"
        ansible_ssh_pass: "{{ vmware_password }}"
      when: destructive</code></pre>



<p>Next, we need to do a little bit of math.  This could be done live through future executions, but I like to split things like this out into separate set_fact tasks to ensure I can easily run any debug tasks in the future.</p>



<p>Basically, this accomplishes telling VMWare that I want my CPU cores evenly distributed across sockets.  This is not perfect because it does not take care of edge cases of 1 CPU or 3 CPUs being defined in inventory.  For my use cases, I never define anything that way, but this could easily be updated to accommodate.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>    - set_fact:
        num_cpu_cores_per_socket: "{{ vmware.num_cpus | int / 2 }}"</code></pre>



<p>Next, if we are destructive, we need to delete an existing VM.  I am not going to rehash any of the special variables from above.  The only relevant thing to notice here is the state being set to absent which will delete the machine, and force is set to true which will bypass any safety checks VMWare might do.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>    - name: Remove virtual machine from inventory
      community.vmware.vmware_guest:
        validate_certs: false
        hostname: "{{ vmware_host }}"
        username: "{{ vmware_user }}"
        password: "{{ vmware_password }}"
        name: "{{ vmware.name }}"
        state: absent
        force: True
      delegate_to: localhost
      throttle: 1
      when: destructive</code></pre>



<p>Next is a little bit of cleanliness.  The delete statement above will not actually cleanup the VMWare datastore filesystem.  We are performing a <code>delegate_to: {{ vmware_host }}</code> which means we will be running a direct delete over SSH to your server running vmware.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>    - name: Delete VM Folders
      ansible.builtin.file:
        path: "{{storage_path}}/{{ vmware.name }}/"
        state: absent
      delegate_to: "{{ vmware_host }}"
      when: destructive
      throttle: 5</code></pre>


<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
</p>



<p>Finally, the meat of the playbook.  This task creates the VM which is defined in the inventory.  I will break down the relevant variables below.</p>



<ul><li>Folder is neccisary for vShpere.  When only running ESXi, this only requires a default value of /vm/.  Most home labs will not need to change this.</li><li>state is set to poweredoff.  You could set this to poweredon but leaving it poweredoff ensures you can do post-processing after this create task.</li></ul>



<p>Please note, <code>Create a virtual machine on vmware</code> is not referencing any kind of existing disk image.  This will create a new completely blank VM.  Subsequent tasks will utilize your disk image to ensure it is properly attached to this machine.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>    - name: Create a virtual machine on vmware
      community.vmware.vmware_guest:
        validate_certs: false
        hostname: "{{ vmware_host }}"
        username: "{{ vmware_user }}"
        password: "{{ vmware_password }}"
        folder: /vm/
        name: "{{ vmware.name }}"
        state: poweredoff
        guest_id: "{{ vmware.guest_id }}"    
        disk: "{{ vmware.disks }}"
        datastore: "{{ datastore_name }}"
        hardware:
          boot_firmware: efi
          memory_mb: "{{ vmware.memory_mb }}"
          num_cpus: "{{ vmware.num_cpus }}"
          num_cpu_cores_per_socket: "{{ num_cpu_cores_per_socket | int }}"
          scsi: paravirtual
        networks:
        - name: "{{ vmware.port_group }}"
          connect: yes
          mac: "{{ vmware.mac_address  }}"
          ip: "{{ vmware.ip_address }}"
          netmask: "{{ vmware.netmask }}"
          device_type: vmxnet3
          type: static
      delegate_to: localhost
      register: deploy_vm
      throttle: 5
      when: destructive</code></pre>



<p>Next, perform a copy of an existing disk image into the folder that was just created for this new virtual machine.  This will essentially perform the same action that vSphere performs when cloning templates.</p>



<p>The key here is to utilize <code>vmkfstools</code> over ssh to ensure that you are able to get a thin provisioned copied disk.  If this is performed directly via ansible modules, you are not able to get a thin disk without vSphere.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>    - name: Copy boot disk VMDK Files
      ansible.builtin.command: "{{ item }}"
      delegate_to: "{{ vmware_host }}"
      loop:
        - vmkfstools -i "{{storage_path}}/{{ image_name }}/{{ image_name }}.vmdk" "{{storage_path}}/{{ vmware.name }}/{{ image_name }}.vmdk" -d thin
      when: destructive
      throttle: 3</code></pre>



<p>Next, we need to tell VMWare to mount our cloned disk to the recently created VM.  The new VM will have a scsi_controller so we just need to give it the right controller number of 0, and unit_number 1 to ensure we do not overwrite the new disk created via <code>Create a virtual machine on vmware</code>.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>    - name: Add boot disks to virtual machine
      community.vmware.vmware_guest_disk:
        validate_certs: false
        hostname: "{{ vmware_host }}"
        username: "{{ vmware_user }}"
        password: "{{ vmware_password }}"
        name: "{{ vmware.name }}"
        datacenter: ha-datacenter
        disk:
          - filename: "&#091;{{datastore_name}}] {{ vmware.name }}/{{ image_name }}.vmdk"
            scsi_type: 'paravirtual'
            scsi_controller: 0
            unit_number: 1
      delegate_to: localhost
      register: disk_facts
      when: destructive
      throttle: 5</code></pre>



<p>And finally we tell ESXi to power on the virtual machine.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>    - name: Power on virtual machine
      community.vmware.vmware_guest:
        validate_certs: false
        hostname: "{{ vmware_host }}"
        username: "{{ vmware_user }}"
        password: "{{ vmware_password }}"
        name: "{{ vmware.name }}"
        state: poweredon
        wait_for_ip_address: yes
      delegate_to: localhost
      register: deploy_vm
      when: destructive</code></pre>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>As you can see, with a fairly concise set of steps, you can level up your DevOps automation game by rapidly creating and tearing down virtual machines in your home lab.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Convert Text File to JSON with Ansible</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/ansible-text-to-json/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ansible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ansible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[howto]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1187</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I was looking through Reddit today and saw an interesting question about how to manipulate files with Ansible. I took a few minutes to throw together an example of how to convert a relatively simple file, a list of strings&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>I was looking through Reddit today and saw an <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ansible/comments/ycgtkg/convert_output_of_file_to_json_using_j2_template/" data-type="URL" data-id="https://www.reddit.com/r/ansible/comments/ycgtkg/convert_output_of_file_to_json_using_j2_template/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">interesting question</a> about how to manipulate files with <a href="https://www.ansible.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="7" title="Ansible">Ansible</a>.  I took a few minutes to throw together <a href="https://github.com/gwagner/ansible-examples/tree/main/read-file-output-json" data-type="URL" data-id="https://github.com/gwagner/ansible-examples/tree/main/read-file-output-json" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an example </a>of how to convert a relatively simple file, a list of strings broken up by new lines, and output it as JSON.  </p>



<p>Doing file conversions or data munging is an important skill to learn when growing in a <a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="Demystifying the DevOps Methodology and How You Can Leverage it for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> position.  While this is a fairly basic example, utilize this as a stepping stone to understanding more complex data structures.</p>


<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
</p>



<h2>Simple Text to JSON Conversion with Ansible</h2>



<p>Below is the Ansible code to read in a file name input.txt delimited by newline characters and then do a simple conversion to JSON writing to output.json.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>- name: Simple Read file and output JSON
  hosts: localhost
  connection: local 
  become: false
  tasks:
  - name: Read Data File
    set_fact:
      data: "{{lookup('ansible.builtin.file', './input.txt').split('\n')}}"

  - name: Show debug data
    ansible.builtin.debug: var=data

  - name: Write output json file
    copy:
      dest: output.json
      content: "{{ data | to_json }}" </code></pre>



<h3>Task By Task Breakdown</h3>



<p>The first task reads the input.txt file into a data variable that Ansible can use. It also splits the file into a list via the \n (newline) character.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>  - name: Read Data File
    set_fact:
      data: "{{lookup('ansible.builtin.file', './input.txt').split('\n')}}"</code></pre>



<p>set_fact can be one of your best friends in Ansible. It allows you to take either data from what you have available in your playbook run, or lookup data and set it to a useable var for future tasks.  Here I am calling lookup to read an input.txt file and saving it to a data var.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>  - name: Show debug data
    ansible.builtin.debug: var=data</code></pre>



<p>ansible.builtin.debug lets you output the values of variables to the terminal during a playbook run.  This code should not be utilized anywhere except for testing.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>  - name: Write output json file
    copy:
      dest: output.json
      content: "{{ data | to_json }}" </code></pre>



<p>Finally, utilizing the built-in copy module, you can feed it a variable, like data, and then pipe that to a to_json jinja2 function which will then write your file out to dest.</p>



<p>The result of running this playbook will look something like this:</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code json"><code>&#091;"/site/foo/", "/site/bar/"]</code></pre>


<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
</p>



<h2>Complex Text to JSON Conversion with Ansible</h2>



<p>Below is the Ansible code to read in a file name input.txt delimited by newline characters.  After reading the file, a new variable is initialized name data_elements.  A loop is then run to create new dictionary objects with a key of &#8216;name&#8217; and a value of each line of input.txt.  Finally, a copy is run to write the data to disk under output.json.  </p>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>- name: Complex Read file and output JSON
  hosts: localhost
  connection: local 
  become: false
  tasks:
  - name: Read Data File
    set_fact:
      data: "{{lookup('ansible.builtin.file', './input.txt').split('\n')}}"

  - name: Show debug data
    ansible.builtin.debug: var=data

  - name: Create a new array
    set_fact: 
      data_elements: &#091;]

  - name: Loop through lines and add data elements to array
    set_fact:
      data_elements: "{{ data_elements + &#091;{'name': item}] }}"
    loop: "{{ data }}"

  - name: Show debug data
    ansible.builtin.debug: var=data_elements

  - name: Write output json file
    copy:
      dest: output.json
      content: "{{ {'records': data_elements} | to_json }}" 
</code></pre>



<h3>Task By Task Breakdown</h3>



<p>Since most of the code here is the same, I will only focus on breaking out the differences.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code> - name: Create a new array
    set_fact: 
      data_elements: &#091;]</code></pre>



<p>The block above sets up the empty data_elements array that we will utilize to map our file lines onto.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>  - name: Loop through lines and add data elements to array
    set_fact:
      data_elements: "{{ data_elements + &#091;{'name': item}] }}"
    loop: "{{ data }}"</code></pre>



<p>This is setting up a loop to loop over our initial data variable which was read from input.txt.  It is appending new dictionaries into a larger array with a key of &#8216;name&#8217; and a value of the item in a loop.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>  - name: Write output json file
    copy:
      dest: output.json
      content: "{{ {'records': data_elements} | to_json }}" </code></pre>



<p>Finally, we are doing the same write operation as the simple example, but this time we are creating a dictionary with a key of &#8216;records&#8217; and a value of the data_elements array.</p>



<p>This will have an output that looks like this:</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code json"><code>{
   "records":&#091;
      {
         "name":"/site/foo/"
      },
      {
         "name":"/site/bar/"
      }
   ]
}</code></pre>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>As I stated at the beginning of the article, data manipulation in DevOps is a key skill to learn.  Hopefully, this helps kickstart someone on their journey into becoming a DevOps engineer!.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Do DevOps Engineers Write a lot of Scripting Code?</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/devops-scripting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greer Shepherd]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 21:45:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tools]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1180</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Whether it’s Python, JavaScript, or other programming languages, Developers spend a lot of time writing code. More traditional infrastructure engineers are going to spend their time in a user interface configuring their systems and services to work for their organizations.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Whether it’s Python, JavaScript, or other programming languages, Developers spend a lot of time writing code. More traditional infrastructure engineers are going to spend their time in a user interface configuring their systems and services to work for their organizations. Operations teams are going to be picking up what was developed for them by other groups and determine the right ways to run it efficiently.</p>



<p><strong><a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="Demystifying the DevOps Methodology and How You Can Leverage it for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> engineers are going to be performing configuration management efforts, software development, operations activities, and quality assurance activities. Each of these can be automated by writing code with scripting languages. This means that DevOps engineers write code!</strong></p>



<p>Let&#8217;s explore what this means to a DevOps engineer who may not be comfortable with code since they are coming from a practice that generally performs their activities inside of a user interface.</p>


<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
</p>



<h2>Why Scripting Code is Important</h2>



<p>Automation is important. It’s a key part of the DevOps process, which aims to reduce the time it takes to perform manual processes. Automation also increases the reliability and stability of those processes.</p>



<p>While a lot of people talk about it, they rarely talk about why. If you don’t have a good reason, there’s a good chance that you won’t see the benefits of automation in your organization. That’s why it helps to understand why you are automating in the first place.</p>



<p>DevOps organizations have a lot of tools and technologies that need to integrate together. DevOps engineers will spend almost every day automating these integrations utilizing a variety of scripting languages or DevOps tools.</p>



<p>When you spend your days configuring everything from <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="14" title="AWS" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">AWS</a> keys to the location of a database; it’s easy to understand why organizations want to reduce the amount of time spent doing it manually.</p>



<h2>DevOps and Scripts</h2>



<p>Those who work across multiple different technologies to build applications and services spend a ton of time configuring environments, virtual machines, and cloud providers.</p>



<p>That means developers have to learn how to use every single one of those tools. At first, this might feel like a chore; after all, no one wants to learn how to use Inversion of Control (IoC) or batch files to get something from AWS into their local computer or network.</p>



<p>When you look at it from the perspective of someone who spends most of his or her day typing in code and reading other people’s scripts—the process can seem more like an abomination than anything else.</p>



<p>A majority of engineers are writing scripts to make their jobs more efficient. Scripts are the shortcut version of automation. They’re designed to help engineers reduce the amount of time they spend doing system administration, delivering software to servers, monitoring systems, performing configuration management, managing cloud vendors, and many other activities.</p>



<p>I have always advocated if you perform an activity against a user interface that has an API then you should take the time to implement that activity in code via your scripting language of choice.</p>



<p>By scripting your changes out, you both get an opportunity to codify a change, but you have an opportunity to introduce that code into version control. This will help shift the responsibility of that code from a single person to an entire team.</p>



<p>Additionally, scripting gives you the opportunity to add comments to your code. Software developers utilizing high-level programming languages will add comments in their code so that the next person that picks up their work understands the intentions of their work. Changes through scripting should be treated the same way. When someone spends time writing scripts, those should be added to the collective code base and their peers should be able to understand the code and consume their work.</p>



<p>Contributing to the code base also allows that code to be integrated into CI/CD systems for future automated actions.</p>



<h2>Which DevOps Engineers Should be Working With Scripts?</h2>



<p>The first step in automating any process is figuring out who should do the automation. That can be tricky. It’s easy to think that the developers who spend most of their day writing code should be the ones to automate their work.</p>



<p>After all, they have all of the technical knowledge. But, depending on the organization, that might not be the best idea. In organizations using DevOps practices, developers aren’t soley responsible for creating new end-to-end application solutions.</p>



<p>Instead, everyone on the team is responsible for creating an entire infrastructure along with the entire DevOps lifecycle.</p>



<p>DevOps engineers are responsible for automating the deployment and operations process of software applications. They are responsible for automating everything from creating configuration files to configuring software environments.</p>



<p>Many DevOps engineers work with scripts. There are many reasons why this is the case. One reason is that scripts allow DevOps engineers to automate tasks that are repeatable across multiple environments and application iterations.</p>



<p>If an automated task must be performed multiple times during the development process, it makes sense to create a script that can be used in each environment. Another reason is that scripts help reduce errors by providing clear instructions on how to perform the task.</p>



<p>DevOps engineers should be knowledgeable about scripting languages, such as Bash, Python, Ruby, and Javascript. They should also be familiar with automation tools like <a href="https://www.docker.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="16" title="Docker" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Docker</a> and <a href="https://www.ansible.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="7" title="Ansible">Ansible</a>.</p>



<p>They should be able to identify areas where automation can improve their workflow and determine what types of changes are needed to make automation possible in their organization.</p>



<h2>Why is it So Hard to Transition from Scripting to Automation?</h2>



<p>It might seem like your engineers would love to transition from scripting to automation. After all, they are spending their day writing code.</p>



<p>Sometimes a jump from scripting to automation can be difficult. If scripts are not written in a way that they can be parameterized, those scripts will not fit into an overall automation structure natively. Additionally, when you’re used to customizing everything from your local machine to your cloud providers, the thought of learning a new configuration tool can seem like a nightmare.</p>



<p>All of this confusion can lead engineers to either choose not to automate at all or make bad choices about how to automate. The software development industry has an answer for this.</p>



<p>Most engineers will take a little bit of time to work through the transition from their previous role into one that is inclusive of DevOps. This is why it is so critical to work with the team on learning DevOps and embracing a full DevOps transition.</p>



<p>Most software development starts as writing scripts, shell scripting, or learning bash. From there, it will expand into utilizing different popular programming languages. If your background is in Office365 administration, you will not go through this general progression.</p>



<p>Developers should take new DevOps engineers under their wing and help them utilize tools that may not be ultimately familiar with. DevOps engineering is the combination of many different skill sets breaking down traditional barriers. Helping DevOps engineers write scripts that are able to be integrated into a larger set of automation will be a huge step forward for anyone feeling lost in this adoption.</p>


<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
</p>



<h2>How to Get Started With Automation in a DevOps Organization</h2>



<p>DevOps engineers constantly improve their automation, but there’s a lot to learn. That’s why it’s important to bring on someone to help with the transition to automation.</p>



<p>There are a few things you can do to get started. First, look at your existing scripts and see if you have any that could be automated. Are there any tasks that are taking more time than they should? If so, you might want to take a closer look at them. Next, look at your existing infrastructure. Do you have a known, consistent state? If so, you might want to take a closer look at your scripts.</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>If you’re a DevOps engineer who is coming from a user interface, the idea of writing code that can automate different tasks may seem scary. You may feel overwhelmed by the scope of this responsibility and wonder whether you can actually do it.</p>



<p>To start, you can check out some resources that are available on <a href="https://www.github.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="6" title="Github" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">GitHub</a>. One of the best ways to get started is to dive right into the world of scripting. The Python programming language is great for beginner developers because it’s very easy to pick up and performs well under the hood. Python has a free online course available that teaches you the basics with a few projects you can complete.</p>



<p>Once you know your way around Python, you can move on to the next step. As you progress, you can check out some of the other scripting languages in use. There are many options out there, and most of them are open-source and available for use. Your best bet is to choose one that you feel comfortable with, and then get familiar with the basics. You can find plenty of tutorials and documentation on how to get started with any of them.</p>



<p>When you feel ready, you can start experimenting with the different ways to configure your systems.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Are DevOps Engineers in Demand in 2022?</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/are-devops-engineers-in-demand/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 20:17:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[delivery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jobs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1127</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Whether you are looking to make a shift in your career path, or you are looking to change companies a common question job seekers will have is &#8220;Are DevOps Engineers in Demand?&#8221; Simply looking at job boards and reviewing the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Whether you are looking to make a shift in your career path, or you are looking to change companies a common question job seekers will have is &#8220;Are <a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="Demystifying the DevOps Methodology and How You Can Leverage it for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> Engineers in Demand?&#8221;</p>



<p><strong>Simply looking at job boards and reviewing the numbers does not tell the entire story here. As of the time of writing LinkedIn has roughly 42,000 positions and Indeed has roughly 11,000 positions for the search term DevOps engineer.</strong></p>



<p>I believe that the honest answer to this question has more to do with market conditions than it does with job openings, though job openings are still a good indicator.</p>



<p>Let&#8217;s take a look at the market conditions to understand if a DevOps engineering skillset is in demand!</p>


<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
</p>



<h2>Rising Demand for DevOps Talent</h2>



<p>Many of us in the technology industry know how DevOps is revolutionizing software development. Companies adopting the DevOps approach are doing more with greater efficiency in the process. DevOps can help a company provide a software solution quickly. It can therefore help prevent production problems if necessary and the result will also be improved customer experience, feedback, and communications.</p>



<p>Through to pandemic, more and more businesses needed to move to a digital presence to stay competitive in the market. This either means investing more heavily in technology or standing up new technology they may not have been ready for.</p>



<p>As the dust has settled, businesses are now left with aging technology that is not growing with their business which means future investment. The tech industry is stepping up to respond in this newly opened market.</p>



<p>If a business is not purely technology focused but utilizes technologies to enable sales, they are going to want to get into the most reliable modes of future delivery. This is where DevOps skills are filling the gap.</p>



<p>I have seen a new term popping up in the industry recently: &#8220;DevOps As A Service&#8221;. This is born out of the idea that the DevOps methodology can be bolted onto technologies that are becoming more relevant in the market to ensure more reliable modes of delivery.</p>



<h2>Is DevOps still in Demand?</h2>



<p>I am a hiring manager running a DevOps group. I have been hiring, training, and converting people from either IT operations teams or software development teams for nearly a decade now. I can confidently say that DevOps engineering roles are hard to fill, they are also very in demand and you need to move quickly when hiring.</p>



<h2>DevOps Talent is Still Hard to Find</h2>



<p>Let&#8217;s face it, the industry has done a terrible job of defining what DevOps really is. In most places, my experience has been, DevOps means infrastructure as code and does not account for the overall methodology.</p>



<p>Because of the incongruency between expectation and implementation, I would argue that a large portion of the talent pool is underdeveloped at this point. With the proper guidance, the talented job seekers out there can transition into a more DevOps-oriented mindset.</p>



<p>Businesses will need to take this into account when hiring for a DevOps engineer role. The perfect purple unicorn may not be as readily available as more well-defined roles like software engineering. With a little time and patience with a team committed to DevOps transformations, you can develop talent that will deliver high-quality work.</p>



<h2>Is it hard to get a job in DevOps?</h2>



<p>Many organizations do not know what DevOps actually means, so it&#8217;s challenging to find the right person for the position.</p>



<p>I updated my LinkedIn profile in 2015 to illustrate my transition into DevOps Engineering. Since then, I have progressed through an organization to lead teams of DevOps engineers.</p>



<p>I am not telling you this to brag, but I do want to use it as an example.</p>



<p>In my previous life, I was a PHP developer. I got bored of putting values into a database and then returning the exact same values to the screen. I started to get interested in configuration management and continuous integration which is when i hit the job market looking for my next gig.</p>



<p>Since 2015, when i changed by job title on LinkedIn, i still get recruiters reaching out looking to place me in another software engineering role.</p>



<p>I believe that the cycle of job searching in the technology industry is a bit upside down today. Companies seek talent and job seekers are looking for companies that want their skilled talent. It should be a perfect union, but there are a hoard of recruiters standing in the way of those perfect fits.</p>



<p>I would recommend spending your time learning about DevOps methodologies, optimizing value, soft skill, interpersonal skills, and automation tools. Form there, i would spend time looking up individuals with existing DevOps roles on LinkedIn (management or engineering) and make some connections. Those connections have a better chance of landing you a DevOps role than the normal recruiting mechanism most of the technology space uses today.</p>



<h2>Is DevOps Engineer a good career?</h2>



<p>DevOps is booming with an estimated US $287 billion market size by 2026. There are many roles available to developers in the world&#8217;s marketplace. Let&#8217;s face it, technology is not going away. Businesses that survive over the long haul are going to progressively adopt newer and more modern strategies to optimize their software development life cycle.</p>



<p>Because of the perpetual adoption of DevOps methodology by businesses, a DevOps engineer is going to have a long and vibrant career path. Silo&#8217;d development and operations teams will become more of an antiquated setup, and the merge of these disciplines together will become more of the norm.</p>



<p>I think the answer of &#8220;Good&#8221; is probably a bit more nebulous and needs a bit of personal soul-searching to really answer. I won&#8217;t be able to answer what is &#8220;Good&#8221; for you.</p>


<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="3622503162"></ins>
</p>



<h2>Why DevOps is a Good Career in 2022?</h2>



<p>DevOps has remained a popular role since its inception in 2018. CodinGame released a survey that ranks &#8220;DevOps Engineer&#8221; among the most popular developer job positions for 2021. Additionally, the survey revealed that 43% of hiring professionals are unable to fulfill their DevOps roles.</p>



<h2>What are Relevant Skills to start a DevOps career?</h2>



<p>Unlike most careers, DevOps requires basic knowledge and skills. When choosing an employment option, understanding this section can prove very important. If you do this before, then the barriers will be lower. Depending on the skills you have you can try another course.</p>



<p>I have an entire write-up over here that discusses the <a href="https://www.valewood.org/top-relevant-devops-skills/" data-type="post" data-id="330">Top Relevant DevOps Skills</a>.</p>



<p>TLDR; Focus on skills that support the DevOps philosophy. These are going to be focused on soft skills such as planning and communication. Also focus on learning some new tools, ci/cd, how to enable automation, and automated testing.</p>



<p>Don&#8217;t be afraid if you are lacking in any of these areas as well, most of the &#8220;DevOps pros&#8221; that i talk to are not familiar with half of the skills described in either the blog post or TLDR.</p>



<h2>How do I Progress in my DevOps Career?</h2>



<p>DevOps engineers with learning mindsets will be able to develop in their respective fields with plenty more to do. It seems obvious that one has to progress from junior engineering engineer to junior engineer eventually becoming a leader. DevOps also offers many career changes that could be made.</p>



<p>A simple way to think about progression is to focus on anything that helps drive a business forward through growth or hitting new targets. This means that, in general, new technologies will not progress your career path forward.</p>



<p>Building a DevOps mindset, working with a team to adopt DevOps, training new DevOps engineers, working with teams to develop software in a more streamlined way, bringing in automated testing, breaking down organizational silos, influencing team leaders, and any other non-technology-specific skill you can pick up will help progress your DevOps career.</p>



<p>Focusing on technologies will help progress from a DevOps engineer role into a DevOps architect role, but note that a pure technology focus does have an upper bound on it. That is not a bad thing because not everybody wants to get into management.</p>



<p>If you are looking to progress your career into management, work on building a DevOps culture.</p>



<h2>Will I get paid more as a DevOps Engineer?</h2>



<p>DevOps professionals are generally paid quite well. This is because the skillset for DevOps jobs demands a broader set of skilled talent. DevOps experts who can work with companies on DevOps transformations will yield an even greater salary. When negotiating, do not sell your talents and skills short.</p>



<p>If you are just diving into this space, also be realistic about where you are at and sell yourself on your aptitude and ability to learn new skills. Any organization worth sticking around and working for will recognize your growth and give you the bump in compensation that you deserve.</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>DevOps is evolving and changing. It is growing in importance for businesses to move forward in the digital age. DevOps engineers are key players in this evolution and have a wide range of skills needed by companies to thrive in the modern economy. They can work within many different industries, from financial services to automotive. DevOps engineers typically work with software teams across multiple departments within organizations, including IT operations and engineering.</p>



<p>DevOps teams are constantly looking for more talent that can fulfill the vision of smoother and more reliable delivery. That trend is not going away any time soon!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is DevOps a Skill?</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/devops-skills/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 02:17:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[delivery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opinion]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1103</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This is a pretty loaded question. Is cooking a skill? Are home builders skilled or unskilled labor? A skill would denote being able to do something well or having expertise in practice. Skills can be trained! Being in a field&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>This is a pretty loaded question.  Is cooking a skill?  Are home builders skilled or unskilled labor?  A skill would denote being able to do something well or having expertise in practice.  Skills can be trained!  Being in a field of skilled labor like running CNC equipment requires a tremendous amount of skill.</p>



<p>So, is <a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="Demystifying the DevOps Methodology and How You Can Leverage it for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> a skill or is it a logical evolution where technology delivery ends up going regardless of the forces that drive it there?</p>


<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
</p>



<h2>Technology Delivery</h2>



<p>Delivering technology, with any kind of <a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/benefits-of-devops/devops-culture-of-quality/" data-type="page" data-id="1036">quality</a> backing that delivery, will require several different practices.  Depending on your domain; you will probably employ the specialties of software developers, infrastructure/cloud engineers, quality assurance engineers, security engineers, and network engineers, along with a whole host of other roles.  Each of those roles is critical to the successful execution of a project at a very high standard.  </p>



<p>Once the technology is delivered to the market, someone is going to have to pick up the mantle and run that technology solution.  In some organizations that will be a dedicated operations team, and in others they will adhere to a &#8220;you build it you own it&#8221; strategy.</p>



<p>One of the biggest misnomers that I run across quite frequently is this; once a project is launched, the skilled labor that developed that project is no longer needed over the lifetime of that technology.  I believe that this could not be further from the truth.</p>



<h2>Technology Lifecycle > Delivery</h2>



<p>I prefer to look at technology through the lens of a lifecycle rather than a static point-in-time delivery.  Once a technology product is launched, it needs a tremendous amount of care and feeding to ensure that it remains valuable to its end users.  </p>



<p>Due to the complex nature of the domains that I generally work in, this means that the skilled labor that helped produce said technology product will continue to have a hand in that technology product for its entire lifecycle.  It does not mean that they will be entirely dedicated to a single effort, but it does mean they will continue to lend their expertise.</p>



<p>So, how does this answer the question &#8220;Is DevOps a skill?&#8221;.  For me, the answer is a simple one, YES!  But I think that it first takes an understanding of what <a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-type="page" data-id="505">DevOps</a> is.</p>



<h2>What is DevOps?</h2>



<p>DevOps is a series of practices that combine together into a consistent delivery flow for technology.  It is generally misrepresented as purely automation, but that is only a particular skilled practice inside DevOps.  Embracing DevOps fully is a serious commitment to changing how technology delivery is performed, and full adoption means that you will be more interested in the overall lifecycle of technology instead of just finite delivery points in time.</p>



<h2>What Expertise is Needed for DevOps?</h2>



<p>I believe that most organizations are following a more traditional software delivery methodology.  They have not adopted DevOps or agile in any meaningful way, and if they have at the very least adopted agile they are not using a standardized framework.  This is not true everywhere, but I believe it is more true than false.</p>



<h3>Advocating for and Leading Change</h3>



<p>Since most organizations are building and deploying software with some degree of success in whatever way works for them, to build real DevOps adoption, a change agent is going to need to be bravely thrown into the mix to help drive the change they want to see in the world.</p>



<p>Let&#8217;s face it, Change is hard.  Change brings the unknown right to our doorsteps and forces us to confront aspects of our work that may feel uncomfortable.  Depending on your level in an organization, either being an advocate for change or leading through change is a trainable skill that individuals should look into developing.</p>



<h3>Agile Project Management</h3>



<p>Project management is a pretty crowded space.  There are plenty of certifications out there that individuals can go get to skill up in this space as well.  But, agile project management is not just for project managers, everyone should become well versed in this space.</p>



<p>Learning about risks and risk management, work breakdown structures, timelines, forecasting, Gantt charts, resource management, and all of the rest of the highly skilled practices in agile project management will only enhance a DevOps team&#8217;s ability to deliver effective and high-quality solutions.  If a project manager is left to fully manage a project independently while engineers are heads down in code and poorly communicating, that project is doomed for failure from the very beginning.</p>


<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
</p>



<h3>Transforming Communication</h3>



<p>In order to adopt effective DevOps practices, a team will need to build effective communication patterns.  </p>



<p>Some organizations will adopt a pattern of tickets first.  &#8220;If it isn&#8217;t in the ticket, it didn&#8217;t happen&#8221;.  This is a great asynchronous communication pattern that ensures that communication is available more broadly to any consumers that may have questions or need updates.  It is an ineffective communication pattern if nobody ever reads the tickets.</p>



<p>Other organizations will adopt in-person or remote scrums to talk about what they worked on, will be working on, and challenges.  This can be a really good communication pattern for individuals who like to talk through and collaborate on problems.  This is a terrible pattern when it comes to groups that are spread a little too thin or have a WIP problem.</p>



<p>Communication must work for the individuals who are producing communication and consuming communication.  I have seen multiple different scenarios fail because members of the team are not willing to adapt to each other and ensure success.  There are a tremendous number of tools on the market, I am confident that any team willing to put in the work to find the right one can become effective communicators.</p>



<h3>Effective Feedback Loops</h3>



<p>Along with communication, feedback loops are also incredibly important to a DevOps team.  If automated testing fails, where do notifications go?  If there is a problem with production, where does communication go?  If these two events, or many other different kinds of events, impact delivery; where does that communication go?</p>



<p>By ensuring that feedback is making its way back to the proper parties, more effective data-driven decision-making can happen.  Without feedback loops from tools, systems, or people; we are all left guessing!</p>



<h3>Tools Tools Tools</h3>



<p>10 years ago, the market for DevOps tools (technology tools) was pretty sparse.  You were left with bash scripts on Linux servers, limited API access, and using your legs to walk down to your local data center to pop in the newest RedHat CD.</p>



<p>Today, the number of tools in the DevOps space is expansive.  I am not going to go too deep into the tooling here because of its depth, but any DevOps team worth its weight will need to have some serious skills with the latest DevOps tools.</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>I wrote this post to answer the question, &#8220;Is DevOps a skill?&#8221;.  I believe that the answer to that question is a resounding yes.  It is as much of a skill as sculpting clay into a piece of art or customizing a classic car.  There is a high degree of depth in expertise for a DevOps team to be effective in their delivery processes.  Finally, any organization out there that thinks they are doing DevOps without these skills is not fully realizing the benefits that DevOps has to offer.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Which Programming Language Should I Learn as a DevOps Engineer?</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/devops-languages/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 22:11:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tools]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=344</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[DevOps&#160;is all about bringing software development and operations together under a single functional team to increase quality, communication, collaboration, and efficiency.&#160; Developers already have a background in development (duh), but a question I get asked frequently by operations engineers is&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong><a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="Demystifying the DevOps Methodology and How You Can Leverage it for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a></strong>&nbsp;is all about bringing software development and operations together under a single functional team to increase quality, communication, collaboration, and efficiency.&nbsp; Developers already have a background in development (duh), but a question I get asked frequently by operations engineers is “Are there 4 top programming languages to learn for DevOps?”</p>



<p>Everyone could use a little bit of development in their life.&nbsp; It could be something as simple as a bash script to take care of a simple task, all the way up to running a blog like this one.&nbsp; Learning about the logical flow that a computer takes to compute everything is an empowering door to open when growing as a technology specialist in whatever field you specialize in.</p>



<p>There are numerous programming languages to choose from so it can be a bit daunting to narrow it down when doing research. Luckily, I have done some narrowing down for you!&nbsp; Below are a few of my favorite DevOps languages but this is by no means a definitive list.&nbsp; These are languages that I have used in my workflows and found some great success.</p>



<p>Let&#8217;s discuss some of the popular programming languages you can learn as someone with little to no experience so you can level up your DevOps game!</p>


<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
</p>



<h2>Interpreted vs Compiled Languages</h2>



<p>The first concept that we should tackle is the difference between an interpreted language vs a compiled language.&nbsp; There are some specific semantics to get under your belt as part of your language selection process.&nbsp; In the world of DevOps, I would say that there really is not an incorrect choice here, but; DevOps is all about flow and your choices here can have an impact on your desired technology flow.</p>



<h3>Interpreted Langauge</h3>



<p>An interpreted language requires that a separate runtime be installed on your system which will generally perform a JIT runtime on the code you have written.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>If I am writing code in Python, and I want that python to run on a remote Linux system, I need to have both the Python runtime installed on the remote system along with ensuring my code also exists on that system.</p>



<p>There is some practical utility to this.&nbsp; Your systems require a dependency like Python, PHP, Ruby, Bash, etc. to be installed on the remote system, but you get a pretty good guarantee that you can write code once and use it in many places across many architectures.&nbsp; The architecture (x86, ARM, SPARC, etc) has the runtime binaries installed (Python) and Just In Time “compile” (interprets) your code to be run on that architecture.&nbsp; Pretty neat right?</p>



<h3>Compiled Languages</h3>



<p>A compiled language requires that a full compilation happens prior to the code being runnable.&nbsp; In Windows land, think about this like a .exe file, or on Linux, this would be a binary.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>If I am writing code in C++, and I want to run by C++ on a remote Linux system, I have 2 options.&nbsp; I can install C++ on the remote system, add my code to that system, run a compile step, and finally run my binary.&nbsp; Alternatively, I could compile my binary locally (ensuring I match the OS and CPU architecture as part of the compile step) and then distribute that binary to the remote system for execution.</p>



<p>Generally, a compiled language will be statically linked which means that there are zero additional dependencies that need to live on a remote system, unlike an interpreted language.&nbsp; You do need to have a more detailed understanding of the remote system you will be deploying to so that your pre-compiled binary has a much better shot of being able to run on the destination.</p>



<h3>Need for Speed?</h3>



<p>Compiled languages are generally going to be faster than interpreted languages.&nbsp; A compiled application or script does not need to get converted from human-readable text into a binary that the CPU will understand.&nbsp; That compilation was done when the application was built.&nbsp; An interpreted language is going to need some kind of JIT compilation in order to be executed through the language&#8217;s runtime.&nbsp; In the PHP world, this JIT compilation is transforming human-readable text into OpCode.&nbsp; Once that OpCode is created then the PHP runtime can just execute what the OpCode tells it to execute.</p>



<p>When trying to do tool selection, there is generally an argument about the speed an application runs and whether the right tool is the fastest tool.&nbsp; When doing DevOps where you are generally trying to get a machine or environment into a specific state, the speed of the language itself is generally not your biggest impediment.&nbsp; Your biggest bottleneck will be remote resources like packages, downloads, etc.&nbsp; I would rather choose the right tool for the job inside of the ecosystem that I work in instead of trying to make my tool selection for DevOps based solely on performance.</p>



<h2>DevOps with Python</h2>



<p>Python is an interpreted language and was created in the 1980s by Guido van Rossum in the Netherlands.&nbsp; It is widely adopted and widely used across the industry.&nbsp; You can find Python pre-installed on most modern Linux distributions today, though there is still a bit of fracturing between Python 2.x and 3.x communities. Aside from Javascript, you will find that Python is easily one of the most popular programming languages ou there today.</p>



<h3>How Big is the Python Community?</h3>



<p>Python has a strong community backing it.&nbsp; At the time of writing this, PyPI has ~391,000 packages with nearly 660,000,000 package downloads per day.&nbsp; PyPI is a package repository for Python where you can download community or vendor-developed code and add it directly to your project.&nbsp; There are a lot of pre-solved problems out there like connecting to a database.&nbsp; PyPI enables users to download packages like those database connectors automatically.</p>



<h3>What is the Utility of Python?</h3>



<p>Python has a lot of utility in the DevOps space.&nbsp; Since it is born out of the Linux and Unix ecosystem, it has some very strong ties to the Linux operating system for performing common tasks.&nbsp; It is so well suited for this task that <a href="https://www.ansible.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="7" title="Ansible">Ansible</a>-Core is written in Python.&nbsp; Python is also runnable on Windows!</p>



<p>Python is clearly a good choice when it comes to writing automation code for DevOps, but it has a lot of other utilities as well.&nbsp; Much of the Big-Data space is using python for number crunching and machine learning specifically because the language lends itself well to that kind of computation.&nbsp; Being a dynamically typed language instead of a statically typed one, data transformations can be done quickly without a lot of overhead by the end user.</p>



<p>Being an interpreted language gives it a lot of power as well when it comes to distributing and running the code.&nbsp; Aside from activities like automated testing, packaging Python consists of compressing your directory structure, moving it to where you want, decompressing, and finally running the code.&nbsp; If there is a bug, you can also fix it in place, though I would recommend ensuring that you have centralized code repositories and follow a good process of version control and pushing new versions out.</p>



<h3>Python Learning Resources</h3>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.learnpython.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://www.learnpython.org/</a></li><li><a href="https://www.codecademy.com/learn/learn-python" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://www.codecademy.com/learn/learn-python</a></li><li><a href="https://www.pythontutorial.net/python-basics/python-write-csv-file/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://www.pythontutorial.net/python-basics/python-write-csv-file/</a></li></ul>



<h2>DevOps with JavaScript</h2>



<p>Nevertheless, Javascript may not have a lot of flexibility compared to Python but is still widely available to add value in DevOps. It can be incorporated as client code as well as server code. JavaScript is widely available on the web and has a huge footprint. If your work environments depend on Node.js, the ability to develop Javascript is an advantage. As with Python, JavaScript has an enormous user base. There are many Javascript projects that could benefit from this community.</p>



<p>Much like Python, is an interpreted language. Unlike Python, Javascript is easily multithreaded (async tasks on a single main thread) directly out of the box with no additional work required. Javascript creates immersive and interactive websites, can be used as a server-side scripting language, can be used for GUI development powering both mobile and desktop applications, and can be utilized to build fully functional server and client-side web-based applications. It really is the swiss army knife of DevOps programming languages.</p>



<p>If you start to work with Javascript, you will find that it is an extremely versatile language and it could be the right programming language for your specific cases. There is a reason why the community is as large as it is!</p>



<h3>How big is the Javascript Community?</h3>



<p>Javascript could probably be considered the most popular programming language at this point. I would not argue that by code volume, but I would argue that just about every single developer that has touched the internet has either developed, debugged, or been confused by Javascript. The community then got bigger with the advent of Node.JS. This moved code from the front end to the backend where it could easily be run on a server. At the time of writing, there are over 1.3 million NPM packages available for consumption.</p>



<h3>What is the Utility of Javascript?</h3>



<p>When it comes to DevOps engineers, Javascript is widely used across numerous cloud platforms as a configuration management tool, scripting language, or as traffic routing or traffic modification runtime. <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="14" title="AWS" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">AWS</a> Cloudfront uses Javascript as its primary configuration language in its event-driven Origin or Response systems. <a href="https://pages.cloudflare.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="10" title="Cloudflare Pages" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Cloudflare pages</a> will utilize Javascript as its Functions framework for performing request modifications in line with internet requests.</p>



<p>DevOps engineers are going to need a pile of scripting languages at their disposal as we. If you are working in an environment that already has Node.JS included, then Javascript can be a really good language to use. This Blog uses Node.JS as its delivery pipeline through Cloudflare Pages to do some content manipulation between WordPress and publishing static pages.</p>



<h4>Additional Utility!</h4>



<p>Javascript can be utilized as an interactive command language directly from the browser through the Developer tools. An ICL lets you input code into a running environment to get information back. Through Developer Tools consoles, you are able to run code, print variable states, etc.</p>



<p>Popular tools like VSCode are also written in Javascript (TypeScript) using a tool called Electron. Electron is a cross-platform application framework for running Javascript, HTML, and CSS on desktop.</p>



<h3>Javascript Learning Resources</h3>



<ul><li><a target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.codecademy.com/learn/introduction-to-javascript">https://www.codecademy.com/learn/introduction-to-javascript</a></li><li><a target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://teamtreehouse.com/library/javascript-basics">https://teamtreehouse.com/library/javascript-basics</a></li><li><a target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.learn-js.org/">https://www.learn-js.org/</a></li></ul>



<h2>DevOps with Golang</h2>



<p>Golang was originally designed at Google in 2007 as a replacement for C and C++.&nbsp; Go foregoes some of the more tedious facets of C and C++ like header files for type definitions.&nbsp; Go is also a compiled language instead of an interpreted language meaning that the result of something in Golang is going to be a binary.&nbsp; Golant has quickly grown in popularity and is the core language behind the very popular container orchestration framework <a href="https://kubernetes.io/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="4" title="Kubernetes" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Kubernetes</a>.</p>



<h3>Community</h3>



<p>The size of the Golang community is tough to nail down because of the way that Go mod works.&nbsp; Go mod can be any git URL that has a go.mod and go.sum file in its repository.&nbsp; From there, go mod will check out the code, and check out the code&#8217;s dependencies all while doing dependency resolution in the background.&nbsp; Since git can be hosted anywhere, nailing down how many downloads a day without some kind of body providing central registration of packages like PyPI does, the best we can do is look at something like google trends for a baseline of activity.</p>



<script type="text/javascript" src="https://ssl.gstatic.com/trends_nrtr/3045_RC01/embed_loader.js"></script>
  <script type="text/javascript">
    trends.embed.renderExploreWidget("TIMESERIES", {"comparisonItem":[{"keyword":"/m/09gbxjr","geo":"US","time":"today 12-m"},{"keyword":"/m/06ff5","geo":"US","time":"today 12-m"},{"keyword":"/m/05z1_","geo":"US","time":"today 12-m"}],"category":0,"property":""}, {"exploreQuery":"geo=US&q=%2Fm%2F09gbxjr,%2Fm%2F06ff5,%2Fm%2F05z1_&date=today 12-m,today 12-m,today 12-m","guestPath":"https://trends.google.com:443/trends/embed/"});
  </script>



<p>As you can see by the graphic above, at the time of writing, Python is the dominant search in Google Trends compared to something like Golang.&nbsp; I would consider Golang a strong and growing community with projects like Kubernetes and CockroachDB along with large technology groups moving into using the stack like <a href="https://www.github.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="6" title="Github" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">GitHub</a> and Uber.</p>



<h3>Utility</h3>



<p>In my workflow, I am generally using Golang for 2 things; microservice apps and API middleware.</p>



<p>When I say microservice apps, I am generally not talking about something which is composed of a larger ecosystem.&nbsp; My microservice-type apps are usually tied into a Kubernetes stack.&nbsp; I had a particular challenge with <a href="https://linkerd.io/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="3" title="Linkerd" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">LinkerD</a> where I need to create a MutatingAdmissionWebhook to rewrite my HTTP(s) probes as in pod curl probes after setting my namespace to deny all.&nbsp; This was a good workaround to wrapping and rewriting many different helm charts to use curl probes instead of using standard HTTP(s) probes.</p>



<p>You can find that code <a href="https://github.com/gwagner/linkerd-convert-http-to-curl" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>When doing API orchestration, I have written a few applications which will pull data from one API (or have data pushed via a webhook) into an application that may amend or transform the data before pushing it into another receiving API.&nbsp; This is particularly useful when trying to normalize data from system A to system B.&nbsp; This was particularly useful when moving from a Graphite-based metric TSDB system over to InfluxDB.&nbsp; We did not need to rewrite all of our metric collectors, we just needed to tap into the metric stream, do an on-the-fly conversion, and then output metrics to InfluxDB.</p>



<h3>Learning Resources</h3>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.udemy.com/course/go-building-devops-tools/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://www.udemy.com/course/go-building-devops-tools/</a></li><li><a href="https://go.dev/learn/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://go.dev/learn/</a></li><li><a href="https://www.codecademy.com/learn/learn-go" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://www.codecademy.com/learn/learn-go</a></li></ul>



<h2>DevOps with Ruby</h2>



<p>Because of its efficiency in DevOps, Ruby is a preferred scripting language for automating IT environments&#8217; repetitive tasks. In addition to web development, data science, and unit testing, this dynamic, interpreted programming language is used for DevOps. Ruby is also fairly simple to learn. As a result, the language has a fast-growing community of DevOps engineers. With no prior programming experience, beginners can get started with Ruby pretty quickly.&nbsp;</p>



<h3>Community</h3>



<p>Ruby is a difficult community to quantify fully simply because of how spread out it is.&nbsp; Ruby Gem can be a good baseline metric with roughly ~174,000 gems available from RubyGems.org and 111B+ (yeah, billion) downloads.&nbsp; If you look past ruby gems, the second most popular place that ruby is being utilized is with <a href="https://www.chef.io/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="8" title="Chef">Chef</a>.&nbsp; The marketplace has roughly 4,000 cookbooks with roughly ~80,0000 maintainers</p>



<h3>Utility</h3>



<p>Ruby has some great utility when it comes to DevOps automation.&nbsp; When building out an early DevOps-focused monitoring stack, we chose Sensu Core due to its configuration-driven and scalable design.&nbsp; Most of the community-produced checks at that point were written in ruby which lent itself very well to building reusable consistent libraries that were well-tested.</p>



<p>Much like the Golang example above, I have also utilized ruby as an API middleware for doing data payload manipulations.&nbsp; Prior to <a href="https://www.docker.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="16" title="Docker" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Docker</a> supporting <a href="https://docs.docker.com/config/containers/logging/json-file/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">JSON File Logging</a>, there were very long debates about what separation between log entries means between different programming languages.&nbsp; Ruby was used in an environment where I was working into tail log output from containers and based on its configuration, properly parse and package logs to be sent to centralized logging systems upstream with additional metadata.</p>



<h3>Learning Resources</h3>



<ul><li><a href="https://gorails.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://gorails.com/</a></li><li><a href="https://www.chef.io/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://www.chef.io/</a></li></ul>


<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
</p>



<h2>Security Considerations</h2>



<p>When utilizing any code for any function whether it be DevOps or software development, you should always be concerned about security.&nbsp; Let’s say you have a 3-year-old server sitting around and its original automation code has not had any electricity run through it in the same time frame.&nbsp; That server&#8217;s automation code is probably outdated enough that there is at least some kind of CVE attached to it.&nbsp; This will be particularly easy to find if you are doing robust infrastructure scanning but will be much more obscure if you are running compiled binaries where the source code is not under some kind of routine scrutiny.&nbsp; Regardless of how you are building and running code, please make sure to clean up after yourself and avoid getting attacked by leaving a trail of outdated technology behind you.</p>



<h3>Supply Chain Attacks</h3>



<p>Supply chain attacks are all the rage these days.&nbsp; Consider the supply chain of your code dependency management system.&nbsp; Are you routinely scanning it for CVEs?&nbsp; Are you doing any kind of dynamic automated or manual testing of the code looking for vulnerabilities?&nbsp; Are you sure you can trust the source of your code dependencies?</p>



<p>DevOps code can be commonly overlooked in a supply chain attack scenario.&nbsp; Maybe you are writing a console tool to help make your life a little bit easier.&nbsp; You go ahead and pull in a few libraries from the internet to help aid in the creation of that tool like colored output.&nbsp; You also want to be really good and write automated tests as a best practice and you need help generating some data for those tests.&nbsp; Without a persistent review of code dependencies, the OSS developer/contributor of one of the dependencies that you are utilizing is tired of their <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/dev-corrupts-npm-libs-colors-and-faker-breaking-thousands-of-apps/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">work being used for free without any recognition or compensation</a> and deliberately destroys the project.&nbsp; There are also less directly malicious scenarios where the developer of a <a href="https://blog.sonatype.com/npm-project-used-by-millions-hijacked-in-supply-chain-attack" target="_blank" rel="noopener">popular package gets targeted and code is unknowingly slipped into their project</a>.</p>



<p>The lesson is this: assume that attack vectors are everywhere and ensure that you are scanning everything you can get your hands on for CVEs.&nbsp; The industry has a good focus on this now, and the question is not IF you will get compromised, but when.&nbsp; Keep yourself safe by being proactive.</p>


<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
</p>



<h2>What Languages do I Use Most Often?</h2>



<p>When I am sitting down to take care of simple tasks or to write scripts for a problem I am trying to solve; I am most often looking at a language that can help me do data manipulation, develop operational automation, build infrastructure as code, or build a deployment pipeline for my projects.</p>



<h3>What do I use for Data Manipulation?</h3>



<p>For me, this is generally a quick and dirty task that i am not going to be releasing to production in any form. This website does a bunch of different data manipulation tasks under the covers as part of its pipeline. I will generally choose PHP (not on this list, but it is a majority of my pure software dev background) or Javascript.</p>



<p>Javascript is a fairly common language utilized in a multitude of DevOps environments that i would be able to quickly onboard someone with if needed. All of the tasks i am doing here are also fairly simple tasks in need of a simple language. I am not trying to do big data analytics, just mutate some links, move around some HTML, and soon some automated testing.</p>



<h3>What do I use for Infrastructure Management (or Infrastructure as Code)?</h3>



<p>I have a Home Lab where the WYSIWG part of this website is hosted. I push all of my changes there as part of a continuous integration pipeline through Ansible. This means that I am living in the Python space.</p>



<p>It could be easy to argue that i am not really using Python here. I am for sure not a full fledged Python programmer, but I have dug through a fair bit of the source code behind Kubespray to understand the real intentions of what it is trying to accomplish. This has also helped me utilize Ansible as a swiss army knife for any of my infrastructure management needs.</p>



<h3>What do I use for Deployment Pipelines?</h3>



<p>I currently utilize a mixture of Javascript and GitHub Actions and GitOps to build deployment pipelines. There are a variety of other languages i could be using, but these work well for me. As stated earlier, i will shift all of my data round with Javascript. From there, GitHub actions will run any builds that i need with any triggered deploys.</p>



<p>If the end result needs to go on the internet, i dont really need to deal with a fully weight object oriented programming language, or linux servers/linux systems, relational databases, business intelligence or anything like that. It makes more sense for GitOps style triggers to be in place to automagically move my code from repo to the internet without manual intervention.</p>



<h2>Is there a good General Purpose Programming Language?</h2>



<p>I think you need to first ask, what is most native to my environment. If Node.JS is not installed on every single one of your servers, but you want to write all your scripts in Javascript, that is going to be tough.</p>



<p>If you are looking for a one-size fits all answer, then you are not going to find one. I would keep your mind open, try out new things, and see what fits the situation you are in.</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>As I stated at the beginning of this article, this is by no means a definitive list. I do not believe there is an answer to the question &#8220;which is the right programming languages to pick up for DevOps&#8221;.&nbsp; This is a list of some of the tools that I utilized to build effective DevOps workflows and to enable the flow of delivery.&nbsp; I utilize these tools at my job along with utilizing these tools in my homelab.&nbsp; I believe that everyone could use a little bit of software development in their life.&nbsp; Python, Javascript, Golang, or Ruby are really great places to start with languages because of their utility, communities, and ties to DevOps and DevOps tooling.</p>



<p>There are absolutely other programming languages that are not on this list. If you feel like I have left anything out that is very relevant to DevOps technologies and system administration, or are just common languages that are being utilized frequently, don&#8217;t hesitate to contact me and I can update the list.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What are the two major benefits of DevOps?</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/major-benefits-of-devops/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greer Shepherd]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 21:16:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[delivery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=488</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The first benefit of DevOps is that it enables organizations to release software faster, more reliably, and with higher quality. By breaking down the barriers between development and operations, DevOps allows teams to work together more effectively and efficiently. This&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The first benefit of <a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="Demystifying the DevOps Methodology and How You Can Leverage it for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> is that it enables organizations to release software faster, more reliably, and with higher quality. By breaking down the barriers between development and operations, DevOps allows teams to work together more effectively and efficiently. This helps companies get new features and updates into the hands of their customers more quickly.</p>



<p>The second benefit of DevOps is that it helps organizations become more agile. By automating the deployment process, DevOps makes it possible for companies to respond quickly to changes in customer demand or market conditions. This allows businesses to be more competitive and stay ahead of the curve.</p>



<p>Let&#8217;s take a look at each of these benefits in detail!</p>


<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
</p>



<h2>Benefit #1: Deliver technology faster and at higher quality</h2>



<p>When your customers want more complex software products and expect you to deliver for them more quickly, the ways in which your company revolutionizes its product and service offerings will require a complete revamp. Collaboration and productivity enhancements brought about by DevOps are a big assist in meeting the innovation objectives of businesses.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The DevOps method of app development provides a company with a number of benefits, but the following five are the most important for any business that wishes to be inventive, available, and scalable. The following are those in question:</p>



<h3>Accelerate Time To Market</h3>



<p>DevOps reduces the amount of time it takes to bring a product to market, which in turn boosts business revenue. As a result of bringing together the IT and development teams to collaborate, the amount of time required to construct, test, and launch services or features is cut significantly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The DevOps strategy enables businesses to rapidly introduce new features, rapidly improve already existing ones, and rapidly make these new or improved features available to users.</p>



<h3>Changing in Response to the Industry and Competition</h3>



<p>You have to consistently offer high-quality items if you want to succeed in an industry that is very competitive. Even if you had a fantastic idea for a business and had already started building it, that wouldn&#8217;t help you capture market share. You are in need of an improved strategy as well as a process, both of which are provided by DevOps.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The delivery of new code is made both speedy and dependable thanks to DevOps. In addition, it allows teams to construct a scalable and robust application environment while still providing users with an outstanding experience. This approach not only helps acquire the market but also thrives in a competitive market by boosting the user base and income. In other words, it is a win-win situation.</p>



<h3>Keeping the System Reliable While Preserving Its Stability</h3>



<p>Continuous testing or automated testing is something that DevOps encourages. Testing that is automated enables engineers to provide test results that are more accurate, offer fast feedback on the build, and monitor the completion of all operations. When the team searches for results, the DevOps methodology provides time savings by accelerating the availability and the entire body of work related to results in analysis on each CI/CT cycle.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This helps the team get results more quickly. The team is able to simply manage the system&#8217;s stability and dependability while also guaranteeing that the software products have excellent performance and availability.</p>



<h3>Bringing Down The Average Time To Recovery</h3>



<p>The bigger the financial effect that a corporation will have to deal with, the longer the MTTR will be. MTTR, which stands for &#8220;mean time to recovery,&#8221; is a problem that can be solved via DevOps. When a service experiences an outage, having DevOps in place may help speed up the process of repair, reaction, and recovery.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It provides assistance for monitoring mission-critical systems, which enables users to gain real-time insights on decreased performance as well as entire outages caused by events and failures. The methodology of DevOps not only makes it easier to collect precise information but also makes the incident-management system more automated. In this method, it is feasible to swiftly address the issue, which will ultimately result in a reduced MTTR.</p>



<h3>Capabilities for Providing a Better Experience to Customers</h3>



<p>DevOps approaches also place an emphasis on the one-of-a-kind characteristics of software designed for the user experience. The development of both the quality of the software and the customer experience may be sped up with the use of DevOps.&nbsp;</p>



<p>DevOps specialists monitor the customer&#8217;s point of view, plan sprints in accordance with that perspective, and test the product with the customer&#8217;s objective in mind. The team not only rapidly develops new features but also defines and enhances the whole customer journey for omnichannel.</p>


<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
</p>



<h2>Benefit #2: React to changing market conditions more quickly</h2>



<p>These days, businesses undergo digital transformations by adopting innovative technology and methods. Keeping up with the digital economy is a top priority, and as a result, they are putting in extra effort to improve in all areas.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They need to improve their financial performance, product quality, product speed to market, and overall company adaptability. Maintaining competitive flexibility requires effective communication, collaboration, and bug-free code, all of which may be attained through the use of Agile and DevOps processes.</p>



<h3>Create a Culture-Oriented Structure</h3>



<p>It is common practice for an organization&#8217;s culture and structure to become one and the same. Teams need to adjust their mindset in order to use DevOps successfully. To put it simply, DevOps is a rearrangement of the teams and the way they work together and communicate.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Only when individuals work well together as a team can organizations make effective use of the available resources and technology. Both the development and operations teams need each other&#8217;s support. Being able to think critically sets humans apart from machines.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Therefore, agile culture and the way humans naturally think are incompatible with the sequential waterfall paradigm. There is an urgent need to proactively address these difficulties, and the classic waterfall approach can do just that. It can also impart the benefits of the DevOps paradigm and harmonize the organizational structure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This will boost overall collaboration and adaptability and guarantee that the company&#8217;s culture and the culture of its employees are properly melded. By focusing on the whole value chain of software delivery, DevOps is the logical next step after Agile.</p>



<h3>Streamline Techniques, Procedures, and Policies</h3>



<p>Collaboration across the organization&#8217;s development, testing, infrastructure, and IT teams is essential. Thus, the organization&#8217;s rules, procedures, and processes should reflect this. DevOps needs to reevaluate its workflow, roles, responsibilities, and methodologies if it is to attain genuine agility.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other words, they need to have a mentality that is consistent with the agile culture, which centers on producing incremental results and accommodating change. It&#8217;s not as simple as just adding weekly scrums on top of everything else, so be prepared for some complexity.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Development and operations must collaborate with automation technologies and fully integrated processes to operate in a succession of brief efforts and genuinely execute production-ready code that can actually be delivered to clients.</p>



<h3>Streamline Rapid Growth with Minimal Discomfort</h3>



<p>Agility in DevOps is achieved by bringing together the principles of rapid development, high throughput, and careful scheduling to improve dependability and minimize disturbance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To take advantage of Agile&#8217;s rapid iteration cycles without sacrificing quality, the DevOps model may be used to zero in on the best approach and set you up with the best agile testing tools. It helps businesses find their footing so they can effectively and efficiently adapt to changing market conditions and capitalize on emerging possibilities.</p>



<h3>Remove Organizational Barriers</h3>



<p>Organizational agility may be improved by closing the communication and collaboration gaps across departments like operations, development, and testing. By enabling continuous development, testing, and deployment with a reliable toolchain, agility may be accomplished.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There is a tight coupling between the teams, instruments, and procedures in this method. The success of the DevOps model relies on effective communication and cooperation between several functional teams, which guarantees zero barriers across multiple agile teams supported by the proper collaboration technologies.</p>



<h3>Maintain Constant Monitoring</h3>



<p>For DevOps to be effective and for a plan to be developed, feedback is essential. Having fast and accurate input is crucial to the success of a DevOps approach. Each deployment should record the basic metrics of duration, expense, and quality. Over time, this information may be examined to determine DevOps&#8217;s efficiency and adaptability and to pinpoint problem spots.</p>



<p>Culture-based indicators like team cohesion, the average time to resolve conflicts, sense of pride and ownership, and so on can be challenging to quantify. When determining the speed and efficiency of DevOps, however, these cultural criteria are crucial.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Organizational culture, methods, mentality, and toolchain should be streamlined in order to expand the DevOps model and keep it agile and relevant for providing excellent deliveries. For this reason, it is essential to employ experienced teams that can work together to concentrate on constant development and evaluation.</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>By focusing on the whole value chain of software delivery, DevOps is the logical next step after Agile. Additionally, the DevOps model helps businesses find their footing so they can effectively and efficiently adapt to changing market conditions and capitalize on emerging possibilities.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Do DevOps engineers need a coding background?</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/do-devops-engineers-need-a-coding-background/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 21:55:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=326</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The primary skill sets that&#160;DevOps engineers need are either in the system administration or software development space. Those 2 foundational skill sets will help any team build some cool solutions to complex problems. There are fringe cases where the skillset&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The primary skill sets that&nbsp;<a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="Demystifying the DevOps Methodology and How You Can Leverage it for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> engineers need are either in the system administration or software development space. Those 2 foundational skill sets will help any team build some cool solutions to complex problems.</p>



<p>There are fringe cases where the skillset matures outside of those two primary skill sets. Whichever skillset is lacking when making the transition from traditional delivery patterns over to a more DevOps-focused delivery pattern will need to be picked up to ensure that the team has a complete understanding of the technology stack.</p>



<p>A system administrator will not need to become a full software developer, and a software developer will not need to become a veteran system administrator. Bringing the best of these two practices together is what makes for a successful DevOps engineer.</p>


<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
</p>



<h2>Don&#8217;t let Role Separation Scare you Off!</h2>



<p>First, let&#8217;s dive into role separation. I am a firm believer in specialization in job functions. Someone who is a jack of all trades is also generally not a master at any of them.</p>



<p>Individuals on the DevOps team should not be looking to be a master at every part of their delivery pipeline but they should be in a position where they are picking up adjacent skills to help back up their team members when needed.</p>



<p>A software developer who is familiar with one or more programming languages does not need to be intimately familiar with every intricate detail of a backup solution but should know how to retrieve and restore backups when necessary.</p>



<p>A system administrator does not need to dive deeply into SQL query optimization, but knowing how to write and retrieve data from the database is a useful skill to help support the team.</p>



<p>I firmly believe that everyone should pick up at least one programming language that they can become dangerous with. Utilizing code to quickly evaluate, split, transform, or compare lists is a great place to start off since every company has data that needs something done with it. From there, you can choose to grow your skills organically or strategically depending on your affinity for writing code.</p>



<h2>Why do System Administrators Need a Coding Background?</h2>



<p>As system administrators make the transition from the GUI to doing DevOps, they will be faced with many challenges where a coding background can really help out.</p>



<p>DevOps is all about automating the flow of delivery through resilient pipelines to increase quality. To do this, most of your work is going to be through scripts or tools like&nbsp;<a href="https://www.chef.io/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="8" title="Chef">Chef</a>, Terraform, <a href="https://puppet.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="9" title="Puppet">Puppet</a>, CloudFormation, etc. Composing individual scripts for individual tasks is a good place to start, but will quickly become overwhelming if you are not embracing a more generated approach.</p>



<p>Now, all teams are going to be set up a bit differently, but a common thread across all of them will be the scale of technology becoming overwhelming at some point. One day you may be looking at fifteen servers/services and the next day your product explodes in popularity and you are dealing with thousands of servers/services. Take a step back and ask yourself how you can use business logic to generate your infrastructure, monitoring, configurations, backups solutions, etc. This approach will make something that feels unmanageable and makes it manageable again.</p>



<h2>Why do Operations Teams Need a Coding Background?</h2>



<p>Let&#8217;s say you are working in a hybrid multi-tenant environment that is changing at a rapid pace. Let&#8217;s also say that you are saddled with several different operating systems or services in this environment. Now let&#8217;s say you are a small team of only a few people with operations tasks piling up by the hour and you are unable to complete them due to the sheer volume of incoming work.</p>



<p>Sounds pretty standard right? I believe there are a series of DevOps tools that can help. Beyond that, I believe that scripting languages along with some coding knowledge can greatly increase your efficiency.</p>



<p>In a hybrid environment, you are going to need to really lean on your technical skills to ensure that the right machines or services in the right place are being maintained. On top of that, you are going to need a pretty accurate inventory of information to work from in order to stay efficient. Deploying a scripting language to utilize cloud console tools may be a quick way to pull together something like a bash alias file for quick environment access.</p>



<p>When faced with the challenge of scripting against any specific operating system, one could keep a series of scripts handy on their computer to run repetitive tasks. Alternatively, they could utilize a tool like <a href="https://www.ansible.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="7" title="Ansible">Ansible</a> and ensure not only is their automation targetable but also ensure that it is composed in a reusable way as well. This could all be contributed to by a DevOps team in a source code management system like <a href="https://www.github.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="6" title="Github" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">GitHub</a> ensuring it is accessible by everyone on the team.</p>



<p>The key to operations teams is to keep work fast and efficient. Spending some time orchestrating complex events into the software development life cycle is a great way to ensure that operations becomes everyone&#8217;s responsibility to contribute to.</p>



<h2>Why do Quality Assurance Teams Need a Coding Background?</h2>



<p>Coding skills are becoming more and more relevant to quality assurance teams. I believe that most quality engineering tools focus too much on being able to point and click your way to success.</p>



<p>By bringing automated testing into your ecosystem, and integrating it directly into your source code management tools, a qa engineer will be able to promote ensuring quality is the responsibility of everyone on the team. People will use what is accessible to them as long as it has a very low barrier to entry.</p>



<p>Coding knowledge is also very helpful in this space. We have all, at one point or another, filed a bug with a development team but since our programming skills were not up to snuff, we were unable to provide any valuable or additional context to the bug. By being able to utilize development tools to dive into the code and return bug tickets with actionable insight, the DevOps team will be able to move much more quickly to resolution.</p>



<p>Another area that I have seen quality teams need some assistance with is around tracking code versions after deploying a new version of their application. By tying your test tracking systems together with a code repository tag and running preflight validation checks on the deployed code versions to ensure they are in sync, you can ensure you are not wasting cycles trying to get the next critical release out the door.</p>



<h2>Why does Software Development Need a Coding Background?</h2>



<p>Now, this is a bit of an unfair section because I believe that the software development side of DevOps does need a coding background. How are you going to do software development without that?</p>



<p>In all seriousness, I believe the question “Do DevOps engineers need a coding background?” can be extended into the Ops and Infrastructure space pretty easily. I believe that developers looking to wear the moniker of &#8220;DevOps engineer&#8221; should be looking to extend coding skills into spaces they are less familiar with.</p>



<p>Software developers should be familiar with the basic fundamentals of a data center or cloud depending on where your solution(s) is/are hosted. If you are in a data center, become familiar with fault domains, SANs, LUNs, monitoring, or anything that may impact the stability or performance of your application. In the cloud, become familiar with the cloud&#8217;s elastic nature of volumes, instances, and services.</p>



<p>Along with the familiarity with computing platforms, it will be advantageous to also familiarize yourself with DevOps tools that enhance solution delivery and system configuration.</p>



<p>Solution delivery and delivery pipelines are essential to a good DevOps background. In my experience, most developers are really good at utilizing their ecosystems to compile a binary or build out a package.</p>



<p>Aside from SFTPing that package out to a server and bouncing a service the idea of automated blue/green solution delivery flow with configuration management, rollbacks, database updates, monitoring changes, etc. is not the norm.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>You SFTPers out there know who you are, don&#8217;t try to deny it.</p></blockquote>



<p>Developers should be looking for ways to extend their idealized software development process into the infrastructure, operations, and quality assurance spaces. One of the greatest challenges I see from Operations teams or Infrastructure teams is their ability to produce a consistent and reliable build and deploy pipeline that provides good actionable feedback. Those features are consistently available in any sort of software development life cycle.</p>



<h2>Why is a Coding Background Good For Everyone!</h2>



<p>The primary driver behind configuration management is trying to hit the gold standard of immutable infrastructure. While application code is being perpetually updated and changed, servers should be treated like cattle instead of pets. We should be able to easily destroy and fully rebuild a server and deploy the newest version of the application on top of it. This helps keep things clean and up to date.</p>



<p>Taking time to learn software development, or any technical skills on a technology team helps drive better communication and collaboration skills. As the team starts to move into continuous integration and continuous delivery model as part of their agile methodology adoption, DevOps teams will need to find new ways to effectively share information. By putting development front and center, and I don&#8217;t mean just application code here, there is a set of basic knowledge baselines that everyone can agree to communicate under.</p>



<p>Organizations can also find some common ground to reduce extraneous costs on their products as well. Focusing on a smaller set of software development languages, and configuration management tools, and reducing other such technological diversity; you can build an economy of scale around your skilled workforce that has focused on delivering value to the market more quickly. This is especially true when adopting DevOps by merging development and operations teams together. This first move will generally expose a lot of technological waste.</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>Do DevOps engineers need a coding background? My perspective is, that it wouldn&#8217;t hurt. Diving into software development patterns and extending them into the DevOps delivery space allows for greater consistency, along with the ability to scale to meet demand much more quickly without feeling overwhelmed. I don&#8217;t think that software developers need to become the best systems administrators ever created. I don&#8217;t think that systems administrators need to become the greatest software developers ever created. I do think that everyone in technology could benefit from a bit of exposure to spaces outside of their primary responsibilities because it lends itself well to increasing quality and flexibility while delivering solutions.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
