<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>A DevOps Blog</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.valewood.org/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.valewood.org/</link>
	<description>Occasionally a developer makes an Ops!</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 22:48:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.valewood.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/A-DevOoops-1-e1660773390219.png</url>
	<title>A DevOps Blog</title>
	<link>https://www.valewood.org/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>7 Tips for Landing a DevOps Position Without a Degree</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/devops-without-education/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greer Shepherd]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 21:28:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1645</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[DevOps is hot right now. The demand for professionals with the skills to bridge the gap between software development and information technology operations is growing significantly. It’s not difficult to understand why. DevOps is a methodology that optimizes processes, removes&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> is hot right now. The demand for professionals with the skills to bridge the gap between software development and information technology operations is growing significantly.</p>



<p>It’s not difficult to understand why. DevOps is a methodology that optimizes processes, removes barriers, and improves collaboration between software developers and information technology (IT) operations teams. Because of its benefits, it’s becoming an increasingly attractive option for IT professionals who want to stand out from the crowd.</p>



<p>In this blog post, you will learn about the types of roles available in DevOps, how you can land your first DevOps job, and what you need to succeed in your new role as a DevOps engineer or specialist.</p>



<h2>What Is DevOps?</h2>



<p>DevOps is short for &#8220;software development operations.&#8221; It describes a set of best practices related to transforming the relationship between software developers and information technology (IT) operations personnel.</p>



<p>DevOps aims to improve collaboration, increase efficiency, and reduce waste. This organizational transformation is commonly referred to as cultural transformation.</p>



<p>Achieving cultural transformation requires employees in both departments to change their perspectives and expectations of each other. This is why DevOps is often seen as an ongoing journey, not a destination. DevOps is often associated with agile software development methodologies, such as Kanban, Scrum, and others.</p>



<h2>Types of Jobs in DevOps</h2>



<p>DevOps is a methodology that requires several different disciplines to fully adopt and become proficient in. Let&#8217;s look at a few different roles in DevOps to see how the market is segmenting labor in this space.</p>



<ul>
<li>Software Engineer &#8211; Software engineers are responsible for building software products and services against a set of requirements.</li>



<li>Operations Engineer &#8211; Responsible for managing the lifecycle of technology ensuring the stability and reliability of systems.</li>



<li>Quality Assurance &#8211; Responsible for validating the quality of software being developed through automated testing. Also responsible for making testing available to an entire devops team.</li>



<li>DevOps Engineer &#8211; Let’s start with the basics. If you’re looking to work as a DevOps engineer, you’ll need to be able to understand and work with code, have an excellent knowledge of server environments, and be able to think on the fly and find solutions to new problems.</li>



<li>DevOps Engineer Manager &#8211; In this capacity, you’ll need to be able to work with both technical and non-technical staff. You’ll be responsible for ensuring that the team is working effectively and efficiently. So, it goes without saying that you’ll need strong communication skills.</li>



<li>DevOps Architect &#8211; A DevOps architect is responsible for designing and implementing the organization’s software delivery system. This is often a challenging role that requires a great deal of experience, knowledge and a strong understanding of organizational needs.</li>



<li>DevOps Manager &#8211; As a DevOps manager, you’ll be responsible for overseeing the entire DevOps process, including hiring, training, and managing staff. You’ll need to be able to understand and communicate the needs of multiple stakeholders. You’ll also need to be able to manage the entire lifecycle of products, from development to delivery and ongoing maintenance.</li>
</ul>



<p>As you can see, normal everyday engineering roles can join a DevOps team. Don&#8217;t immediately exclude yourself because you have not been a DevOps engineer in the past. Most of us have started out in software engineering or system operations roles anyway.</p>



<h2>Tips for Landing a DevOps Job Without a Degree</h2>



<p>In today’s job market, it is not enough to just have a good education and experience from your previous job. You must also know how to write a resume that highlights your skills and experience in a way that shows you as the best candidate for the job.</p>



<p>This can be done by taking some time to research and learn about the particular industry you are interested in working in, as well as the company and the specific role you want to apply for.</p>



<p>When you have this information in hand, you can then create a resume that places your skills, experience, and values at the top of the list. This will make it easy for hiring managers to see what makes you different than other candidates and more likely to be hired.</p>



<p>With these things in mind, it is important to keep your resume updated as new jobs become available. You should also stay on top of employment trends so that you are ready when opportunities arise. By doing this, you will increase your chances of landing an interview and ultimately getting hired.</p>



<p>Here are a few additional steps you can take to increase your odds of landing a DevOps Engineering position:</p>



<ol>
<li>Research the role you want &#8211; Blindly showing up to a job interview for a DevOps position is not going to go well. Take some time to learn and understand the DevOps methodology and what it is trying to accomplish. Any of the technical skills needed can be acquired on the job so do let that be a limiting factor.</li>



<li>Network &#8211; The single best way to land a job in DevOps without a degree is to network, network, network. It’s one of the most effective ways to find out about new opportunities, learn about the industry, and connect with people who can help you advance your career.</li>



<li>Identify Your Skills &#8211; Before you can network effectively, you need to know what your skills are. Doing this will help you identify which organizations are best for you, as well as identify skill gaps. Furthermore, it will help you understand how to position yourself as the best candidate for a given role.</li>



<li>Join a DevOps Community &#8211; DevOps communities, like meetup groups and online forums, are excellent ways to find out about new opportunities and connect with people who can help you advance your career.</li>



<li>Create an Online Portfolio &#8211; Online portfolios can be incredibly powerful tools for job seekers without a degree. You should include examples of your work and information about your projects and roles.</li>



<li>Phone a Friend &#8211; Look through Linkedin, Facebook, Twitter, or other free resources for peers who are already working in the DevOps space to find out what they think is important and work towards developing similar skills.</li>



<li>Network with Employers &#8211; When you’re networking with employers, don’t sell yourself short. Be sure to highlight your skills, background, and experience.</li>
</ol>



<h2>3 Steps to Landing Any Job You Want</h2>



<p>If you’re looking to find a job, landing any kind of position is a big deal. You can start by proactively searching for the positions you want, or by going through a recruiter or headhunter if they have a specific role you’re interested in.</p>



<p>When you land a new job, you have to be prepared for all kinds of situations. You might have to move across the country if the company has an office there, and you may also have to learn new skills or take on new responsibilities.</p>



<p>Making yourself ready for these situations can help you land any kind of job. For example, you could build up your résumé and online presence by completing online courses or volunteering at local organizations. This will show that you are ready for a new position and will also make it easier to find work once you are ready.</p>



<p>Another option is to join professional organizations like Toastmasters or other networking groups where you can meet people who can help you land a new job. Just remember: Landing any kind of job takes time, so be prepared by taking steps now that will make it easier in the future!</p>



<ul>
<li>Define What You Want &#8211; Before you embark on your job search, you need to make an honest assessment of what you want. Do you want a full-time position, or will a contract position work for you? How many hours do you want to work per week? What is your salary range? These are just a few of the questions you’ll need to answer.</li>



<li>Identify Your Strengths &#8211; Once you’ve identified what you want, you need to assess what you have to offer. What are your strengths? What are your weaknesses? This will help you identify which employers will be best for you.</li>



<li>Write a Great Resume &#8211; Once you’ve assessed your skills and talents, you need to translate them into action for your resume. This is your first opportunity to impress a prospective employer.</li>
</ul>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>If you want a job in DevOps, you’ll need to be prepared to show what you have to offer and sell yourself to prospective employers. Remember, though, that there are many different types of jobs in DevOps.</p>



<p>So, before you start your search, it’s important to understand what you are looking for and how to stand out in a competitive hiring landscape. If you want a job in DevOps, you’ll need to be prepared to show what you have to offer and sell yourself to prospective employers.</p>



<p>Remember, though, that there are many different types of jobs in DevOps: DevOps engineer, architect, engineer manager, and manager. Target what you want to be doing, and start applying. You are probably more qualified than you initially thought!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why You Need to Build A Culture of Trust and Respect in DevOps</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/devops-trust/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 22:45:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops trust]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1657</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Trust and respect are essential ingredients in any healthy working environment. When trust and respect are present, team members feel safe to give their best, collaborate openly, and challenge one another constructively. When trust and respect are absent, team members&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Trust and respect are essential ingredients in any healthy working environment. When trust and respect are present, team members feel safe to give their best, collaborate openly, and challenge one another constructively.</p>



<p>When trust and respect are absent, team members feel insecure about their performance, withhold ideas for fear of judgement or worry about repercussions if they speak up.</p>



<p>There is an inherent risk in bringing together people from different backgrounds with different skill sets. And in the context of <a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a>, you’re also putting together people who likely have very different roles within your organization as well. The potential for discord is high.</p>



<p>So how do you create a culture of trust and respect when working with so many new and different people? Here’s why you need to build a culture of trust and respect in your DevOps initiative.</p>



<h2>It’s the Foundation for Good Communication</h2>



<p>Communication is the foundation for everything in DevOps. You have to be able to openly share what’s working, what isn’t, and why without judgement, without fear of repercussions, and without ego getting in the way.</p>



<p>What happens when, in a meeting, someone says they aren’t getting the information they need from a team member? Or that they feel rushed to get their job done? Or that they aren’t seeing the value in the continuous integration process?</p>



<p>Without a culture of trust and respect, communication will be strained. Team members will be hesitant to speak up, and afraid of judgement. They’ll feel anxious like they don’t have permission to be honest with the team.</p>



<p>And if they don’t feel safe speaking up, the communication breaks down, and the DevOps initiative will suffer as a result.</p>



<h2>It Builds Confidence for Everyone</h2>



<p>One of the biggest challenges in DevOps is building trust between different people, and different parts of the organization. But if you lack the confidence to speak up, you’ll never be able to build that trust missing out on the opportunity to learn from your colleagues and grow yourself as a result.</p>



<p>In a culture where trust and respect are absent, people are less likely to share their ideas, and more likely to either shut down and not try at all, speak up in ways that create discord, and don’t encourage others to respond.</p>



<p>You need to feel confident to share your ideas, challenge others, and learn from both your successes and your mistakes. Without trust and respect, you won’t feel confident enough to do any of these things, and again, the DevOps initiative will suffer as a result.</p>



<h2>It Creates a Safe Environment For Learning</h2>



<p>A healthy DevOps culture needs to create a safe environment for learning. This means not only being transparent about what’s working and what isn’t, but also being open to feedback without fear of judgement.</p>



<p>This is the best way to identify pain points and areas where improvement is needed. When team members feel safe to share their feedback, they can do so in a way that doesn’t create any sense of judgement, but rather, encourages the team to look at the information objectively and decide how to act on it.</p>



<p>But when a team is operating in a culture where trust and respect aren’t present, this kind of feedback is very tricky to navigate. Because team members are likely to feel anxious about sharing their true feelings and experiences, and will likely speak up in ways that are designed to minimise judgement. This can lead to misunderstood feedback, and squashing the open and objective dialogue that is needed for improvement.</p>



<h2>DevOps is About People and Culture</h2>



<p>All of the above leads us to one important conclusion: building a healthy DevOps culture is about people and trust. Building trust and respect is never a one-time thing, and it requires a sustained effort from all members of the team, regardless of their backgrounds.</p>



<p>When you see a team member struggling to find their footing, or growing frustrated at their role, you have to be willing to lend a helping hand. And to do this, you must first be aware of your own behaviour and how you’re modelling the behaviour you want to see.</p>



<p>You must be willing to confront your own behaviours that are likely to be creating a culture that is lacking in trust and respect. And you must be willing to take ownership of your own feelings and be open about how they are impacting your work and the team as a whole.</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>DevOps is all about collaboration, communication and cooperation. When everyone on the team trusts and respects each other, they are much more likely to collaborate effectively. This can only happen when everyone feels safe to give their opinion and be open about their needs. Building a culture of trust and respect will take time and effort. However, it is well worth the effort as it will lead to better communication, a healthier team, and ultimately better results for your organization.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How are Agile and DevOps Interrelated?</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/devops-and-agile/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 20:49:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[delivery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops and agile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1264</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[DevOps (an abbreviation of developer operations) is the marriage between software development and IT operation. It’s a term used to describe practices and technologies aimed at bringing together software engineers and IT professionals to produce software more efficiently. In this&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> (an abbreviation of developer operations) is the marriage between software development and IT operation. It’s a term used to describe practices and technologies aimed at bringing together software engineers and IT professionals to produce software more efficiently.</p>



<p>In this blog post, we’ll cover the main principles of DevOps and its interrelation with Agile. It can be challenging for teams that are new to both concepts at the same time, but they really make sense when taken in their entirety. In other words, by following these steps, you’ll be able to create an effective DevOps culture within your organization.</p>



<p>So, how do agile and DevOps interrelate?</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>What is DevOps?</h2>



<p>DevOps is a transformation aimed at integrating the software development and operations teams from a business perspective. It’s a combination of techniques found in Lean and Agile methodologies, and it’s used to transform the way organizations produce software.</p>



<p>DevOps merges the disciplines of development and operations to create a more efficient process that successfully addresses the challenges faced by businesses today. DevOps is an umbrella term that describes a set of processes aimed at bridging the gap between software development and IT operations.</p>



<p>I think this is the first key to explaining how agile and DevOps interrelate. In a more traditional approach, there are generally a series of handoffs between different responsibilities in an organization. When trying to understand how agile and DevOps work together, start by visualizing a world where handoffs do not happen anymore. This will immediately produce savings over the life cycle of your products.</p>



<p>Agile teams are also unique in their own right when compared to a more traditional organizational structure. An agile team is going to consistently be reviewing their development processes for areas of improvement. This is going to allow for meaningful growth and promote a model focused on continuous integration and continuous delivery.</p>



<h2>What Makes DevOps Different from Other Methodologies?</h2>



<p>DevOps integrates the development and operations teams into a single functional delivery team. From a business perspective, it focuses on creating product delivery cycles that solve real problems instead of just churning out code for the sake of producing code.</p>



<p>By combining these disciplines developers can spend less time dealing with the complexities of big bang releases and more time creating new rapidly developed incremental features. This is because the process is automated.</p>



<p>This helps organizations achieve high software quality, fast delivery, and easier adaptation to the market. To end-users, DevOps looks like this: When a team of developers wants to create a new feature, they can rapidly plan, prototype, adjust, and release that feature to start realizing the value of that work.</p>



<p>Agile development methodologies are usually found with any functional DevOps team. When looking at a more traditional project management methodology like Waterfall, anyone trying to implement DevOps will generally stop short at automating infrastructure as code. A project utilizing the Agile DevOps methodology will take that several steps further.</p>



<p>An Agile DevOps team will focus on automating the entire process. Continuous integration will be utilized as a cornerstone to build a robust framework to test and deploy their software. The end goal is to transition into a model of continuous delivery to enable many releases to production in a single day.</p>



<p>Day 2 operations will be integrated into their technology pipelines as well. Tools and automation will be built to take care of more routine tasks such as certificate renewals or auto-remediation. Because DevOps pipelines are test-driven, future unexpected changes are also quickly identified and fixed much more easily.</p>



<h2>What Makes a More Traditional SDLC Risky?</h2>



<p>When working in a more traditional software methodology software moves down an assembly line with bigger changes leading to larger risk.</p>



<p>New features are approved and then tested, followed by regression, and finally deployed to production. This is the most traditional way to work with code. However, it is not always the most efficient way to work with code.</p>



<p>Changes to the code base should be approached from the perspective of the risk involved with any change. When working with big changes in the code base, it is important to look at the big picture of the software. If you are only focused on one aspect of the software, even though it might be the most crucial aspect, you risk overlooking something else that is just as important.</p>



<p>Big-picture thinking is achieved by working with the whole software. If you are building a new feature, you need to start with a new branch of the code base. Without testing the new code, you risk breaking something else in the software. Once you are sure there are no errors in the new code, you can start the testing process. After you are certain the new code has no bugs, you can release it to your production environment.</p>



<p>When the process relies on larger changes, with more complex processes, and more opinions about quality in every decision being made down the assembly line there is a higher likelihood that project timelines will slip or never be delivered at all.</p>



<h2>The Importance of Collaboration in DevOps</h2>



<p>DevOps is the marriage between software development and IT operations. It’s a term used to describe practices and technologies aimed at bringing together software engineers and IT professionals to produce software more efficiently.</p>



<p>In this marriage, there must be a collaboration between the teams involved. This collaboration allows for a better understanding of each other’s roles, and for the shared goal of creating better software with minimal time and effort.</p>



<p>DevOps is key to transforming the operations side of an organization and allowing everyone involved to create high-quality, reliable software. And collaboration between the teams is what allows for this.</p>



<h2>Establishing a Culture of Collaboration for Success in DevOps</h2>



<p>Before you can start implementing DevOps in your organization, you need to establish a culture of collaboration between the teams involved. DevOps is a marriage between teams, and successful marriages are built on communication and a mutual understanding of what both parties bring to the table.</p>



<p>To create this culture, you’ll want to start by determining which members of your organization are involved in the transformation. You can do this by identifying the individuals who are responsible for bringing the different teams together (such as product managers, architects, developers, and operations staff).</p>



<p>You can also do a deeper dive into how the teams interact with each other. Ask yourself:</p>



<ul><li>What information does each team need from the other?</li><li>What do they do with that information?</li><li>What are their roles and responsibilities?</li></ul>



<p>This will help you determine where the gaps are between the teams and what needs to change.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>What is Agile?</h2>



<p>Agile has been used in the software development community for a long time, but DevOps has brought it to the forefront.</p>



<p>Agile is a collection of methodologies based on rapid, evolutionary development. It’s about understanding your business needs and developing products and services to meet them.</p>



<p>This type of development is often referred to as evolutionary development, and it’s meant to be a continuous process. This means that in order to adjust to changes in your business, you’ll need to adjust your processes accordingly.</p>



<p>Evolutionary development has many advantages over traditional methods of development, such as waterfall. Waterfall is a method that focuses on a single target release date, and it’s often used in traditional methodologies.</p>



<h2>The Importance of Agility in Digital Development</h2>



<p>Agile development emphasizes the need for constant communication and collaboration between the teams responsible for product development. This communication is key to the success of the transformation, and it’s achieved by bringing together architects, product managers, developers, and operations staff.</p>



<p>By bringing everyone together, you’ll be able to understand their roles and responsibilities and make adjustments as necessary. And, most importantly, you’ll be able to communicate better and collaborate.</p>



<p>By developing products and services that respond to the needs of your customers, you’ll be able to create better software with minimal effort.</p>



<p>When you develop products that your customers actually want, they’re going to be much happier with your software. It’s important to remember that creating customer value is the goal of every business process. Finding ways to make your own business process more efficient is important, but it’s even more critical to focus on customer value.</p>



<h2>Interaction Between Agile and DevOps Principles</h2>



<p>Many people are under the assumption that DevOps and Agile are two different methods, when, in fact, they’re both about rapid, continuous improvement. There are some differences between them, but both focus on bringing the best out of their team members.</p>



<p>Both DevOps and Agile are about collaboration between teams, and both aim to create high-quality, reliable software. But clearly, there are differences between the two. Let’s take a look at some of the similarities between the two methodologies.</p>



<p>Both DevOps and Agile work best when they are integrated. The goal of an integrated approach is to produce high-quality software as quickly as possible. Through the collaboration between developers, testers, operations staff, and other members of the team, you can achieve a faster turnaround time for your software.</p>



<p>To make this collaboration possible, teams must adhere to certain principles such as communication, consistency, and agility.</p>



<p>Additionally, an integrated DevOps and Agile approach can help to reduce the risk of software defects. To accomplish this, you must work with your team to create automated tests for your software.</p>



<p>By integrating DevOps and Agile development processes, you can increase your team’s overall quality. Through testing, you can catch problems before they are shipped to customers. Operations can also be integrated into the process, reducing bottlenecks and increasing the speed of software releases.</p>



<p>These principles aren’t rigid rules; rather, they’re guidelines for implementing good practices for developing software and delivering it more efficiently. They aren’t meant to replace traditional methods of doing business or IT operations; rather, they complement them in order to achieve greater results as quickly as possible.</p>



<h3>Being Agile with DevOps</h3>



<p>DevOps is based on an Agile mindset. It’s an approach to agile software development and software delivery. This means developers and operations professionals must collaborate closely to create a better product in the shortest amount of time possible.</p>



<h3>Being Lean with DevOps</h3>



<p>Lean principles are also important in DevOps, but they are used differently than they are in traditional lean methodologies. These principles focus on continuous improvement, continuous learning, and continuous feedback. The overall goal is to make the process more efficient by minimizing waste and increasing quality.</p>



<h2>Limitations of Traditional Methods of Software Development</h2>



<p>Traditional methodologies are focused on creating a single version of the truth, which can be a limitation if you want to adapt to changing business needs. DevOps, on the other hand, is all about continuous change, so it can be challenging to adapt to that. While related, the need to be agile is a significant difference between DevOps and traditional methodologies.</p>



<h2>Advantages of DevOps over Traditionally practiced methodologies</h2>



<p>The main advantage of DevOps over traditional methodologies is that it helps organizations create better software with minimal effort. With traditional methodologies, such as Waterfall, there is a high probability that the software will not be delivered on time and within budget, and that can be a significant problem. With DevOps, on the other hand, it’s important to note that there’s a difference between creating better software and just producing more of it.</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>DevOps is a transformation aimed at bringing together the disciplines of development and operations to produce high-quality software. It’s a marriage between the teams involved, and it needs to be built on communication and collaboration. DevOps is key to transforming operations and allowing everyone to create high-quality, reliable software. And collaboration between teams is what allows for this. DevOps is the marriage between software engineers and IT professionals.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What is Automation Testing in DevOps</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/devops-testing/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greer Shepherd]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 19:39:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[testing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tools]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1239</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Automation Testing in DevOps is generally relegated to the software being released to production. Environmental testing is performed by manual testing practices or high-level smoke tests. Test automation should cover the full CI/CD pipeline including infrastructure, delivery tools, software, UI,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Automation Testing in <a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> is generally relegated to the software being released to production. Environmental testing is performed by manual testing practices or high-level smoke tests.</p>



<p><strong>Test automation should cover the full CI/CD pipeline including infrastructure, delivery tools, software, UI, and any other technology that is included in the pipeline. Automated tests should not be relegated to the land of software development.</strong></p>



<p>Let&#8217;s explore what automation testing in DevOps really means when you are looking to stabilize your delivery process and accelerate your business!</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Automated Testing in DevOps</h2>



<p>Generally, developers tend toward coding unit tests to validate that the code is running the way they expected. At the same time, quality practitioners create automated user tests that validate the end-to-end user experience.</p>



<p>Quality practitioners can arrange explorative testing sessions in which teams manually look at various application area issues.</p>



<p>DevOps&#8217; best practice for the automation of CI/CD pipelines is to run automatic testing whenever possible. This means deploying automatic test UIs to production to detect and proactively address user experience concerns.</p>



<p>I generally like to take this a step further when looking at environmental conditions. Tests for environments can also be thought about in the context of monitoring and observability. A pipeline should be qualified through the use of testing tools in an automated test process. The tests should also be composed in a way that they are usable as part of your monitoring system.</p>



<p>For example, if you are willing to validate that a certificate is valid as part of your testing framework, you should also be willing to run continuous testing to validate that the certificate does not expire between releases.</p>



<h2>The Importance of Test Automation</h2>



<p>Test automation improves reliability, continuity, and productivity within teams of developers and products. DevOps teams have a better chance of staying within budget without disrupting crucial debugging or problem-shooting processes.</p>



<p>Test automation can be quicker than manual testing. It helps to avoid costly errors by eliminating communication barriers and saves money in teams by eliminating unnecessary work. Testing automation provides new forms of flexibility that enable the development team to reuse test scripts across the testing software.</p>



<p>As a business leader, do not be fooled by the short-term investment cost of introducing automated testing into your environment. Testing automation is not new and sexy functionality that you can provide to the market which is why I believe it is skipped by many businesses. Automated testing, continuous integration, and continuous delivery are critical investments to the longevity of your products.</p>



<p>Each release is always going to end up being more complex than the previous release. Employing a good testing process ensures that your products are being introduced to the market in a reliable and expected way. Because of the increased complexity, any manual testing process will need to scale to meet that complexity. Automated testing does not scale in cost the same way that manual testing does.</p>



<h2>What is test automation?</h2>



<p>Test Automation enables users to automate their software testing to ensure that they meet specified quality standards. Different types of testing are often depicted in pyramids. As you ascend the pyramid, the number of testing types decreases, and the costs of creating and operating the test increase. The most traditional tests were conducted using manual methods in the Pyramids in the past. It was a slow and costly procedure until automated testing tooling came into effect.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://www.headspin.io/blog/the-testing-pyramid-simplified-for-one-and-all" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img decoding="async" src="https://global-uploads.webflow.com/619e15d781b21202de206fb5/6316d9e765cd53d9937e2b6a_The-Testing-Pyramid-Simplified-for-One-and-All.webp" alt="The Testing Pyramid"/></a><figcaption>Headspin: The Testing Pyramid: Simplified for One and All</figcaption></figure>



<h2>Common Test Automation Pitfalls</h2>



<p>Below are some of the most common issues when adding automated testing to your technology products:</p>



<ul><li>Developers not participating in testing</li><li>Unit tests not being written with code</li><li>Testing tools are not being used to their fullest potential</li><li>No standard for code coverage</li><li>Best practices not being employed for a specific technology stack</li><li>Tests are not being run in the proper places of a pipeline.</li></ul>



<h2>How Automated Testing Powers DevOps?</h2>



<p>One of the core goals of DevOps is to improve delivery flow. Test automation is one of the core strategies used to help smooth out both flow and quality expectations. A cultural pillar of DevOps is continuous improvement.</p>



<p>Due to the shortened feedback loop of your continuous delivery pipeline, smaller and more nimble software testing and release cycles can be achieved by the development team. This means that your applications will be less prone to errors due to robust testing.</p>



<p>When issues are discovered in production they are not turned into a grandiose response event. A DevOps team is able to get adjustments made to both code and tests and re-release the software quickly back into production.</p>



<p>Without automating releases and tests, teams will scramble to recertify software before being ready to push it back to production with bug fixes. Worse, if your software teams do not employ any testing, you may never know about critical issues before customers bring them up.</p>



<h2>How Can I Improve Continuous Testing?</h2>



<p>Continuous testing is one of the most important things you can do to improve your success rates. If you’re doing it right, continuous testing will help you catch bugs at the earliest stages of development and make sure that problems don’t creep up in production.</p>



<p>Continuous testing helps to keep projects on track and ensure that they stay on schedule, which means that your customers get their products sooner.</p>



<p>A good way to start building a continuous test strategy is by creating an automated integration test pipeline. It should consist of a series of tests that are run automatically when new code is added to your application.</p>



<p>Automated integration tests can be especially useful when you have a large team developing multiple applications that share common code libraries or frameworks. They can also be useful for large-scale applications with many users and complex data models.</p>



<p>Continuous testing also allows developers to build trust with their customers by letting them know that their products are being continuously tested and improved. This can help to increase customer confidence in your product and boost retention rates.</p>



<h2>How Does Automated Testing Change the Role of Quality Assurance?</h2>



<p>Automated testing is a way to evaluate the quality of software. The basic idea is that you write automated tests, or scripts, to check for unexpected behaviors or errors in the code.</p>



<p>Automated testers can run these scripts automatically, which saves time and effort for both developers and QA staff. When you have automated testing in place, you can focus on other tasks, like exploring new features or fixing bugs, without worrying about whether your application is running correctly.</p>



<p>There are two types of automated testing: static and dynamic. Static testing checks for basic issues like syntax errors, security holes, and database integrity. Dynamic testing checks for unexpected behaviors such as out-of-order execution, race conditions, and timeout issues.</p>



<p>QA teams use automated testing to maintain high standards of quality throughout the development process. They can catch issues early on in the development cycle and communicate findings effectively with developers and stakeholders.</p>



<p>By reducing bugs and improving overall quality, automated testing can help organizations achieve their goals more quickly and cost-effectively.</p>



<p>A Quality Assurance Engineers&#8217; role changes when embracing test automation testing. Their role will now be to enable the entire team to contribute tests to the automation pipeline. Test cases should be developed and run as part of the normal delivery process.</p>



<p>By making this transition, Quality Assurance Engineers can now focus on higher value work like covering edge cases, improving testing tools and methodology, and leveling up team members&#8217; skills in testing.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Test Automation Stages</h2>



<p>Test Automation includes several fundamental automation techniques that should be followed for quality testing. Testing automation systems are presented in stages atop test pyramids based on their hierarchy.</p>



<h3>Integration testing</h3>



<p>Integration tests measure whether logical integration is effective across all systems and can be achieved without unavoidable errors in integration. Incorporated testing is designed to test compliance with systems to determine how different modules interact.</p>



<h3>Unit testing</h3>



<p>Unit Testing means isolating your Application into unit testing and then checking its behavior independently of external parties or database configuration. Unit tests are often conducted throughout the build period and are considered the primary test phase.</p>



<h3>End-to-end testing</h3>



<p>Test frameworks for the testing of applications simulate user requirements to ensure they meet the needs of users at all levels. The final purpose is to ensure the application can be validated and checked by all the users.</p>



<h3>Exploratory testing</h3>



<p>Exploration testing can be regarded as a more advanced software testing strategy that involves learning, checking, and reviewing functional and visual components for users.</p>



<h3>Environmental Testing</h3>



<p>Building tests to validate the consistency that your software will be running in after deployment.</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>As you can see, automated testing is a cornerstone to DevOps. Most focus is generally put on running automated testing against software being developed. There are a lot of advantages to developing automated testing which also looks at environmental conditions as well. Accelerate your business by introducing automated testing tools today!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Modify VMWare ESXi Guest Files with Ansible</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/ansible-modify-vmware-esxi-guest-file/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 01:25:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ansible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[howto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tools]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1232</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This post will help anyone who is attempting to use ansible to modify files on VMs running on ESXI via automation when Practicing DevOps. This method assumes that you have cloned out a machine, but do not yet have network&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>This post will help anyone who is attempting to use <a href="https://www.ansible.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="7" title="Ansible">ansible</a> to modify files on VMs running on ESXI via automation when <a href="https://www.valewood.org/practicing-devops/">Practicing DevOps</a>.  This method assumes that you have cloned out a machine, but do not yet have network access to that machine meaning you would need to utilize native ESXi methods to get communication setup.  </p>



<p>I use methods like this in my home lab to help stay current with new trends in <a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> Not everyone is going to be fortunate enough to have cloud playgrounds to test out new things, and home labs are a great way to make a one-time investment in your future.</p>



<p>The code for the project can be found <a href="https://github.com/gwagner/ansible-examples/tree/main/modify-vmware-esxi-guest-file" target="_blank" data-type="URL" data-id="https://github.com/gwagner/ansible-examples/tree/main/modify-vmware-esxi-guest-file" rel="noreferrer noopener">here</a>!</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Prerequisites</h2>



<p>This article is going to assume that you already have VMWare running in a home lab somewhere. This also assumes that you have some familiarity with VMware and networking.</p>



<p>This post will also assume that you have already installed a baseline OS running open-vm-tools. <a href="https://www.packer.io/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="17" title="Packer" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Packer</a><a href="https://www.packer.io/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"></a> is a good tool to use to automate your baseline operating system installation to create a reusable disk image.</p>



<p>You may also want to read <a href="https://www.valewood.org/ansible-create-vmware-esxi-vm/" data-type="post" data-id="1213">this post</a> to get a good feeling about how to automate cloning images when vSphere or Center are not available solutions.</p>



<h2>The Playbook</h2>



<p>Below is the full code to copy SSH keys to a newly cloned machine, and set an IP address with a NetworkManager restart.</p>



<p>The general idea is to run <code>ansible-playbook modify-vmware-esxi-guest-file.yaml -i inventory.yaml</code> from your command line.  The playbook will then connect to ESXi and create a .ssh folder on your fresh machine.  It will then copy your local <code>/home/user/.ssh/id_rsa.pub</code> file to the remote machine.  Finally, it will run <code>/bin/nmcli </code>commands to get a static IP address set on the VM.</p>



<p>A majority of this playbook is also setup with <code>delegate_to: localhost</code>. This means that the computer running the ansible script will also execute anything with the defined <code><code>delegate_to</code>: localhost</code>. Since the remote machine from inventory exists but is not yet able to be connected to <code><code>delegate_to</code>: localhost</code> is necessary of you would immediately receive an ansible connection error.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>---
- name: Modify VMWare ESXi VM File
  hosts: all
  gather_facts: false
  tasks:
    - include_vars: config.yaml
      delegate_to: localhost

    - include_vars: creds.yaml # Remember, this should be in a vault
      delegate_to: localhost   # These creds are for example use only

    - name: Create .ssh folder
      community.vmware.vmware_guest_file_operation:
        validate_certs: false
        hostname: "{{ vmware_host }}"
        username: "{{ vmware_user }}"
        password: "{{ vmware_password }}"
        datacenter: ha-datacenter
        vm_id: "{{ vmware.name }}"
        vm_username: "{{ centos_template_user }}"
        vm_password: "{{ centos_template_password }}"
        directory:
          path: "/home/user/.ssh/"
          operation: create
          recurse: no
      delegate_to: localhost

    - name: Copy RSA to VM
      community.vmware.vmware_guest_file_operation:
        validate_certs: false
        hostname: "{{ vmware_host }}"
        username: "{{ vmware_user }}"
        password: "{{ vmware_password }}"
        datacenter: ha-datacenter
        vm_id: "{{ vmware.name }}"
        vm_username: "{{ centos_template_user }}"
        vm_password: "{{ centos_template_password }}"
        copy:
          src: "/home/user/.ssh/id_rsa.pub"
          dest: "/home/user/.ssh/authorized_keys"
          overwrite: yes
      delegate_to: localhost

    - name: Run command inside a virtual machine
      community.vmware.vmware_vm_shell:
        hostname: "{{ vmware_host }}"
        username: "{{ vmware_user }}"
        password: "{{ vmware_password }}"
        datacenter: ha-datacenter
        vm_id: "{{ vmware.name }}"
        vm_username: "{{ centos_template_user }}"
        vm_password: "{{ centos_template_password }}"
        vm_shell: "{{ item.shell }}"
        vm_shell_args: "{{ item.args }}"
      loop:
        - { shell: "/bin/nmcli", args: "connection modify ens192 IPv4.ignore-auto-dns yes" }
        - { shell: "/bin/nmcli", args: "connection modify ens192 IPv4.address \"{{ vmware.ip_address }}/24\"" }
        - { shell: "/bin/nmcli", args: "connection modify ens192 IPv4.gateway \"{{ vmware.gateway_address }}\"" }
        - { shell: "/bin/nmcli", args: "connection modify ens192 IPv4.dns \"{{ vmware.dns_address }}\"" }
        - { shell: "/bin/nmcli", args: "connection modify ens192 IPv4.method manual" }
        - { shell: "/bin/systemctl", args: "NetworkManager restart" }
      delegate_to: localhost

</code></pre>



<h2>Task By Task Breakdown</h2>



<p>To not rehash details I have gone through in other articles, you can find a breakdown of the inventory, credentials, and config in <a href="https://www.valewood.org/ansible-create-vmware-esxi-vm/#penci-A-Task-By-Task-Breakdown" data-type="URL" data-id="/ansible-create-vmware-esxi-vm/#penci-A-Task-By-Task-Breakdown">this post.</a></p>



<p>The first step of this playbook is to create a users .ssh folder so an authorized_keys file can be created.  The playbook makes an assumption that your user is named&#8230; user, but that could be modified and turned into a configuration parameter pretty quickly.  I will break down each of the config parameters below:</p>



<ul><li>validate_certs is set to false because most of us are not going to be using trusted 3rd party certs in our VMware environment. If you are doing this in a professional environment, ensure you have valid certs installed and leave validate_certs set to the default of true.</li><li>validate_certs should also be set to false if you are connecting to your VMWare server via IP address since your cert will not match an IP address.</li><li>vmware_user and vmware_password should be set to a user that has SSH access to your VMWare server. I would not recommend that you do this in any sort of production environment, but it is perfectly fine for a home lab.</li><li>datacenter is set to ha-datacenter. This is the default name of a “datacenter” in ESXi. There is no reason to change this.</li><li>vm_id is either the exact case-sensitive name of the virtual machine being configured.  If you created your machine using ansible, then make sure you map the name you gave it here via variables.</li><li>vm_username and vm_password is in reference to the user you setup when creating your template or disk image.  ESXi needs this to effectively run an interactive login to the server to perform your commands.</li><li>directory is signifying that our action is going to be taken on a directory.  In the next task you will see that we use the copy key instead of directory but we are utilizing the exact same module.</li><li>directory.path is the path on the ESXi guests that you want to take action on.</li><li>directory.operation denotes what we want to have happen.  In this case, we are going to create a directory.</li><li>directory.recurse tells ansible if it should send a command that recursively creates directories.  If your default user is not named user, you would end up with a /home/user/.ssh directory that will be fairly useless.</li></ul>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>    - name: Create .ssh folder
      community.vmware.vmware_guest_file_operation:
        validate_certs: false
        hostname: "{{ vmware_host }}"
        username: "{{ vmware_user }}"
        password: "{{ vmware_password }}"
        datacenter: ha-datacenter
        vm_id: "{{ vmware.name }}"
        vm_username: "{{ centos_template_user }}"
        vm_password: "{{ centos_template_password }}"
        directory:
          path: "/home/user/.ssh/"
          operation: create
          recurse: no
      delegate_to: localhost</code></pre>



<p>This next task does a copy of a file from the machine you executed the ansible playbook from onto the ESXi guest that we are configuring.  In the interest of brevity, I am not going to rehash the duplicate keys from above.  Here are the specific keys of interest in this task:</p>



<ul><li>copy denotes that we want to copy a file.  The file needs to exist on your source system and will be copied to the ESXi guest.</li><li>copy.src is the path to the source file.  As you can see, we are targeting the public key here.</li><li>copy.dest is the full path to the destination.   As you can see we are targeting an authorized_keys file as the destination.  This could be dangerous if that file already exists as it will be overwritten.</li><li>copy.overwrite ensures that we will clobber whatever exists on the destination system with the file from our source system.</li></ul>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>    - name: Copy RSA to VM
      community.vmware.vmware_guest_file_operation:
        validate_certs: false
        hostname: "{{ vmware_host }}"
        username: "{{ vmware_user }}"
        password: "{{ vmware_password }}"
        datacenter: ha-datacenter
        vm_id: "{{ vmware.name }}"
        vm_username: "{{ centos_template_user }}"
        vm_password: "{{ centos_template_password }}"
        copy:
          src: "/home/user/.ssh/id_rsa.pub"
          dest: "/home/user/.ssh/authorized_keys"
          overwrite: yes
      delegate_to: localhost</code></pre>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<p>This last task is composed a bit differently.  Effectively it is being used to run a series of nmcli commands along with a single systemctl command to set a static IP address for this machine.  I have this task composed this way to clean up ansible code.  This could be written as six fully independent tasks in ansible, but remember to stay DRY and don&#8217;t repeat yourself.  Here is a breakdown of the specific keys of interest:</p>



<ul><li>vm_shell represents the exact path to the command that is going to be run on the ESXi guest.  Do not include command arguments in this field, the documentation specifically states that it wants a full path to an executable.</li><li>vm_shell_args represents the arguments to the vm_shell command.  </li><li>loop controls how the task will loop through the data defined underneath.  I have the keys setup as dictionary objects so that we get both shell executables and arguments from the loop.</li></ul>



<pre class="wp-block-code"><code>    - name: Run command inside a virtual machine
      community.vmware.vmware_vm_shell:
        hostname: "{{ vmware_host }}"
        username: "{{ vmware_user }}"
        password: "{{ vmware_password }}"
        datacenter: ha-datacenter
        vm_id: "{{ vmware.name }}"
        vm_username: "{{ centos_template_user }}"
        vm_password: "{{ centos_template_password }}"
        vm_shell: "{{ item.shell }}"
        vm_shell_args: "{{ item.args }}"
      loop:
        - { shell: "/bin/nmcli", args: "connection modify ens192 IPv4.ignore-auto-dns yes" }
        - { shell: "/bin/nmcli", args: "connection modify ens192 IPv4.address \"{{ vmware.ip_address }}/24\"" }
        - { shell: "/bin/nmcli", args: "connection modify ens192 IPv4.gateway \"{{ vmware.gateway_address }}\"" }
        - { shell: "/bin/nmcli", args: "connection modify ens192 IPv4.dns \"{{ vmware.dns_address }}\"" }
        - { shell: "/bin/nmcli", args: "connection modify ens192 IPv4.method manual" }
        - { shell: "/bin/systemctl", args: "NetworkManager restart" }
      delegate_to: localhost</code></pre>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>As you can see, with a fairly concise set of steps, you can level up your DevOps automation game by rapidly configuring virtual machines in your home lab.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>PurpleUrchin Crypto Mining with Free GitHub Actions</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/purpleurchin-crypto-mining/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 02:26:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1225</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sysdig Threat Research Team has discovered PURPLEURCHIN, an elaborate crypto mining operation taking advantage of automated CI/CD services. Attackers have used millions of free compute cycles through services such as GitHub Actions, Heroku, and others, to run the operation. What&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://sysdig.com/blog/massive-cryptomining-operation-github-actions/" data-type="URL" data-id="https://sysdig.com/blog/massive-cryptomining-operation-github-actions/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sysdig Threat Research Team</a> has discovered PURPLEURCHIN, an elaborate crypto mining operation taking advantage of automated CI/CD services. Attackers have used millions of free compute cycles through services such as <a href="https://www.github.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="6" title="Github" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">GitHub</a> Actions, Heroku, and others, to run the operation.</p>



<p>What does this mean to the <a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> community?</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>A Basic Breakdown of the Attack</h2>



<p>The attack was first identified when automated scanning identified some obscurely named images on DockerHub were being updated through automated patterns that did not match any kind of heuristic pattern.  From there, it appears that free-tier GitHub accounts were being created and each account allows for 2000 minutes per month of free GitHub Actions runtime.  Repositories were then created and a specially crafted <code>github-actions.yaml</code> workflow was created in those repositories.  Containers were then started which kick off crypto mining operations.  Ports are also opened up to serve as command and control for the distributed attack.</p>



<p>To get the full details of the attack, which are extremely fascinating, I would look into the article linked at the top of this post.  There are a ton of depth and built-in workarounds to combat the systems of control that GitHub has in place to protect its infrastructure from attack.</p>



<h2>What is the Threat of a Poorly Secured Code Repository?</h2>



<p>Supply chain attacks have become commonplace in software development.  Companies are constantly chasing CVEs from packages that are either not being well maintained by the community or are being maintained but companies are not allocating enough funding to keep their software in line with community updates.  </p>



<p>The most pronounced threat in recent memory was <a href="https://nvd.nist.gov/vuln/detail/CVE-2021-44228" data-type="URL" data-id="https://nvd.nist.gov/vuln/detail/CVE-2021-44228" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Log4j remote code execution bug</a> found in versions below 2.16.  This allowed attackers to craft a simple attack that was able to quickly run arbitrary code that could have real consequences.</p>



<p>Companies all over the planet rushed to update their code bases.  You can find massive Reddit threads that were discussing their companies&#8217; responses to the issue.  I would imagine, even with all of the industry hype, this vulnerability still exists in the wild and is still being exploited.</p>



<p>How can something like this be avoided in the future?  People familiar with DevOps automation will quickly reply by adding more automation to their environments and building systems.  While I completely agree with this response, if automation is added irresponsibly the threat landscape you are looking at will broaden very quickly.</p>



<p>In high school, I was enrolled in vocational education where I learned how to build a shed.  It was a pretty awesome experience and I learned a lot.  The shop teacher in charge of running the class and keeping the students safe was generally opposed to using power tools to aid in our learning.  When approached as to why his response was simply this; &#8220;power tools are just going to ensure that you kids screw something up faster than with hand tools&#8221;.</p>



<p>When adding automation to an environment, especially in concert with code repositories and build systems, you are opening yourself up to a lot of risks that need to be mitigated.  If your pipelines are fully automated from commit through production, then all it takes is one simple push before disaster strikes.</p>



<p>Tom Scott from &#8220;Things You Might Not Know&#8221; does a pretty good theoretical exercise about how quickly things can go wrong in a scenario like this.  I have added the video below.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Single Point of Failure: The (Fictional) Day Google Forgot To Check Passwords" width="1170" height="658" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/y4GB_NDU43Q?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div><figcaption>Single Point of Failure: The (Fictional) Day Google Forgot To Check Passwords</figcaption></figure>



<h2>What Does PurpleUchin mean for DevOps and Automation?</h2>



<p>PURPLEURCHIN appears to be a fairly sophisticated vehicle to utilize free computing resources to mine cryptocurrency.  On its face, a group is just trying to make a buck.</p>



<p>On its face, it does not seem very threatening.  This kind of attack really shows not only the creativity of attackers today, but it highlights how complex a company&#8217;s technology stack has gotten, and how easy it is to hide inside of it.  </p>



<p>Here are some questions that you can ask yourself to understand your level of visibility:</p>



<ul><li>Would you know if all of the code that made it into production on your next release was intentionally put there by good actors?</li><li>Would you know if your servers are only running what you intended for them to be running?</li><li>Could a sidecar process be spun up by a bad actor and would anybody notice?</li><li>Does your automated testing stack take environmental considerations into account when passing a build?</li><li>Do you know what versions of 3rd party dependencies are running in your environment?</li><li>Would you know if a 3rd party dependency has been compromised?</li><li>Could you quickly replace a compromised dependency to ensure business continuity?</li><li>Do you know if your organization is utilizing GitHub Actions workflows that have been vetted by the security community?</li></ul>



<p>Now, these questions may seem like a little bit of fear-mongering, and that is intentional.  There are solutions for every single one of these already-solved problems on the market.  In my experience, companies are not always going that extra mile to ensure that they are protected from threat actors.</p>



<p>The factors that compound all of this are speed and automation.  I don&#8217;t think anybody will dispute the argument that the technology space moves extremely quickly.  On top of that, businesses must ship and release software at the pace of the market to remain competitive.  Because of that speed, automation is generally employed as a stop-gap to maintain a consistent pace.  Businesses have the possibility of leaving themselves exposed if those automated tools are not held to a higher standard than the software they are developing.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>PURPLEURCHIN serves as another reminder about the time and attention we need to pay to our supply chain and automated tool stacks.  While this particular attack does not constitute immediate concern for the technology community holistically like Log4J did, it serves as a great reminder that technology hygiene is as important as shipping valuable technology solutions to the market.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/y4GB_NDU43Q" medium="video" width="1280" height="720">
			<media:player url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/y4GB_NDU43Q" />
			<media:title type="plain">Single Point of Failure: The (Fictional) Day Google Forgot To Check Passwords</media:title>
			<media:description type="html"><![CDATA[http://tomscott.com/ - @tomscott - I spin a (fictional) tale of the day that Google accidentally opened everything. Performed at GeekyConf, with thanks to Bet...]]></media:description>
			<media:thumbnail url="/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/devops-purpleurchin.jpg" />
			<media:rating scheme="urn:simple">nonadult</media:rating>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How To Create ESXi VM With Ansible</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/ansible-create-vmware-esxi-vm/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 03:28:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ansible]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1213</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This post will help anyone who is attempting to use Ansible to create new VMs with automation when Practicing DevOps. I use this in my home lab to help stay current with new trends in DevOps. Not everyone is going&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>This post will help anyone who is attempting to use <a href="https://www.ansible.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="7" title="Ansible">Ansible</a> to create new VMs with automation when <a href="https://www.valewood.org/practicing-devops/" data-type="post" data-id="14">Practicing DevOps</a>.  I use this in my home lab to help stay current with new trends in <a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a>.  Not everyone is going to be fortunate enough to have cloud playgrounds to test out new things, and home labs are a great way to make a one-time investment in your future.</p>



<p>The code for the project can be found <a href="https://github.com/gwagner/ansible-examples/tree/main/create-vmware-esxi-vm" data-type="URL" data-id="https://github.com/gwagner/ansible-examples/tree/main/create-vmware-esxi-vm" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>!</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Prerequisites</h2>



<p>This article is going to assume that you already have VMWare running in a home lab somewhere.  This also assumes that you have some familiarity with VMware and networking.</p>



<p>This post will also assume that you have already installed a baseline OS.  <a href="https://www.packer.io/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="17" title="Packer" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Packer</a> is a good tool to use to automate your baseline operating system installation to create a reusable disk image.</p>



<h2>The Playbook</h2>



<p>Below is the full code to deploy a virtual machine from a disk image.  </p>



<p>The general idea is to run <code>ansible-playbook create-vmware-esxi-vm.yaml -i inventory.yaml</code> from your command line.  The playbook will then check to see if a machine exists.  If set to destructive, it will then delete any machine with the same name, copy an existing disk image, set some machine specifics like IP address, and then power on your machine.</p>



<p>VMWare vSphere makes this a fairly novel activity via the use of templates.  A standalone ESXi node does not have the benefit of templates which is why things get a bit more complex in this space.</p>



<p>A majority of this playbook is also setup with <code>delegate_to: localhost</code>.  This means that the computer running the ansible script will also execute anything with the defined <code><code>delegate_to</code>: localhost</code>.  The remote machine from inventory does not yet exist, which means; if <code><code>delegate_to</code>: localhost</code> was not set, you would immediately receive an ansible connection error.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>---
- name: Create VMWare ESXi VM
  hosts: all
  gather_facts: false
  vars:
    destructive: false
  tasks:
    - include_vars: config.yaml
      delegate_to: localhost

    - include_vars: creds.yaml # Remember, this should be in a vault
      delegate_to: localhost   # These creds are for example use only

    - name: Check if virtual machine exists
      community.vmware.vmware_guest_info:
        validate_certs: false
        hostname: "{{ vmware_host }}"
        username: "{{ vmware_user }}"
        password: "{{ vmware_password }}"
        datacenter: "ha-datacenter"
        name: "{{ vmware.name }}"
      delegate_to: localhost
      ignore_errors: true
      throttle: 1
      register: vmware_validate_guest
      when: destructive is not defined or not destructive

    - set_fact:
        destructive: yes
      when: |
        vmware_validate_guest is defined and (
          (vmware_validate_guest.skipped is defined and not vmware_validate_guest.skipped) 
          or (vmware_validate_guest.failed is defined and vmware_validate_guest.failed == True)
        )

    - name: Add vmware as a host
      add_host:
        hostname: "{{ vmware_host }}"
        ansible_ssh_host: "{{ vmware_host }}"
        ansible_user: "{{ vmware_user }}"
        ansible_ssh_pass: "{{ vmware_password }}"
      when: destructive

    - set_fact:
        num_cpu_cores_per_socket: "{{ vmware.num_cpus | int / 2 }}"

    - name: Remove virtual machine from inventory
      community.vmware.vmware_guest:
        validate_certs: false
        hostname: "{{ vmware_host }}"
        username: "{{ vmware_user }}"
        password: "{{ vmware_password }}"
        name: "{{ vmware.name }}"
        state: absent
        force: True
      delegate_to: localhost
      throttle: 1
      when: destructive

    - name: Delete VM Folders
      ansible.builtin.file:
        path: "{{storage_path}}/{{ vmware.name }}/"
        state: absent
      delegate_to: "{{ vmware_host }}"
      when: destructive
      throttle: 5

    - name: Create a virtual machine on vmware
      community.vmware.vmware_guest:
        validate_certs: false
        hostname: "{{ vmware_host }}"
        username: "{{ vmware_user }}"
        password: "{{ vmware_password }}"
        folder: /vm/
        name: "{{ vmware.name }}"
        state: poweredoff
        guest_id: "{{ vmware.guest_id }}"    
        disk: "{{ vmware.disks }}"
        datastore: "{{ datastore_name }}"
        hardware:
          boot_firmware: efi
          memory_mb: "{{ vmware.memory_mb }}"
          num_cpus: "{{ vmware.num_cpus }}"
          num_cpu_cores_per_socket: "{{ num_cpu_cores_per_socket | int }}"
          scsi: paravirtual
        networks:
        - name: "{{ vmware.port_group }}"
          connect: yes
          mac: "{{ vmware.mac_address  }}"
          ip: "{{ vmware.ip_address }}"
          netmask: "{{ vmware.netmask }}"
          device_type: vmxnet3
          type: static
      delegate_to: localhost
      register: deploy_vm
      throttle: 5
      when: destructive

    - name: Copy boot disk VMDK Files
      ansible.builtin.command: "{{ item }}"
      delegate_to: "{{ vmware_host }}"
      loop:
        - vmkfstools -i "{{storage_path}}/{{ image_name }}/{{ image_name }}.vmdk" "{{storage_path}}/{{ vmware.name }}/{{ image_name }}.vmdk" -d thin
      when: destructive
      throttle: 3

    - name: Add boot disks to virtual machine
      community.vmware.vmware_guest_disk:
        validate_certs: false
        hostname: "{{ vmware_host }}"
        username: "{{ vmware_user }}"
        password: "{{ vmware_password }}"
        name: "{{ vmware.name }}"
        datacenter: ha-datacenter
        disk:
          - filename: "&#091;{{datastore_name}}] {{ vmware.name }}/{{ image_name }}.vmdk"
            scsi_type: 'paravirtual'
            scsi_controller: 0
            unit_number: 1
      delegate_to: localhost
      register: disk_facts
      when: destructive
      throttle: 5

    - name: Power on virtual machine
      community.vmware.vmware_guest:
        validate_certs: false
        hostname: "{{ vmware_host }}"
        username: "{{ vmware_user }}"
        password: "{{ vmware_password }}"
        name: "{{ vmware.name }}"
        state: poweredon
        wait_for_ip_address: yes
      delegate_to: localhost
      register: deploy_vm
      when: destructive</code></pre>



<h2>A Task By Task Breakdown</h2>



<p>First, we should look at the inventory.</p>



<p>This example has only one example host defined in it under a group called example.  You are able to define as many hosts in inventory that you would like.  </p>



<p>The structure of the vars defined under example-01.valewood.lab are there to provide everything the playbook needs in order to provision a server in ESXi.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>---
all:
  hosts:
  children:
    example:
      hosts:
        example-01.valewood.lab:
          ip: 192.168.1.10 
          ansible_host: 192.168.1.10
          vmware:
            ip_address: 192.168.1.10
            gateway_address: 192.168.1.1
            dns_address: 192.168.1.1
            netmask: 255.255.255.0
            mac_address: "00:16:3E:A0:06:43"
            memory_mb: 8192
            name: example-01
            num_cpus: 4
            port_group: Example-App
            guest_id: centos64Guest
            disks: &#091;]</code></pre>



<p>Below is the code that reads in configurations and credentials.  These are broken up into 2 different files because credentials should always be encrypted and never stored in plaintext.  </p>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>    - include_vars: config.yaml
      delegate_to: localhost

    - include_vars: creds.yaml # Remember, this should be in a vault
      delegate_to: localhost   # These creds are for example use only</code></pre>



<p>The next step is to check to see if a VM exists in VMWare or not with the same name.  This is a crucial step to ensure that duplicate names are not used in VMWare.  Here are some key notes about additional configurations:</p>



<ul><li>validate_certs is set to false because most of us are not going to be using trusted 3rd party certs in our VMware environment.  If you are doing this in a professional environment, ensure you have valid certs installed and leave validate_certs set to the default of true.</li><li>validate_certs should also be set to false if you are connecting to your VMWare server via IP address since your cert will not match an IP address.</li><li>vmware_user and vmware_password should be set to a user that has SSH access to your VMWare server.  I would not recommend that you do this in any sort of production environment, but it is perfectly fine for a home lab.</li><li>datacenter is set to ha-datacenter.  This is the default name of a &#8220;datacenter&#8221; in ESXi.  There is no reason to change this.</li><li>throttle is set to 1 to provide time to ctrl+c IF you happen to run your playbook by mistake against many machines at once.</li><li>destructive is a variable that can be set which tells this playbook to not destroy and rebuild machines if they already exist.  By default, the destructive variable it is not defined which means a check will be performed.</li></ul>



<pre class="wp-block-code"><code>    - name: Check if virtual machine exists
      community.vmware.vmware_guest_info:
        validate_certs: false 
        hostname: "{{ vmware_host }}"
        username: "{{ vmware_user }}"
        password: "{{ vmware_password }}"
        datacenter: "ha-datacenter"
        name: "{{ vmware.name }}"
      delegate_to: localhost
      ignore_errors: true
      throttle: 1
      register: vmware_validate_guest
      when: destructive is not defined or not destructive</code></pre>



<p>The next block of code will set the <code>destructive</code> variable to true IF we did the validation check from the previous block.  The validation check in the previous block will not run if <code>destructive</code> is set to true.  This acts as a one-way gate.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>    - set_fact:
        destructive: yes
      when: |
        vmware_validate_guest is defined and (
          (vmware_validate_guest.skipped is defined and not vmware_validate_guest.skipped) 
          or (vmware_validate_guest.failed is defined and vmware_validate_guest.failed == True)
        )</code></pre>



<p>Things get a little bit tricky here, but I will explain the rationale behind this next block.  Your inventory file only has virtual machines defined in it, but for ansible remote connections to work properly, a host must be in inventory.  To get around this, in the middle of this playbook run, we call add_host which has an explicit delegate_to statement so that it runs on localhost.</p>



<p>The reason this is tricky is because of the way that ansible does variable expansion.  One would think that a single host is being added to the inventory, but what is really happening in a playbook?  Ansible is expanding variable scope out to each individual machine in the inventory.  This means that add_host is actually being added in the context of each host in the inventory.  If you have 10 hosts defined in inventory, add_host adds variables for your VMWare host for each inventory host.</p>



<p>TLDR; each host in inventory now has the ability to utilize a <code>delegate_to: {{ vmware_host }}</code> statement as part of their tasks.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>    - name: Add vmware as a host
      add_host:
        hostname: "{{ vmware_host }}"
        ansible_ssh_host: "{{ vmware_host }}"
        ansible_user: "{{ vmware_user }}"
        ansible_ssh_pass: "{{ vmware_password }}"
      when: destructive</code></pre>



<p>Next, we need to do a little bit of math.  This could be done live through future executions, but I like to split things like this out into separate set_fact tasks to ensure I can easily run any debug tasks in the future.</p>



<p>Basically, this accomplishes telling VMWare that I want my CPU cores evenly distributed across sockets.  This is not perfect because it does not take care of edge cases of 1 CPU or 3 CPUs being defined in inventory.  For my use cases, I never define anything that way, but this could easily be updated to accommodate.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>    - set_fact:
        num_cpu_cores_per_socket: "{{ vmware.num_cpus | int / 2 }}"</code></pre>



<p>Next, if we are destructive, we need to delete an existing VM.  I am not going to rehash any of the special variables from above.  The only relevant thing to notice here is the state being set to absent which will delete the machine, and force is set to true which will bypass any safety checks VMWare might do.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>    - name: Remove virtual machine from inventory
      community.vmware.vmware_guest:
        validate_certs: false
        hostname: "{{ vmware_host }}"
        username: "{{ vmware_user }}"
        password: "{{ vmware_password }}"
        name: "{{ vmware.name }}"
        state: absent
        force: True
      delegate_to: localhost
      throttle: 1
      when: destructive</code></pre>



<p>Next is a little bit of cleanliness.  The delete statement above will not actually cleanup the VMWare datastore filesystem.  We are performing a <code>delegate_to: {{ vmware_host }}</code> which means we will be running a direct delete over SSH to your server running vmware.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>    - name: Delete VM Folders
      ansible.builtin.file:
        path: "{{storage_path}}/{{ vmware.name }}/"
        state: absent
      delegate_to: "{{ vmware_host }}"
      when: destructive
      throttle: 5</code></pre>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<p>Finally, the meat of the playbook.  This task creates the VM which is defined in the inventory.  I will break down the relevant variables below.</p>



<ul><li>Folder is neccisary for vShpere.  When only running ESXi, this only requires a default value of /vm/.  Most home labs will not need to change this.</li><li>state is set to poweredoff.  You could set this to poweredon but leaving it poweredoff ensures you can do post-processing after this create task.</li></ul>



<p>Please note, <code>Create a virtual machine on vmware</code> is not referencing any kind of existing disk image.  This will create a new completely blank VM.  Subsequent tasks will utilize your disk image to ensure it is properly attached to this machine.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>    - name: Create a virtual machine on vmware
      community.vmware.vmware_guest:
        validate_certs: false
        hostname: "{{ vmware_host }}"
        username: "{{ vmware_user }}"
        password: "{{ vmware_password }}"
        folder: /vm/
        name: "{{ vmware.name }}"
        state: poweredoff
        guest_id: "{{ vmware.guest_id }}"    
        disk: "{{ vmware.disks }}"
        datastore: "{{ datastore_name }}"
        hardware:
          boot_firmware: efi
          memory_mb: "{{ vmware.memory_mb }}"
          num_cpus: "{{ vmware.num_cpus }}"
          num_cpu_cores_per_socket: "{{ num_cpu_cores_per_socket | int }}"
          scsi: paravirtual
        networks:
        - name: "{{ vmware.port_group }}"
          connect: yes
          mac: "{{ vmware.mac_address  }}"
          ip: "{{ vmware.ip_address }}"
          netmask: "{{ vmware.netmask }}"
          device_type: vmxnet3
          type: static
      delegate_to: localhost
      register: deploy_vm
      throttle: 5
      when: destructive</code></pre>



<p>Next, perform a copy of an existing disk image into the folder that was just created for this new virtual machine.  This will essentially perform the same action that vSphere performs when cloning templates.</p>



<p>The key here is to utilize <code>vmkfstools</code> over ssh to ensure that you are able to get a thin provisioned copied disk.  If this is performed directly via ansible modules, you are not able to get a thin disk without vSphere.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>    - name: Copy boot disk VMDK Files
      ansible.builtin.command: "{{ item }}"
      delegate_to: "{{ vmware_host }}"
      loop:
        - vmkfstools -i "{{storage_path}}/{{ image_name }}/{{ image_name }}.vmdk" "{{storage_path}}/{{ vmware.name }}/{{ image_name }}.vmdk" -d thin
      when: destructive
      throttle: 3</code></pre>



<p>Next, we need to tell VMWare to mount our cloned disk to the recently created VM.  The new VM will have a scsi_controller so we just need to give it the right controller number of 0, and unit_number 1 to ensure we do not overwrite the new disk created via <code>Create a virtual machine on vmware</code>.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>    - name: Add boot disks to virtual machine
      community.vmware.vmware_guest_disk:
        validate_certs: false
        hostname: "{{ vmware_host }}"
        username: "{{ vmware_user }}"
        password: "{{ vmware_password }}"
        name: "{{ vmware.name }}"
        datacenter: ha-datacenter
        disk:
          - filename: "&#091;{{datastore_name}}] {{ vmware.name }}/{{ image_name }}.vmdk"
            scsi_type: 'paravirtual'
            scsi_controller: 0
            unit_number: 1
      delegate_to: localhost
      register: disk_facts
      when: destructive
      throttle: 5</code></pre>



<p>And finally we tell ESXi to power on the virtual machine.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>    - name: Power on virtual machine
      community.vmware.vmware_guest:
        validate_certs: false
        hostname: "{{ vmware_host }}"
        username: "{{ vmware_user }}"
        password: "{{ vmware_password }}"
        name: "{{ vmware.name }}"
        state: poweredon
        wait_for_ip_address: yes
      delegate_to: localhost
      register: deploy_vm
      when: destructive</code></pre>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>As you can see, with a fairly concise set of steps, you can level up your DevOps automation game by rapidly creating and tearing down virtual machines in your home lab.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Convert Text File to JSON with Ansible</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/ansible-text-to-json/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ansible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ansible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[howto]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1187</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I was looking through Reddit today and saw an interesting question about how to manipulate files with Ansible. I took a few minutes to throw together an example of how to convert a relatively simple file, a list of strings&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>I was looking through Reddit today and saw an <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ansible/comments/ycgtkg/convert_output_of_file_to_json_using_j2_template/" data-type="URL" data-id="https://www.reddit.com/r/ansible/comments/ycgtkg/convert_output_of_file_to_json_using_j2_template/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">interesting question</a> about how to manipulate files with <a href="https://www.ansible.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="7" title="Ansible">Ansible</a>.  I took a few minutes to throw together <a href="https://github.com/gwagner/ansible-examples/tree/main/read-file-output-json" data-type="URL" data-id="https://github.com/gwagner/ansible-examples/tree/main/read-file-output-json" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an example </a>of how to convert a relatively simple file, a list of strings broken up by new lines, and output it as JSON.  </p>



<p>Doing file conversions or data munging is an important skill to learn when growing in a <a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> position.  While this is a fairly basic example, utilize this as a stepping stone to understanding more complex data structures.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Simple Text to JSON Conversion with Ansible</h2>



<p>Below is the Ansible code to read in a file name input.txt delimited by newline characters and then do a simple conversion to JSON writing to output.json.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>- name: Simple Read file and output JSON
  hosts: localhost
  connection: local 
  become: false
  tasks:
  - name: Read Data File
    set_fact:
      data: "{{lookup('ansible.builtin.file', './input.txt').split('\n')}}"

  - name: Show debug data
    ansible.builtin.debug: var=data

  - name: Write output json file
    copy:
      dest: output.json
      content: "{{ data | to_json }}" </code></pre>



<h3>Task By Task Breakdown</h3>



<p>The first task reads the input.txt file into a data variable that Ansible can use. It also splits the file into a list via the \n (newline) character.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>  - name: Read Data File
    set_fact:
      data: "{{lookup('ansible.builtin.file', './input.txt').split('\n')}}"</code></pre>



<p>set_fact can be one of your best friends in Ansible. It allows you to take either data from what you have available in your playbook run, or lookup data and set it to a useable var for future tasks.  Here I am calling lookup to read an input.txt file and saving it to a data var.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>  - name: Show debug data
    ansible.builtin.debug: var=data</code></pre>



<p>ansible.builtin.debug lets you output the values of variables to the terminal during a playbook run.  This code should not be utilized anywhere except for testing.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>  - name: Write output json file
    copy:
      dest: output.json
      content: "{{ data | to_json }}" </code></pre>



<p>Finally, utilizing the built-in copy module, you can feed it a variable, like data, and then pipe that to a to_json jinja2 function which will then write your file out to dest.</p>



<p>The result of running this playbook will look something like this:</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code json"><code>&#091;"/site/foo/", "/site/bar/"]</code></pre>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Complex Text to JSON Conversion with Ansible</h2>



<p>Below is the Ansible code to read in a file name input.txt delimited by newline characters.  After reading the file, a new variable is initialized name data_elements.  A loop is then run to create new dictionary objects with a key of &#8216;name&#8217; and a value of each line of input.txt.  Finally, a copy is run to write the data to disk under output.json.  </p>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>- name: Complex Read file and output JSON
  hosts: localhost
  connection: local 
  become: false
  tasks:
  - name: Read Data File
    set_fact:
      data: "{{lookup('ansible.builtin.file', './input.txt').split('\n')}}"

  - name: Show debug data
    ansible.builtin.debug: var=data

  - name: Create a new array
    set_fact: 
      data_elements: &#091;]

  - name: Loop through lines and add data elements to array
    set_fact:
      data_elements: "{{ data_elements + &#091;{'name': item}] }}"
    loop: "{{ data }}"

  - name: Show debug data
    ansible.builtin.debug: var=data_elements

  - name: Write output json file
    copy:
      dest: output.json
      content: "{{ {'records': data_elements} | to_json }}" 
</code></pre>



<h3>Task By Task Breakdown</h3>



<p>Since most of the code here is the same, I will only focus on breaking out the differences.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code> - name: Create a new array
    set_fact: 
      data_elements: &#091;]</code></pre>



<p>The block above sets up the empty data_elements array that we will utilize to map our file lines onto.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>  - name: Loop through lines and add data elements to array
    set_fact:
      data_elements: "{{ data_elements + &#091;{'name': item}] }}"
    loop: "{{ data }}"</code></pre>



<p>This is setting up a loop to loop over our initial data variable which was read from input.txt.  It is appending new dictionaries into a larger array with a key of &#8216;name&#8217; and a value of the item in a loop.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>  - name: Write output json file
    copy:
      dest: output.json
      content: "{{ {'records': data_elements} | to_json }}" </code></pre>



<p>Finally, we are doing the same write operation as the simple example, but this time we are creating a dictionary with a key of &#8216;records&#8217; and a value of the data_elements array.</p>



<p>This will have an output that looks like this:</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code json"><code>{
   "records":&#091;
      {
         "name":"/site/foo/"
      },
      {
         "name":"/site/bar/"
      }
   ]
}</code></pre>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>As I stated at the beginning of the article, data manipulation in DevOps is a key skill to learn.  Hopefully, this helps kickstart someone on their journey into becoming a DevOps engineer!.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Do DevOps Engineers Write a lot of Scripting Code?</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/devops-scripting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greer Shepherd]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 21:45:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tools]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1180</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Whether it’s Python, JavaScript, or other programming languages, Developers spend a lot of time writing code. More traditional infrastructure engineers are going to spend their time in a user interface configuring their systems and services to work for their organizations.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Whether it’s Python, JavaScript, or other programming languages, Developers spend a lot of time writing code. More traditional infrastructure engineers are going to spend their time in a user interface configuring their systems and services to work for their organizations. Operations teams are going to be picking up what was developed for them by other groups and determine the right ways to run it efficiently.</p>



<p><strong><a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> engineers are going to be performing configuration management efforts, software development, operations activities, and quality assurance activities. Each of these can be automated by writing code with scripting languages. This means that DevOps engineers write code!</strong></p>



<p>Let&#8217;s explore what this means to a DevOps engineer who may not be comfortable with code since they are coming from a practice that generally performs their activities inside of a user interface.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Why Scripting Code is Important</h2>



<p>Automation is important. It’s a key part of the DevOps process, which aims to reduce the time it takes to perform manual processes. Automation also increases the reliability and stability of those processes.</p>



<p>While a lot of people talk about it, they rarely talk about why. If you don’t have a good reason, there’s a good chance that you won’t see the benefits of automation in your organization. That’s why it helps to understand why you are automating in the first place.</p>



<p>DevOps organizations have a lot of tools and technologies that need to integrate together. DevOps engineers will spend almost every day automating these integrations utilizing a variety of scripting languages or DevOps tools.</p>



<p>When you spend your days configuring everything from <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="14" title="AWS" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">AWS</a> keys to the location of a database; it’s easy to understand why organizations want to reduce the amount of time spent doing it manually.</p>



<h2>DevOps and Scripts</h2>



<p>Those who work across multiple different technologies to build applications and services spend a ton of time configuring environments, virtual machines, and cloud providers.</p>



<p>That means developers have to learn how to use every single one of those tools. At first, this might feel like a chore; after all, no one wants to learn how to use Inversion of Control (IoC) or batch files to get something from AWS into their local computer or network.</p>



<p>When you look at it from the perspective of someone who spends most of his or her day typing in code and reading other people’s scripts—the process can seem more like an abomination than anything else.</p>



<p>A majority of engineers are writing scripts to make their jobs more efficient. Scripts are the shortcut version of automation. They’re designed to help engineers reduce the amount of time they spend doing system administration, delivering software to servers, monitoring systems, performing configuration management, managing cloud vendors, and many other activities.</p>



<p>I have always advocated if you perform an activity against a user interface that has an API then you should take the time to implement that activity in code via your scripting language of choice.</p>



<p>By scripting your changes out, you both get an opportunity to codify a change, but you have an opportunity to introduce that code into version control. This will help shift the responsibility of that code from a single person to an entire team.</p>



<p>Additionally, scripting gives you the opportunity to add comments to your code. Software developers utilizing high-level programming languages will add comments in their code so that the next person that picks up their work understands the intentions of their work. Changes through scripting should be treated the same way. When someone spends time writing scripts, those should be added to the collective code base and their peers should be able to understand the code and consume their work.</p>



<p>Contributing to the code base also allows that code to be integrated into CI/CD systems for future automated actions.</p>



<h2>Which DevOps Engineers Should be Working With Scripts?</h2>



<p>The first step in automating any process is figuring out who should do the automation. That can be tricky. It’s easy to think that the developers who spend most of their day writing code should be the ones to automate their work.</p>



<p>After all, they have all of the technical knowledge. But, depending on the organization, that might not be the best idea. In organizations using DevOps practices, developers aren’t soley responsible for creating new end-to-end application solutions.</p>



<p>Instead, everyone on the team is responsible for creating an entire infrastructure along with the entire DevOps lifecycle.</p>



<p>DevOps engineers are responsible for automating the deployment and operations process of software applications. They are responsible for automating everything from creating configuration files to configuring software environments.</p>



<p>Many DevOps engineers work with scripts. There are many reasons why this is the case. One reason is that scripts allow DevOps engineers to automate tasks that are repeatable across multiple environments and application iterations.</p>



<p>If an automated task must be performed multiple times during the development process, it makes sense to create a script that can be used in each environment. Another reason is that scripts help reduce errors by providing clear instructions on how to perform the task.</p>



<p>DevOps engineers should be knowledgeable about scripting languages, such as Bash, Python, Ruby, and Javascript. They should also be familiar with automation tools like <a href="https://www.docker.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="16" title="Docker" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Docker</a> and <a href="https://www.ansible.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="7" title="Ansible">Ansible</a>.</p>



<p>They should be able to identify areas where automation can improve their workflow and determine what types of changes are needed to make automation possible in their organization.</p>



<h2>Why is it So Hard to Transition from Scripting to Automation?</h2>



<p>It might seem like your engineers would love to transition from scripting to automation. After all, they are spending their day writing code.</p>



<p>Sometimes a jump from scripting to automation can be difficult. If scripts are not written in a way that they can be parameterized, those scripts will not fit into an overall automation structure natively. Additionally, when you’re used to customizing everything from your local machine to your cloud providers, the thought of learning a new configuration tool can seem like a nightmare.</p>



<p>All of this confusion can lead engineers to either choose not to automate at all or make bad choices about how to automate. The software development industry has an answer for this.</p>



<p>Most engineers will take a little bit of time to work through the transition from their previous role into one that is inclusive of DevOps. This is why it is so critical to work with the team on learning DevOps and embracing a full DevOps transition.</p>



<p>Most software development starts as writing scripts, shell scripting, or learning bash. From there, it will expand into utilizing different popular programming languages. If your background is in Office365 administration, you will not go through this general progression.</p>



<p>Developers should take new DevOps engineers under their wing and help them utilize tools that may not be ultimately familiar with. DevOps engineering is the combination of many different skill sets breaking down traditional barriers. Helping DevOps engineers write scripts that are able to be integrated into a larger set of automation will be a huge step forward for anyone feeling lost in this adoption.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>How to Get Started With Automation in a DevOps Organization</h2>



<p>DevOps engineers constantly improve their automation, but there’s a lot to learn. That’s why it’s important to bring on someone to help with the transition to automation.</p>



<p>There are a few things you can do to get started. First, look at your existing scripts and see if you have any that could be automated. Are there any tasks that are taking more time than they should? If so, you might want to take a closer look at them. Next, look at your existing infrastructure. Do you have a known, consistent state? If so, you might want to take a closer look at your scripts.</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>If you’re a DevOps engineer who is coming from a user interface, the idea of writing code that can automate different tasks may seem scary. You may feel overwhelmed by the scope of this responsibility and wonder whether you can actually do it.</p>



<p>To start, you can check out some resources that are available on <a href="https://www.github.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="6" title="Github" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">GitHub</a>. One of the best ways to get started is to dive right into the world of scripting. The Python programming language is great for beginner developers because it’s very easy to pick up and performs well under the hood. Python has a free online course available that teaches you the basics with a few projects you can complete.</p>



<p>Once you know your way around Python, you can move on to the next step. As you progress, you can check out some of the other scripting languages in use. There are many options out there, and most of them are open-source and available for use. Your best bet is to choose one that you feel comfortable with, and then get familiar with the basics. You can find plenty of tutorials and documentation on how to get started with any of them.</p>



<p>When you feel ready, you can start experimenting with the different ways to configure your systems.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Are DevOps Engineers in Demand in 2022?</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/are-devops-engineers-in-demand/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 20:17:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[delivery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jobs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1127</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Whether you are looking to make a shift in your career path, or you are looking to change companies a common question job seekers will have is &#8220;Are DevOps Engineers in Demand?&#8221; Simply looking at job boards and reviewing the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Whether you are looking to make a shift in your career path, or you are looking to change companies a common question job seekers will have is &#8220;Are <a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> Engineers in Demand?&#8221;</p>



<p><strong>Simply looking at job boards and reviewing the numbers does not tell the entire story here. As of the time of writing LinkedIn has roughly 42,000 positions and Indeed has roughly 11,000 positions for the search term DevOps engineer.</strong></p>



<p>I believe that the honest answer to this question has more to do with market conditions than it does with job openings, though job openings are still a good indicator.</p>



<p>Let&#8217;s take a look at the market conditions to understand if a DevOps engineering skillset is in demand!</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Rising Demand for DevOps Talent</h2>



<p>Many of us in the technology industry know how DevOps is revolutionizing software development. Companies adopting the DevOps approach are doing more with greater efficiency in the process. DevOps can help a company provide a software solution quickly. It can therefore help prevent production problems if necessary and the result will also be improved customer experience, feedback, and communications.</p>



<p>Through to pandemic, more and more businesses needed to move to a digital presence to stay competitive in the market. This either means investing more heavily in technology or standing up new technology they may not have been ready for.</p>



<p>As the dust has settled, businesses are now left with aging technology that is not growing with their business which means future investment. The tech industry is stepping up to respond in this newly opened market.</p>



<p>If a business is not purely technology focused but utilizes technologies to enable sales, they are going to want to get into the most reliable modes of future delivery. This is where DevOps skills are filling the gap.</p>



<p>I have seen a new term popping up in the industry recently: &#8220;DevOps As A Service&#8221;. This is born out of the idea that the DevOps methodology can be bolted onto technologies that are becoming more relevant in the market to ensure more reliable modes of delivery.</p>



<h2>Is DevOps still in Demand?</h2>



<p>I am a hiring manager running a DevOps group. I have been hiring, training, and converting people from either IT operations teams or software development teams for nearly a decade now. I can confidently say that DevOps engineering roles are hard to fill, they are also very in demand and you need to move quickly when hiring.</p>



<h2>DevOps Talent is Still Hard to Find</h2>



<p>Let&#8217;s face it, the industry has done a terrible job of defining what DevOps really is. In most places, my experience has been, DevOps means infrastructure as code and does not account for the overall methodology.</p>



<p>Because of the incongruency between expectation and implementation, I would argue that a large portion of the talent pool is underdeveloped at this point. With the proper guidance, the talented job seekers out there can transition into a more DevOps-oriented mindset.</p>



<p>Businesses will need to take this into account when hiring for a DevOps engineer role. The perfect purple unicorn may not be as readily available as more well-defined roles like software engineering. With a little time and patience with a team committed to DevOps transformations, you can develop talent that will deliver high-quality work.</p>



<h2>Is it hard to get a job in DevOps?</h2>



<p>Many organizations do not know what DevOps actually means, so it&#8217;s challenging to find the right person for the position.</p>



<p>I updated my LinkedIn profile in 2015 to illustrate my transition into DevOps Engineering. Since then, I have progressed through an organization to lead teams of DevOps engineers.</p>



<p>I am not telling you this to brag, but I do want to use it as an example.</p>



<p>In my previous life, I was a PHP developer. I got bored of putting values into a database and then returning the exact same values to the screen. I started to get interested in configuration management and continuous integration which is when i hit the job market looking for my next gig.</p>



<p>Since 2015, when i changed by job title on LinkedIn, i still get recruiters reaching out looking to place me in another software engineering role.</p>



<p>I believe that the cycle of job searching in the technology industry is a bit upside down today. Companies seek talent and job seekers are looking for companies that want their skilled talent. It should be a perfect union, but there are a hoard of recruiters standing in the way of those perfect fits.</p>



<p>I would recommend spending your time learning about DevOps methodologies, optimizing value, soft skill, interpersonal skills, and automation tools. Form there, i would spend time looking up individuals with existing DevOps roles on LinkedIn (management or engineering) and make some connections. Those connections have a better chance of landing you a DevOps role than the normal recruiting mechanism most of the technology space uses today.</p>



<h2>Is DevOps Engineer a good career?</h2>



<p>DevOps is booming with an estimated US $287 billion market size by 2026. There are many roles available to developers in the world&#8217;s marketplace. Let&#8217;s face it, technology is not going away. Businesses that survive over the long haul are going to progressively adopt newer and more modern strategies to optimize their software development life cycle.</p>



<p>Because of the perpetual adoption of DevOps methodology by businesses, a DevOps engineer is going to have a long and vibrant career path. Silo&#8217;d development and operations teams will become more of an antiquated setup, and the merge of these disciplines together will become more of the norm.</p>



<p>I think the answer of &#8220;Good&#8221; is probably a bit more nebulous and needs a bit of personal soul-searching to really answer. I won&#8217;t be able to answer what is &#8220;Good&#8221; for you.</p>


<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="3622503162"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Why DevOps is a Good Career in 2022?</h2>



<p>DevOps has remained a popular role since its inception in 2018. CodinGame released a survey that ranks &#8220;DevOps Engineer&#8221; among the most popular developer job positions for 2021. Additionally, the survey revealed that 43% of hiring professionals are unable to fulfill their DevOps roles.</p>



<h2>What are Relevant Skills to start a DevOps career?</h2>



<p>Unlike most careers, DevOps requires basic knowledge and skills. When choosing an employment option, understanding this section can prove very important. If you do this before, then the barriers will be lower. Depending on the skills you have you can try another course.</p>



<p>I have an entire write-up over here that discusses the <a href="https://www.valewood.org/top-relevant-devops-skills/" data-type="post" data-id="330">Top Relevant DevOps Skills</a>.</p>



<p>TLDR; Focus on skills that support the DevOps philosophy. These are going to be focused on soft skills such as planning and communication. Also focus on learning some new tools, ci/cd, how to enable automation, and automated testing.</p>



<p>Don&#8217;t be afraid if you are lacking in any of these areas as well, most of the &#8220;DevOps pros&#8221; that i talk to are not familiar with half of the skills described in either the blog post or TLDR.</p>



<h2>How do I Progress in my DevOps Career?</h2>



<p>DevOps engineers with learning mindsets will be able to develop in their respective fields with plenty more to do. It seems obvious that one has to progress from junior engineering engineer to junior engineer eventually becoming a leader. DevOps also offers many career changes that could be made.</p>



<p>A simple way to think about progression is to focus on anything that helps drive a business forward through growth or hitting new targets. This means that, in general, new technologies will not progress your career path forward.</p>



<p>Building a DevOps mindset, working with a team to adopt DevOps, training new DevOps engineers, working with teams to develop software in a more streamlined way, bringing in automated testing, breaking down organizational silos, influencing team leaders, and any other non-technology-specific skill you can pick up will help progress your DevOps career.</p>



<p>Focusing on technologies will help progress from a DevOps engineer role into a DevOps architect role, but note that a pure technology focus does have an upper bound on it. That is not a bad thing because not everybody wants to get into management.</p>



<p>If you are looking to progress your career into management, work on building a DevOps culture.</p>



<h2>Will I get paid more as a DevOps Engineer?</h2>



<p>DevOps professionals are generally paid quite well. This is because the skillset for DevOps jobs demands a broader set of skilled talent. DevOps experts who can work with companies on DevOps transformations will yield an even greater salary. When negotiating, do not sell your talents and skills short.</p>



<p>If you are just diving into this space, also be realistic about where you are at and sell yourself on your aptitude and ability to learn new skills. Any organization worth sticking around and working for will recognize your growth and give you the bump in compensation that you deserve.</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>DevOps is evolving and changing. It is growing in importance for businesses to move forward in the digital age. DevOps engineers are key players in this evolution and have a wide range of skills needed by companies to thrive in the modern economy. They can work within many different industries, from financial services to automotive. DevOps engineers typically work with software teams across multiple departments within organizations, including IT operations and engineering.</p>



<p>DevOps teams are constantly looking for more talent that can fulfill the vision of smoother and more reliable delivery. That trend is not going away any time soon!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
