<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>development &#8211; A DevOps Blog</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.valewood.org/tag/development/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.valewood.org/</link>
	<description>Occasionally a developer makes an Ops!</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 22:13:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.valewood.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/A-DevOoops-1-e1660773390219.png</url>
	<title>development &#8211; A DevOps Blog</title>
	<link>https://www.valewood.org/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Which language should I learn for DevOps?</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/devops-languages/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 22:11:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tools]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=344</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[DevOps is all about bringing software development and operations together under a single functional team to increase quality, communication, collaboration, and efficiency.&#160; Developers already have a background in development (duh), but a question I get asked frequently by operations engineers&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>DevOps is all about bringing software development and operations together under a single functional team to increase quality, communication, collaboration, and efficiency.&nbsp; Developers already have a background in development (duh), but a question I get asked frequently by operations engineers is “Are there languages to learn for DevOps?”</p>



<p>Everyone could use a little bit of development in their life.&nbsp; It could be something as simple as a bash script to take care of a simple task, all the way up to running a blog like this one.&nbsp; Learning about the logical flow that a computer takes to compute everything is an empowering door to open when growing as a technology specialist in whatever field you specialize in.&nbsp; Below are a few of my favorite DevOps languages but this is by no means a definitive list.&nbsp; These are languages that I have used in my workflows and found some great success.</p>



<p>Let’s discuss some of the languages you can learn as someone with little to no experience so you can level up your DevOps game!</p>


<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
</p>



<h2>Interpreted vs Compiled Languages</h2>



<p>The first concept that we should tackle is the difference between an interpreted language vs a compiled language.&nbsp; There are some specific semantics to get under your belt as part of your language selection process.&nbsp; In the world of DevOps, I would say that there really is not an incorrect choice here, but; DevOps is all about flow and your choices here can have an impact on your desired technology flow.</p>



<h3>Interpreted Langauge</h3>



<p>An interpreted language requires that a separate runtime be installed on your system which will generally perform a JIT runtime on the code you have written.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>If I am writing code in Python, and I want that python to run on a remote Linux system, I need to have both the Python runtime installed on the remote system along with ensuring my code also exists on that system.</p>



<p>There is some practical utility to this.&nbsp; Your systems require a dependency like Python, PHP, Ruby, Bash, etc. to be installed on the remote system, but you get a pretty good guarantee that you can write code once and use it in many places across many architectures.&nbsp; The architecture (x86, ARM, SPARC, etc) has the runtime binaries installed (Python) and Just In Time “compile” (interprets) your code to be run on that architecture.&nbsp; Pretty neat right?</p>



<h3>Compiled Languages</h3>



<p>A compiled language requires that a full compilation happens prior to the code being runnable.&nbsp; In Windows land, think about this like a .exe file, or on Linux, this would be a binary.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>If I am writing code in C++, and I want to run by C++ on a remote Linux system, I have 2 options.&nbsp; I can install C++ on the remote system, add my code to that system, run a compile step, and finally run my binary.&nbsp; Alternatively, I could compile my binary locally (ensuring I match the OS and CPU architecture as part of the compile step) and then distribute that binary to the remote system for execution.</p>



<p>Generally, a compiled language will be statically linked which means that there are zero additional dependencies that need to live on a remote system, unlike an interpreted language.&nbsp; You do need to have a more detailed understanding of the remote system you will be deploying to so that your pre-compiled binary has a much better shot of being able to run on the destination.</p>



<h3>Need for Speed?</h3>



<p>Compiled languages are generally going to be faster than interpreted languages.&nbsp; A compiled application or script does not need to get converted from human-readable text into a binary that the CPU will understand.&nbsp; That compilation was done when the application was built.&nbsp; An interpreted language is going to need some kind of JIT compilation in order to be executed through the language&#8217;s runtime.&nbsp; In the PHP world, this JIT compilation is transforming human-readable text into OpCode.&nbsp; Once that OpCode is created then the PHP runtime can just execute what the OpCode tells it to execute.</p>



<p>When trying to do tool selection, there is generally an argument about the speed an application runs and whether the right tool is the fastest tool.&nbsp; When doing DevOps where you are generally trying to get a machine or environment into a specific state, the speed of the language itself is generally not your biggest impediment.&nbsp; Your biggest bottleneck will be remote resources like packages, downloads, etc.&nbsp; I would rather choose the right tool for the job inside of the ecosystem that I work in instead of trying to make my tool selection for DevOps based solely on performance.</p>



<h2>Python</h2>



<p>Python is an interpreted language and was created in the 1980s by Guido van Rossum in the Netherlands.&nbsp; It is widely adopted and widely used across the industry.&nbsp; You can find Python pre-installed on most modern Linux distributions today, though there is still a bit of fracturing between Python 2.x and 3.x communities.</p>



<h3>Community</h3>



<p>Python has a strong community backing it.&nbsp; At the time of writing this, PyPI has ~391,000 packages with nearly 660,000,000 package downloads per day.&nbsp; PyPI is a package repository for Python where you can download community or vendor-developed code and add it directly to your project.&nbsp; There are a lot of pre-solved problems out there like connecting to a database.&nbsp; PyPI enables users to download packages like those database connectors automatically.</p>



<h3>Utility</h3>



<p>Python has a lot of utility in the DevOps space.&nbsp; Since it is born out of the Linux and Unix ecosystem, it has some very strong ties to the Linux operating system for performing common tasks.&nbsp; It is so well suited for this task that <a href="https://www.ansible.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="7" title="Ansible">Ansible</a>-Core is written in Python.&nbsp; Python is also runnable on Windows!</p>



<p>Python is clearly a good choice when it comes to writing automation code for DevOps, but it has a lot of other utilities as well.&nbsp; Much of the Big-Data space is using python for number crunching and machine learning specifically because the language lends itself well to that kind of computation.&nbsp; Being a dynamically typed language instead of a statically typed one, data transformations can be done quickly without a lot of overhead by the end user.</p>



<p>Being an interpreted language gives it a lot of power as well when it comes to distributing and running the code.&nbsp; Aside from activities like automated testing, packaging Python consists of compressing your directory structure, moving it to where you want, decompressing, and finally running the code.&nbsp; If there is a bug, you can also fix it in place, though I would recommend ensuring that you have centralized code repositories and follow a good process of version control and pushing new versions out.</p>



<h3>Learning Resources</h3>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.learnpython.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://www.learnpython.org/</a></li><li><a href="https://www.codecademy.com/learn/learn-python" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://www.codecademy.com/learn/learn-python</a></li><li><a href="https://www.pythontutorial.net/python-basics/python-write-csv-file/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://www.pythontutorial.net/python-basics/python-write-csv-file/</a></li></ul>



<h2>Golang</h2>



<p>Golang was originally designed at Google in 2007 as a replacement for C and C++.&nbsp; Go foregoes some of the more tedious facets of C and C++ like header files for type definitions.&nbsp; Go is also a compiled language instead of an interpreted language meaning that the result of something in Golang is going to be a binary.&nbsp; Golant has quickly grown in popularity and is the core language behind the very popular container orchestration framework <a href="https://kubernetes.io/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="4" title="Kubernetes" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Kubernetes</a>.</p>



<h3>Community</h3>



<p>The size of the Golang community is tough to nail down because of the way that Go mod works.&nbsp; Go mod can be any git URL that has a go.mod and go.sum file in its repository.&nbsp; From there, go mod will check out the code, and check out the code&#8217;s dependencies all while doing dependency resolution in the background.&nbsp; Since git can be hosted anywhere, nailing down how many downloads a day without some kind of body providing central registration of packages like PyPI does, the best we can do is look at something like google trends for a baseline of activity.</p>



<script type="text/javascript" src="https://ssl.gstatic.com/trends_nrtr/3045_RC01/embed_loader.js"></script>
  <script type="text/javascript">
    trends.embed.renderExploreWidget("TIMESERIES", {"comparisonItem":[{"keyword":"/m/09gbxjr","geo":"US","time":"today 12-m"},{"keyword":"/m/06ff5","geo":"US","time":"today 12-m"},{"keyword":"/m/05z1_","geo":"US","time":"today 12-m"}],"category":0,"property":""}, {"exploreQuery":"geo=US&q=%2Fm%2F09gbxjr,%2Fm%2F06ff5,%2Fm%2F05z1_&date=today 12-m,today 12-m,today 12-m","guestPath":"https://trends.google.com:443/trends/embed/"});
  </script>



<p>As you can see by the graphic above, at the time of writing, Python is the dominant search in Google Trends compared to something like Golang.&nbsp; I would consider Golang a strong and growing community with projects like Kubernetes and CockroachDB along with large technology groups moving into using the stack like <a href="https://www.github.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="6" title="Github" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">GitHub</a> and Uber.</p>



<h3>Utility</h3>



<p>In my workflow, I am generally using Golang for 2 things; microservice apps and API middleware.</p>



<p>When I say microservice apps, I am generally not talking about something which is composed of a larger ecosystem.&nbsp; My microservice-type apps are usually tied into a Kubernetes stack.&nbsp; I had a particular challenge with <a href="https://linkerd.io/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="3" title="Linkerd" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">LinkerD</a> where I need to create a MutatingAdmissionWebhook to rewrite my HTTP(s) probes as in pod curl probes after setting my namespace to deny all.&nbsp; This was a good workaround to wrapping and rewriting many different helm charts to use curl probes instead of using standard HTTP(s) probes.</p>



<p>You can find that code <a href="https://github.com/gwagner/linkerd-convert-http-to-curl" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>When doing API orchestration, I have written a few applications which will pull data from one API (or have data pushed via a webhook) into an application that may amend or transform the data before pushing it into another receiving API.&nbsp; This is particularly useful when trying to normalize data from system A to system B.&nbsp; This was particularly useful when moving from a Graphite-based metric TSDB system over to InfluxDB.&nbsp; We did not need to rewrite all of our metric collectors, we just needed to tap into the metric stream, do an on-the-fly conversion, and then output metrics to InfluxDB.</p>



<h3>Learning Resources</h3>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.udemy.com/course/go-building-devops-tools/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://www.udemy.com/course/go-building-devops-tools/</a></li><li><a href="https://go.dev/learn/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://go.dev/learn/</a></li><li><a href="https://www.codecademy.com/learn/learn-go" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://www.codecademy.com/learn/learn-go</a></li></ul>



<h2>Ruby</h2>



<p>Because of its efficiency in DevOps, Ruby is a preferred scripting language for automating IT environments&#8217; repetitive tasks. In addition to web development, data science, and unit testing, this dynamic, interpreted programming language is used for DevOps. Ruby is also fairly simple to learn. As a result, the language has a fast-growing community of DevOps engineers. With no prior programming experience, beginners can get started with Ruby pretty quickly.&nbsp;</p>



<h3>Community</h3>



<p>Ruby is a difficult community to quantify fully simply because of how spread out it is.&nbsp; Ruby Gem can be a good baseline metric with roughly ~174,000 gems available from RubyGems.org and 111B+ (yeah, billion) downloads.&nbsp; If you look past ruby gems, the second most popular place that ruby is being utilized is with <a href="https://www.chef.io/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="8" title="Chef">Chef</a>.&nbsp; The marketplace has roughly 4,000 cookbooks with roughly ~80,0000 maintainers</p>



<h3>Utility</h3>



<p>Ruby has some great utility when it comes to DevOps automation.&nbsp; When building out an early DevOps-focused monitoring stack, we chose Sensu Core due to its configuration-driven and scalable design.&nbsp; Most of the community-produced checks at that point were written in ruby which lent itself very well to building reusable consistent libraries that were well-tested.</p>



<p>Much like the Golang example above, I have also utilized ruby as an API middleware for doing data payload manipulations.&nbsp; Prior to Docker supporting <a href="https://docs.docker.com/config/containers/logging/json-file/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">JSON File Logging</a>, there were very long debates about what separation between log entries means between different programming languages.&nbsp; Ruby was used in an environment where I was working into tail log output from containers and based on its configuration, properly parse and package logs to be sent to centralized logging systems upstream with additional metadata.</p>



<h3>Learning Resources</h3>



<ul><li><a href="https://gorails.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://gorails.com/</a></li><li><a href="https://www.chef.io/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://www.chef.io/</a></li></ul>


<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
</p>



<h2>Security Considerations</h2>



<p>When utilizing any code for any function whether it be DevOps or software development, you should always be concerned about security.&nbsp; Let’s say you have a 3-year-old server sitting around and its original automation code has not had any electricity run through it in the same time frame.&nbsp; That server&#8217;s automation code is probably outdated enough that there is at least some kind of CVE attached to it.&nbsp; This will be particularly easy to find if you are doing robust infrastructure scanning but will be much more obscure if you are running compiled binaries where the source code is not under some kind of routine scrutiny.&nbsp; Regardless of how you are building and running code, please make sure to clean up after yourself and avoid getting attacked by leaving a trail of outdated technology behind you.</p>



<h3>Supply Chain Attacks</h3>



<p>Supply chain attacks are all the rage these days.&nbsp; Consider the supply chain of your code dependency management system.&nbsp; Are you routinely scanning it for CVEs?&nbsp; Are you doing any kind of dynamic automated or manual testing of the code looking for vulnerabilities?&nbsp; Are you sure you can trust the source of your code dependencies?</p>



<p>DevOps code can be commonly overlooked in a supply chain attack scenario.&nbsp; Maybe you are writing a console tool to help make your life a little bit easier.&nbsp; You go ahead and pull in a few libraries from the internet to help aid in the creation of that tool like colored output.&nbsp; You also want to be really good and write automated tests as a best practice and you need help generating some data for those tests.&nbsp; Without a persistent review of code dependencies, the OSS developer/contributor of one of the dependencies that you are utilizing is tired of their <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/dev-corrupts-npm-libs-colors-and-faker-breaking-thousands-of-apps/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">work being used for free without any recognition or compensation</a> and deliberately destroys the project.&nbsp; There are also less directly malicious scenarios where the developer of a <a href="https://blog.sonatype.com/npm-project-used-by-millions-hijacked-in-supply-chain-attack" target="_blank" rel="noopener">popular package gets targeted and code is unknowingly slipped into their project</a>.</p>



<p>The lesson is this: assume that attack vectors are everywhere and ensure that you are scanning everything you can get your hands on for CVEs.&nbsp; The industry has a good focus on this now, and the question is not IF you will get compromised, but when.&nbsp; Keep yourself safe by being proactive.</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>As I stated at the beginning of this article, this is by no means a definitive list.&nbsp; This is a list of some of the tools that I utilized to build effective DevOps workflows and to enable the flow of delivery.&nbsp; I utilize these tools at my job along with utilizing these tools in my homelab.&nbsp; I believe that everyone could use a little bit of software development in their life.&nbsp; Python, Golang, or Ruby are really great places to start with languages because of their utility, communities, and ties to DevOps and DevOps tooling.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Do DevOps engineers need a coding background?</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/do-devops-engineers-need-a-coding-background/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 21:55:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=326</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The primary skill sets that DevOps engineers need are either in the system administration or software development space. Those 2 foundational skill sets will help any team build some cool solutions to complex problems. There are fringe cases where the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The primary skill sets that DevOps engineers need are either in the system administration or software development space.  Those 2 foundational skill sets will help any team build some cool solutions to complex problems.  There are fringe cases where the skillset matures outside of those two primary skill sets. Whichever skillset is lacking when making the transition from traditional delivery patterns over to a more DevOps-focused delivery pattern will need to be picked up to ensure that the team has a complete understanding of the technology stack. A system administrator will not need to become a full software developer, and a software developer will not need to become a veteran system administrator.</p>


<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
</p>



<h2>Role Separation</h2>



<p>First, let&#8217;s dive into role separation.  I am a firm believer in specialization in job functions.  Someone who is a jack of all trades is also generally not a master at any of them.  Individuals on the team should not be looking to be a master at every part of their delivery pipeline but they should be in a position where they are picking up adjacent skills to help backup their team members when needed.  A software developer does not need to be intimately familiar with every intricate detail of a backup solution but should know how to retrieve and restore backups when necessary.  A system administrator does not need to dive deeply into SQL query optimization, but knowing how to write and retrieve data from the database is a useful skill to help support the team.</p>



<h2>Software Development</h2>



<p>Now, this is a bit of an unfair section because I believe that the software development side of DevOps does need a coding background.  How are you going to do software development without that?</p>



<p>In all seriousness, I believe the question &#8220;Do DevOps engineers need a coding background?&#8221; can be extended into the Ops and Infrastructure space pretty easily.  Software developers should be familiar with the basic fundamentals of a data center or cloud depending on where your solution(s) is/are hosted.  If you are in a data center, become familiar with fault domains, SANs, LUNs, or anything that may impact the stability or performance of your application.  In the cloud, become familiar with the cloud&#8217;s elastic nature of volumes, instances, and services.</p>



<p>Along with the familiarity with computing platforms, it will be advantageous to also familiarize yourself with solution delivery and system configuration.  Solution delivery and delivery pipelines are essential to a good DevOps background.  In my experience, most developers are really good at utilizing their ecosystems to compile a binary or build out a package.  Aside from SFTPing that package out to a server and bouncing a service the idea of automated blue/green solution delivery flow with configuration management, rollbacks,  database updates, monitoring changes, etc. is not the norm.  </p>



<p>You SFTPers out there know who you are, don&#8217;t try to deny it.</p>



<p>The primary driver behind configuration management is trying to hit the gold standard of immutable infrastructure.  While application code is being perpetually updated and changed, servers should be treated like cattle instead of pets.  We should be able to easily destroy and fully rebuild a server and deploy the newest version of the application on top of it.  This helps keep things clean and up to date.</p>



<h2>System Administrators</h2>



<p>As system administrators make the transition from the GUI to doing DevOps, they will be faced with many challenges where a coding background can really help out.  </p>



<p>DevOps is all about automating the flow of delivery through resilient pipelines to increase quality.  To do this, most of your work is going to be through scripts or tools like <a href="https://www.chef.io/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="8" title="Chef">Chef</a>, Terraform, <a href="https://puppet.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="9" title="Puppet">Puppet</a>, CloudFormation, etc.  Composing individual scripts for individual tasks is a good place to start, but will quickly become overwhelming if you are not embracing a more generated approach.  </p>



<p>Now, all teams are going to be set up a bit differently, but a common thread across all of them will be the scale of technology becoming overwhelming at some point.  One day you may be looking at fifteen servers/services and the next day your product explodes in popularity and you are dealing with thousands of servers/services.  Take a step back and ask yourself how you can use business logic to generate your infrastructure, monitoring, configurations, backups solutions, etc.  This approach will make something that feels unmanageable and makes it manageable again.</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>Do DevOps engineers need a coding background?  My perspective is, that it wouldn&#8217;t hurt.  Diving into software development patterns and extending them into the DevOps delivery space allows for greater consistency, along with the ability to scale to meet demand much more quickly without feeling overwhelmed.  I don&#8217;t think that software developers need to become the best systems administrators ever created.  I don&#8217;t think that systems administrators need to become the greatest software developers ever created.  I do think that everyone in technology could benefit from a bit of exposure to spaces outside of their primary responsibilities because it lends itself well to increasing quality and flexibility while delivering solutions.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why are CI/CD Pipelines Part of DevOps?</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/why-are-ci-cd-pipelines-part-of-devops/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 16:47:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sdlc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=312</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[CI/CD pipelines are a key part of the DevOps process. They allow you to automate the process of getting your code from development to production through CI/CD. CI/CD stands for Continuous Integration and Continuous Deployment. This helps to speed up&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>CI/CD pipelines are a key part of the DevOps process. They allow you to automate the process of getting your code from development to production through CI/CD.  CI/CD stands for Continuous Integration and Continuous Deployment. This helps to speed up the process and ensure that your code is always in a ready-to-deploy state. There are a number of different tools that you can use for creating DevOps pipelines. You can think of it like an assembly line where technology components and quality checks and gates are passed on the way to production. A more apt analogy would be the assembly line in the manufacturing industry where physical products are made. Think of a car made of parts going down a conveyor belt to different stations where it is assembled. A DevOps pipeline is kind of like that. But instead of cars, DevOps pipelines are for software and applications. And instead of physical parts, they are for software components like source code and automated scripts.</p>



<p>There are several key parts of the assembly line that must be considered. The key parts of a successful DevOps pipeline are all continuous; integration, delivery, testing, monitoring, feedback, and operations.</p>


<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
</p>



<h2>The DevOps <s>Assembly Line</s> CI/CD Pipeline</h2>



<h3>Continuous Integration</h3>



<p>Integration is the process whereby all developers make their code changes available to other team members. This is often done using a source code repository and an automated build step. Developers, ops, qa, etc. all contribute to the same process which enhances the same product with everybody moving the same automobile down the assembly line together.</p>



<p>Most organizations have a &#8220;git&#8221; repository that holds all the source code. This can be a private repository, shared publically, or a combination of both. It is commonly referred to as a &#8220;<a href="https://www.github.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="6" title="Github" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">GitHub</a>&#8221; or &#8220;GitLab&#8221; repository. Utilizing feature branching strategies, build or feature flags, and a myriad of other code organization strategies; the code repository becomes the central hub for all work happening in and around the technology product.</p>



<h3>Continuous Delivery</h3>



<p>Delivery is the process whereby the integrated code changes are deployed to a test or production environment. It involves package or container creation, deployment, and feature enablement in a production environment. The overall scope of work is narrowed down from large unwieldy projects to something more complementary to a single bolt being added to a car or truck. In the physical world, those incremental steps are not only performed, but in our modern industrial assembly lines, the impact wrench which is utilized will measure and record the torque applied while the car is being assembled. Continuous delivery is no different. Code should always be ready to be deployed to production because every minor tweak, change, or enhancement is fully tested as it is added to the code repository.</p>



<h3>Continuous Testing</h3>



<p>Testing is the stage where the output of delivery is tested to ensure that it performs as expected in a testing environment. The gold standard here is to ensure that 100% of your application is fully tested on every single commit. Full coverage testing is often used when developing in an agile or Scrum environment, where developers will have small, incremental changes to the code. When modernizing an application where automated testing was not done from the start, you may see much lower percentages as you get your application up to spec. This is OK! Make sure testing is a focus and a breakpoint is added where it no longer becomes acceptable to not test changes.</p>



<h3>Continuous Monitoring and Feedback</h3>



<p>I am going to let you in on a secret, &#8220;humans are not robots&#8221;. This means that we are going to make mistakes. It is just part of the job. Mistakes should always be an acceptable part of the work done in the technology sector. Here is what should really drive people crazy instead of mistakes, not knowing when mistakes were made or when something fails. So, what can we do about it? Simply put, build some observability!</p>



<p>Observability, a common NFR in technology, is the concept that not only should your technology have some up/down state monitoring behind it, but you should be able to also get good telemetry around the full set of business processes as well. Looking at some basic observability items such as activity counters, page performance and event timing, errors, failures, success, etc. you can build a set of observability around key metrics which tell you can line up to show the differences between how you expect your application to be performing versus the reality of how it is performing.</p>



<p>When it comes to Continous Feedback, now that we are in this panacea of speedy and rigorously tested application deployments, we can get this observability feedback into the hands of our DevOps teams to ensure that appropriate changes are put into the application. Without good early feedback supported by a mountain of data, the team will be left guessing. Let’s be honest, everyone on the team needs this feedback. The DevOps team doesn’t need to know everything. They do need to know enough to assess whether or not the changes they make to the application are safe and meet business requirements.</p>



<p>Regardless of whether you’re building a standalone product or a company, the key takeaway here is that you want to be thinking about observability in terms of the business process as a whole paired directly with technology. A car company is not going to set out to produce the next top-of-the-line pickup truck and end up with a Pontiac Aztec unless something goes very wrong while nobody is looking.</p>



<h3>Continuous Operations</h3>



<p>Everyone is responsible for operations. Product Managers, Developers, CEOs, Finance and Accounting, and Operations; everybody shares some role in the responsibility. When it comes to DevOps the role of operations is filtered directly into the central workstreams of the team. When an outage occurs, RCAs and post-mortems do not stop at a ceremonial activity. They are carried through to completion with real changes being put in place. Utilizing all of the aforementioned steps of the assembly line, the DevOps team is able to more quickly remediate issues that either show up due to mistakes or show up due to the growth of a system over time.</p>



<p>One of the core things to remember about operations is that technology does not age well. The longer something is running in the wild, the frailer it will get. Think about it this way; if you never service your car, the engine will start to overheat, your tires will start to go bald, and you may run out of blinker fluid. As time goes on, the car gets more and more unreliable. This is true of any technology as well. Operations needs to be accessible to everyone, and it needs to be prioritized in a way that allows for a healthy mix of feature functionality and operations to coexist.</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>In conclusion, DevOps Pipelines can be easily attributed to an assembly line of technology. Through a set of core principles, like always being ready for production, along with integrated technology which promotes testing, monitoring, feedback, and observability the pipeline approach enables organizations to achieve rapid time-to-market and continuous delivery of software products and services (and they can enjoy the velocity and quality benefits at a fraction of the cost).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Build a DevOps Pipeline Geared for Stability?</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/devops-pipeline-geared-for-stability/</link>
					<comments>https://www.valewood.org/devops-pipeline-geared-for-stability/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 02:47:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sdlc]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=95</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Building a devops pipeline is easy. Wire up a few components, write some scripts, glue on some tests, and add credentials for production, and voila you are DevOps-ing!! Well&#8230; not exactly. In my experience, this is where things usually start,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Building a devops pipeline is easy.  Wire up a few components, write some scripts, glue on some tests, and add credentials for production, and voila you are DevOps-ing!!  Well&#8230; not exactly.  In my experience, this is where things usually start, but will quickly lead to new and additional churn in a delivery cycle which was never intended.  Sometimes that churn goes completely unrecognized simply because the thought of doing DevOps is far better than the idea of not doing DevOps.  Either way, do yourself a favor and take a step back to look into how intentional design, intentional component selection, along with care and feeding can get you into a spot where your pipelines work for you instead of you working for your pipelines.</p>



<p>In case you are wondering, &#8220;what is a pipeline in DevOps&#8221;?  A pipeline in DevOps is centered around the idea of ensuring code is continuously delivered which in turn means the business is seeing a continuous flow of value.  There are many DevOps pipeline tools on the market, but I want to take step back and discuss more of the planning and design side of things before diving directly into tooling.</p>


<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
</p>



<h2>Intentional Design</h2>



<p>Deploying Jenkins, giving it some keys, giving it a job to do, and then finally pointing at production will yield a short-term win with long-term consequences.  While I believe that most aspiring DevOps engineers will start here, more intentional design should be considered when building a pipeline.</p>



<h3>Who are the consumers of your DevOps Pipeline?</h3>



<p>Consider who is going to be consuming the pipeline that is being created.  Some organizations want manual approvals, some want automated approvals, some are a bit more cowboy and approvals are not part of the conversation.  Sometimes a QA team, project/program management, developers, executives, or the lunch lady could be consumers of your pipeline.  Consider them when designing what you will use for delivery.</p>



<h3>What are the goals of your DevOps Pipeline?</h3>



<p>Not everyone is going to agree here, but when I am doing a design, I start by conceptualizing my end state much like pointing a ship in the direction that I think I want to go.  This allows me to get more eyes on the concept that I am building toward while pulling in feedback from interested stakeholders.  On the back of that work, I will take a step back and try to understand the strategic themes and goals of the pipeline to get more broad alignment from the consumers and stakeholders.  </p>



<p>Just because someone tells you that they want something, doesn&#8217;t mean that you heard them correctly or they fully understood what they are asking for.  Try to take time and dissect their request and either align it to your design walking the requestor through how your solution solves their needs, or reframe your specific thinking of the problem to accommodate their request.</p>



<h3>Is there a logical flow you can follow?</h3>



<p>I like to map out my process as illustrated below.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img width="1024" height="204" src="https://www.valewood.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/devops-pipeline-flowchart-1024x204.png" alt="DevOps Pipeline Flowchart" class="wp-image-273" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/devops-pipeline-flowchart-1024x204.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/08/devops-pipeline-flowchart-300x60.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/08/devops-pipeline-flowchart-768x153.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/08/devops-pipeline-flowchart-1536x306.png 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/08/devops-pipeline-flowchart-2048x409.png 2048w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/08/devops-pipeline-flowchart-1920x383.png 1920w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/08/devops-pipeline-flowchart-1170x233.png 1170w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/08/devops-pipeline-flowchart-585x117.png 585w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure></div>


<p>By taking the time to understand the ins and outs of your pipeline, the decision tree that gets created, necessary supplemental steps, and points of failure you can design a logical flow that works across many different arenas.  A single logical flow may work well to get code into a development environment, but do you really need to redo each and every step to move code to the next environment or can you adjust your logical flow to be less cumbersome?</p>



<h2>Intentional Component Selection</h2>



<p>Normally I am not a fan of Jenkins.  I believe that it is allowing for quick and dirty instances of automation to be put out into the market in a way that does not promote stability.  Don&#8217;t get me wrong, Jenkins is an interesting tool if you look at it as a dumb task runner, but is a pretty poor tool if you are really taking automation seriously.  Intentional component selection is a topic we should spend some time on due to the technology strongholds that are out in the market today.</p>



<h3>So, who are the consumers of your DevOps Pipeline?</h3>



<p>No no, this section is not a duplicate.  When choosing your components, you need to consider your consumers.  Luckily, most of your consumers in this space are going to be technology focused so we can hopefully ignore non-technical actors for the most part.  If your team is primarily composed of PHP developers, it is probably not a good idea to try and pull in something which is well outside of the PHP ecosystem.  Stick with tools that are similar to other existing tools in your environment.</p>



<p>Providing good feedback to your engineers is also something you should pay attention to.  If your pipeline does happen to break for one reason or another, and the error messages are cryptic, you will end up in the &#8220;You built it you own it&#8221; paradigm.  There is no democratization of the pipeline out to consumers to facilitate care and feeding, which we will discuss later.  A good DevOps pipeline should support your engineers, not be an exercise in decoding the enigma machine.</p>



<h3>Perfection is the enemy of progress!</h3>



<p>Component selections can be a long drawn-out process.  Spending too much time trying to decide will lead to the projects around you getting too far ahead of your efforts causing a lot of undo stress and rework.  It is better to pick something and prove why it won&#8217;t work over time instead of trying to find the magical purple unicorn which solves 200% of use cases.</p>



<h3>Clearly defined single responsibilities!</h3>



<p>To fight perfection shutting down progress, try to limit your components to single responsibilities.  You can really apply <a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/community/conceptual_articles/s-o-l-i-d-the-first-five-principles-of-object-oriented-design" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SOLID OOD</a> can really be applied anywhere in technology.  By limiting your components to a single responsibility, you can set up your components as interfaces with each other.  Component 1 expects this input and provides this output.  The magic between input and output can be as complex as you want it to be as long as the inputs and outputs are consistent.  You can then feed the outputs of component 1 into the inputs of component 2.  Continue this pattern for N components.</p>



<p>What you end up with is a set of &#8220;jobs&#8221; which facilitate specific tasks.  Each of these jobs is testable, improvable, observable, and most importantly; your jobs are understandable!  If you want to break free from &#8220;you built it, you own it&#8221; then everything in your stack should be something that can be handed off to another flesh and blood human being who can pick up your work and run with it.</p>



<h2>Care and Feeding</h2>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignright size-medium is-resized"><img src="https://www.valewood.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/amanda-lim-n0s7y7Nr2A-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="Care and Feeding (Not a real picture of the Ron Popeil Rotisserie)" class="wp-image-278" width="133" height="198" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/amanda-lim-n0s7y7Nr2A-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/08/amanda-lim-n0s7y7Nr2A-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 133px) 100vw, 133px" /></figure></div>


<p>Any technology anywhere will need care and feeding.  There is nothing that can be built and just runs like a perpetual motion machine.  You will need to consider the care and feeding of your DevOps pipeline.  Some of the care and feeding will be simple.  Password rotations, library updates, edge case fixes, etc. can all be accomplished as part of the daily flow of work.  More complex care and feeding such as component replacement, break glass in case of emergency, security hardening, etc. will need to be planned into your delivery lifecycle planning.  </p>



<p>As a quick side tangent, when the term care and feeding comes up as part of normal conversation, does anyone else hear Ron Popeil and his overly excited audience say &#8220;Set it and forget it&#8221;?</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>As you can see, a stable DevOps pipeline will consist of many steps which all feed off of each other ending up in a GitOps-style deployment pipeline.  I believe that the magic in any well-developed, well-set-up DevOps pipeline has a foundation in having a clear definition of your intentions, and intentional components which provide specific functionality, and each component needs attention + care and feeding like any other technology stack that is being supported.  Not every pipeline needs to be as complex, or overly simplistic depending on your frame of reference since there is no one size fits all solution to robust delivery.  Start small, but be intentional and you too can have a DevOps Pipeline Geared for Stability!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.valewood.org/devops-pipeline-geared-for-stability/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Welcome to A DevOoops</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/welcome-to-a-devooops/</link>
					<comments>https://www.valewood.org/welcome-to-a-devooops/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2022 02:36:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fluff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As developers, we are always under the gun to get X feature shipped, or to get Y Sev 1 resolved as quickly as possible. Sometimes in that quest to service our corpo overlords, an Ooops happens in the middle. That&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As developers, we are always under the gun to get X feature shipped, or to get Y Sev 1 resolved as quickly as possible.  Sometimes in that quest to service our corpo overlords, an Ooops happens in the middle.  That is where this blog comes in!  </p>



<p>I want to talk about technology abstracted from the corporate atmosphere.  There are some really cool things going on out there in space of Development and DevOps, and all that coolness rarely sees the light of day.  Let&#8217;s give it some air here and see what happens <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.valewood.org/welcome-to-a-devooops/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
