<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>development &#8211; A DevOps Blog</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/development/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.valewood.org/</link>
	<description>Occasionally a developer makes an Oops!</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 16:47:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.valewood.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/A-DevOoops-1-e1660773390219.png</url>
	<title>development &#8211; A DevOps Blog</title>
	<link>https://www.valewood.org/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Why are CI/CD Pipelines Part of DevOps?</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/why-are-ci-cd-pipelines-part-of-devops/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 16:47:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sdlc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=312</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Introduction CI/CD pipelines are a key part of the DevOps process. They allow you to automate the process of getting your code from development to production through CI/CD. CI/CD stands for Continuous Integration and Continuous Deployment. This helps to speed&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2>Introduction</h2>



<p>CI/CD pipelines are a key part of the DevOps process. They allow you to automate the process of getting your code from development to production through CI/CD.  CI/CD stands for Continuous Integration and Continuous Deployment. This helps to speed up the process and ensure that your code is always in a ready-to-deploy state. There are a number of different tools that you can use for creating DevOps pipelines. You can think of it like an assembly line where technology components and quality checks and gates are passed on the way to production. A more apt analogy would be the assembly line in the manufacturing industry where physical products are made. Think of a car made of parts going down a conveyor belt to different stations where it is assembled. A DevOps pipeline is kind of like that. But instead of cars, DevOps pipelines are for software and applications. And instead of physical parts, they are for software components like source code and automated scripts.</p>



<p>There are several key parts of the assembly line that must be considered. The key parts of a successful DevOps pipeline are all continuous; integration, delivery, testing, monitoring, feedback, and operations.</p>



<h2>The DevOps <s>Assembly Line</s> CI/CD Pipeline</h2>



<h3>Continuous Integration</h3>



<p>Integration is the process whereby all developers make their code changes available to other team members. This is often done using a source code repository and an automated build step. Developers, ops, qa, etc. all contribute to the same process which enhances the same product with everybody moving the same automobile down the assembly line together.</p>



<p>Most organizations have a &#8220;git&#8221; repository that holds all the source code. This can be a private repository, shared publically, or a combination of both. It is commonly referred to as a &#8220;<a href="https://www.github.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="6" title="Github" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">GitHub</a>&#8221; or &#8220;GitLab&#8221; repository. Utilizing feature branching strategies, build or feature flags, and a myriad of other code organization strategies; the code repository becomes the central hub for all work happening in and around the technology product.</p>



<h3>Continuous Delivery</h3>



<p>Delivery is the process whereby the integrated code changes are deployed to a test or production environment. It involves package or container creation, deployment, and feature enablement in a production environment. The overall scope of work is narrowed down from large unwieldy projects to something more complementary to a single bolt being added to a car or truck. In the physical world, those incremental steps are not only performed, but in our modern industrial assembly lines, the impact wrench which is utilized will measure and record the torque applied while the car is being assembled. Continuous delivery is no different. Code should always be ready to be deployed to production because every minor tweak, change, or enhancement is fully tested as it is added to the code repository.</p>



<h3>Continuous Testing</h3>



<p>Testing is the stage where the output of delivery is tested to ensure that it performs as expected in a testing environment. The gold standard here is to ensure that 100% of your application is fully tested on every single commit. Full coverage testing is often used when developing in an agile or Scrum environment, where developers will have small, incremental changes to the code. When modernizing an application where automated testing was not done from the start, you may see much lower percentages as you get your application up to spec. This is OK! Make sure testing is a focus and a breakpoint is added where it no longer becomes acceptable to not test changes.</p>



<h3>Continuous Monitoring and Feedback</h3>



<p>I am going to let you in on a secret, &#8220;humans are not robots&#8221;. This means that we are going to make mistakes. It is just part of the job. Mistakes should always be an acceptable part of the work done in the technology sector. Here is what should really drive people crazy instead of mistakes, not knowing when mistakes were made or when something fails. So, what can we do about it? Simply put, build some observability!</p>



<p>Observability, a common NFR in technology, is the concept that not only should your technology have some up/down state monitoring behind it, but you should be able to also get good telemetry around the full set of business processes as well. Looking at some basic observability items such as activity counters, page performance and event timing, errors, failures, success, etc. you can build a set of observability around key metrics which tell you can line up to show the differences between how you expect your application to be performing versus the reality of how it is performing.</p>



<p>When it comes to Continous Feedback, now that we are in this panacea of speedy and rigorously tested application deployments, we can get this observability feedback into the hands of our DevOps teams to ensure that appropriate changes are put into the application. Without good early feedback supported by a mountain of data, the team will be left guessing. Let’s be honest, everyone on the team needs this feedback. The DevOps team doesn’t need to know everything. They do need to know enough to assess whether or not the changes they make to the application are safe and meet business requirements.</p>



<p>Regardless of whether you’re building a standalone product or a company, the key takeaway here is that you want to be thinking about observability in terms of the business process as a whole paired directly with technology. A car company is not going to set out to produce the next top-of-the-line pickup truck and end up with a Pontiac Aztec unless something goes very wrong while nobody is looking.</p>



<h3>Continuous Operations</h3>



<p>Everyone is responsible for operations. Product Managers, Developers, CEOs, Finance and Accounting, and Operations; everybody shares some role in the responsibility. When it comes to DevOps the role of operations is filtered directly into the central workstreams of the team. When an outage occurs, RCAs and post-mortems do not stop at a ceremonial activity. They are carried through to completion with real changes being put in place. Utilizing all of the aforementioned steps of the assembly line, the DevOps team is able to more quickly remediate issues that either show up due to mistakes or show up due to the growth of a system over time.</p>



<p>One of the core things to remember about operations is that technology does not age well. The longer something is running in the wild, the frailer it will get. Think about it this way; if you never service your car, the engine will start to overheat, your tires will start to go bald, and you may run out of blinker fluid. As time goes on, the car gets more and more unreliable. This is true of any technology as well. Operations needs to be accessible to everyone, and it needs to be prioritized in a way that allows for a healthy mix of feature functionality and operations to coexist.</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>In conclusion, DevOps Pipelines can be easily attributed to an assembly line of technology. Through a set of core principles, like always being ready for production, along with integrated technology which promotes testing, monitoring, feedback, and observability the pipeline approach enables organizations to achieve rapid time-to-market and continuous delivery of software products and services (and they can enjoy the velocity and quality benefits at a fraction of the cost).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Build a DevOps Pipeline Geared for Stability?</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/devops-pipeline-geared-for-stability/</link>
					<comments>/devops-pipeline-geared-for-stability/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 02:47:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sdlc]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=95</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Intro Building a devops pipeline is easy. Wire up a few components, write some scripts, glue on some tests, and add credentials for production, and voila you are DevOps-ing!! Well&#8230; not exactly. In my experience, this is where things usually&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2>Intro</h2>



<p>Building a devops pipeline is easy.  Wire up a few components, write some scripts, glue on some tests, and add credentials for production, and voila you are DevOps-ing!!  Well&#8230; not exactly.  In my experience, this is where things usually start, but will quickly lead to new and additional churn in a delivery cycle which was never intended.  Sometimes that churn goes completely unrecognized simply because the thought of doing DevOps is far better than the idea of not doing DevOps.  Either way, do yourself a favor and take a step back to look into how intentional design, intentional component selection, along with care and feeding can get you into a spot where your pipelines work for you instead of you working for your pipelines.</p>



<p>In case you are wondering, &#8220;what is a pipeline in DevOps&#8221;?  A pipeline in DevOps is centered around the idea of ensuring code is continuously delivered which in turn means the business is seeing a continuous flow of value.  There are many DevOps pipeline tools on the market, but I want to take step back and discuss more of the planning and design side of things before diving directly into tooling.</p>



<h2>Intentional Design</h2>



<p>Deploying Jenkins, giving it some keys, giving it a job to do, and then finally pointing at production will yield a short-term win with long-term consequences.  While I believe that most aspiring DevOps engineers will start here, more intentional design should be considered when building a pipeline.</p>



<h3>Who are the consumers of your DevOps Pipeline?</h3>



<p>Consider who is going to be consuming the pipeline that is being created.  Some organizations want manual approvals, some want automated approvals, some are a bit more cowboy and approvals are not part of the conversation.  Sometimes a QA team, project/program management, developers, executives, or the lunch lady could be consumers of your pipeline.  Consider them when designing what you will use for delivery.</p>



<h3>What are the goals of your DevOps Pipeline?</h3>



<p>Not everyone is going to agree here, but when I am doing a design, I start by conceptualizing my end state much like pointing a ship in the direction that I think I want to go.  This allows me to get more eyes on the concept that I am building toward while pulling in feedback from interested stakeholders.  On the back of that work, I will take a step back and try to understand the strategic themes and goals of the pipeline to get more broad alignment from the consumers and stakeholders.  </p>



<p>Just because someone tells you that they want something, doesn&#8217;t mean that you heard them correctly or they fully understood what they are asking for.  Try to take time and dissect their request and either align it to your design walking the requestor through how your solution solves their needs, or reframe your specific thinking of the problem to accommodate their request.</p>



<h3>Is there a logical flow you can follow?</h3>



<p>I like to map out my process as illustrated below.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img width="1024" height="204" src="https://www.valewood.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/devops-pipeline-flowchart-1024x204.png" alt="DevOps Pipeline Flowchart" class="wp-image-273" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/devops-pipeline-flowchart-1024x204.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/08/devops-pipeline-flowchart-300x60.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/08/devops-pipeline-flowchart-768x153.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/08/devops-pipeline-flowchart-1536x306.png 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/08/devops-pipeline-flowchart-2048x409.png 2048w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/08/devops-pipeline-flowchart-1920x383.png 1920w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/08/devops-pipeline-flowchart-1170x233.png 1170w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/08/devops-pipeline-flowchart-585x117.png 585w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure></div>


<p>By taking the time to understand the ins and outs of your pipeline, the decision tree that gets created, necessary supplemental steps, and points of failure you can design a logical flow that works across many different arenas.  A single logical flow may work well to get code into a development environment, but do you really need to redo each and every step to move code to the next environment or can you adjust your logical flow to be less cumbersome?</p>



<h2>Intentional Component Selection</h2>



<p>Normally I am not a fan of Jenkins.  I believe that it is allowing for quick and dirty instances of automation to be put out into the market in a way that does not promote stability.  Don&#8217;t get me wrong, Jenkins is an interesting tool if you look at it as a dumb task runner, but is a pretty poor tool if you are really taking automation seriously.  Intentional component selection is a topic we should spend some time on due to the technology strongholds that are out in the market today.</p>



<h3>Who are the consumers of your DevOps Pipeline?</h3>



<p>No no, this section is not a duplicate.  When choosing your components, you need to consider your consumers.  Luckily, most of your consumers in this space are going to be technology focused so we can hopefully ignore non-technical actors for the most part.  If your team is primarily composed of PHP developers, it is probably not a good idea to try and pull in something which is well outside of the PHP ecosystem.  Stick with tools that are similar to other existing tools in your environment.</p>



<p>Providing good feedback to your engineers is also something you should pay attention to.  If your pipeline does happen to break for one reason or another, and the error messages are cryptic, you will end up in the &#8220;You built it you own it&#8221; paradigm.  There is no democratization of the pipeline out to consumers to facilitate care and feeding, which we will discuss later.  A good DevOps pipeline should support your engineers, not be an exercise in decoding the enigma machine.</p>



<h3>Perfection is the enemy of progress!</h3>



<p>Component selections can be a long drawn-out process.  Spending too much time trying to decide will lead to the projects around you getting too far ahead of your efforts causing a lot of undo stress and rework.  It is better to pick something and prove why it won&#8217;t work over time instead of trying to find the magical purple unicorn which solves 200% of use cases.</p>



<h3>Clearly defined single responsibilities!</h3>



<p>To fight perfection shutting down progress, try to limit your components to single responsibilities.  You can really apply <a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/community/conceptual_articles/s-o-l-i-d-the-first-five-principles-of-object-oriented-design" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SOLID OOD</a> can really be applied anywhere in technology.  By limiting your components to a single responsibility, you can set up your components as interfaces with each other.  Component 1 expects this input and provides this output.  The magic between input and output can be as complex as you want it to be as long as the inputs and outputs are consistent.  You can then feed the outputs of component 1 into the inputs of component 2.  Continue this pattern for N components.</p>



<p>What you end up with is a set of &#8220;jobs&#8221; which facilitate specific tasks.  Each of these jobs is testable, improvable, observable, and most importantly; your jobs are understandable!  If you want to break free from &#8220;you built it, you own it&#8221; then everything in your stack should be something that can be handed off to another flesh and blood human being who can pick up your work and run with it.</p>



<h2>Care and Feeding</h2>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignright size-medium is-resized"><img src="https://www.valewood.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/amanda-lim-n0s7y7Nr2A-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="Care and Feeding (Not a real picture of the Ron Popeil Rotisserie)" class="wp-image-278" width="133" height="198" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/amanda-lim-n0s7y7Nr2A-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/08/amanda-lim-n0s7y7Nr2A-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 133px) 100vw, 133px" /></figure></div>


<p>Any technology anywhere will need care and feeding.  There is nothing that can be built and just runs like a perpetual motion machine.  You will need to consider the care and feeding of your DevOps pipeline.  Some of the care and feeding will be simple.  Password rotations, library updates, edge case fixes, etc. can all be accomplished as part of the daily flow of work.  More complex care and feeding such as component replacement, break glass in case of emergency, security hardening, etc. will need to be planned into your delivery lifecycle planning.  </p>



<p>As a quick side tangent, when the term care and feeding comes up as part of normal conversation, does anyone else hear Ron Popeil and his overly excited audience say &#8220;Set it and forget it&#8221;?</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>As you can see, a stable DevOps pipeline will consist of many steps which all feed off of each other ending up in a GitOps-style deployment pipeline.  I believe that the magic in any well-developed, well-set-up DevOps pipeline has a foundation in having a clear definition of your intentions, and intentional components which provide specific functionality, and each component needs attention + care and feeding like any other technology stack that is being supported.  Not every pipeline needs to be as complex, or overly simplistic depending on your frame of reference since there is no one size fits all solution to robust delivery.  Start small, but be intentional and you too can have a DevOps Pipeline Geared for Stability!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/devops-pipeline-geared-for-stability/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Welcome to A DevOoops</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/welcome-to-a-devooops/</link>
					<comments>/welcome-to-a-devooops/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2022 02:36:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fluff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As developers, we are always under the gun to get X feature shipped, or to get Y Sev 1 resolved as quickly as possible. Sometimes in that quest to service our corpo overlords, an Ooops happens in the middle. That&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As developers, we are always under the gun to get X feature shipped, or to get Y Sev 1 resolved as quickly as possible.  Sometimes in that quest to service our corpo overlords, an Ooops happens in the middle.  That is where this blog comes in!  </p>



<p>I want to talk about technology abstracted from the corporate atmosphere.  There are some really cool things going on out there in space of Development and DevOps, and all that coolness rarely sees the light of day.  Let&#8217;s give it some air here and see what happens <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/welcome-to-a-devooops/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
