<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>DevOps &#8211; A DevOps Blog</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.valewood.org/devops/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.valewood.org/</link>
	<description>Occasionally a developer makes an Ops!</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 01:17:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.valewood.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/A-DevOoops-1-e1660773390219.png</url>
	<title>DevOps &#8211; A DevOps Blog</title>
	<link>https://www.valewood.org/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Which Term Accurately Describes Agile and DevOps?</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/which-term-describes-devops-and-agile/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 22:20:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opinion]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1796</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[DevOps is a culture and methodology that an organization can prescribe to aid in velocity, consistency, stability, and flow of value to the market. Often confused with &#8220;automation&#8221; being the only benefit of DevOps, the core principles behind DevOps offer&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> is a culture and methodology that an organization can prescribe to aid in velocity, consistency, stability, and flow of value to the market.  Often confused with &#8220;automation&#8221; being the only benefit of DevOps, the core principles behind DevOps offer a common set of ideals that a team can align under and strive to achieve.</p>



<p>Big A Agile is a project management methodology that pairs well with DevOps to aid in rationalizing work delivery against a set of guardrails.  Agile also provides prescriptive visibility to work being performed ensuring engineers are not being overloaded by overwhelming business priorities.</p>



<p>With those descriptions out of the way, what term best describes both Agile and DevOps?</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Consistency</h2>



<p>The goal of any organization going through change is to drive consistency in delivery.  Without consistency, a technology group cannot adapt to change and a business cannot meet the market where it is at.  </p>



<p>By driving consistency, a business gets predictability which is powerful when scoping and planning new work.  By understanding real velocity, not aspirational velocity, a business can invest in its people and products to grow at a more sustainable rate.</p>



<p>By driving consistency, technologists get the predictability that they need to make sound and rational decisions about how to approach work.  When working against an unpredictable cycle, technology groups will quickly get overwhelmed by the rate of change and produce solutions that do not meet the demands of the market.</p>



<h3>Real Velocity vs Aspirational Velocity</h3>



<p>Aspirational velocity is when a leader says &#8220;We need this product to launch by X date!&#8221;.  We have either all been in that position or will be in that position sometime in our careers.</p>



<p>Without proper support, investment, and foresight in planning; aspirational velocity will almost always end with sub-standard products that greatly increase the future cost to the business.  Leaning harder on anyone in the delivery space always leads to decisions that are short-sighted toward a narrow goal.</p>



<p>I believe aspirational velocity is firmly rooted in the idea of needing to &#8220;take a shot&#8221;.  Checks are constantly being written that others are expected to cash.  Sometimes this works out and I would say can be necessary for a startup or green field project.  Any organization looking to grow over time should be looking for its tipping point when aspirational velocity needs to transition into real velocity to offer a more reliable work environment for their employees.</p>



<p>Real velocity is based on the idea that you are going to make hard choices about which work is important to feed into a model where delivery is consistent.  When more work needs to be done than can be achieved by the current velocity, hard choices will be made to cut work, increase staff, defer work, or invest in current technology to increase velocity.  </p>



<p>Any business should have a firm goal of understanding its real velocity and do everything in its power to tamp down or extinguish aspirational velocity.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>DevOps and Agile are Closely Related</h2>



<p>I have another article that describes how DevOps and Agile are related to each other.  Primarily, Agile is about lean work being performed against targets and goals with frequent demos of the work being completed to influence pivots.  Agile was in need of a technology delivery methodology that could help realize the fundamental mission of Agile. </p>



<p>You can read more about how <a href="https://www.valewood.org/devops-and-agile/" data-type="post" data-id="1264">DevOps and Agile are related here!</a></p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>The key to any technology product&#8217;s success is consistency.  DevOps and Agile offer that consistency while remaining flexible and focused on common non-functional requirements like reliability and stability.  How would you boil DevOps and Agile down to a single term?  <a href="https://www.valewood.org/contact/" data-type="page" data-id="984">Contact me</a> and let me know!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why DevOps is Boring in 2022?</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/more-like-boringops/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 18:04:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[delivery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1786</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[DevOps is a hot topic in the technology world. It&#8217;s no longer just an isolated set of tools and processes which promise an automated future, it’s an entire culture that’s infiltrating every facet of software development. This post will try&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> is a hot topic in the technology world. It&#8217;s no longer just an isolated set of tools and processes which promise an automated future, it’s an entire culture that’s infiltrating every facet of software development.</p>



<p>This post will try to explain why the DevOps methodology itself is not boring.  We will also try to explain why a feeling of boredom stems from properly implemented tools and processes. We also dive into how you can make DevOps more exciting while keeping your sanity intact.</p>



<p>There are plenty of posts out there already which try to tackle this question:</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/cscareerquestions/comments/9zn25a/after_a_few_years_devops_gets_super_boring/" data-type="URL" data-id="https://www.reddit.com/r/cscareerquestions/comments/9zn25a/after_a_few_years_devops_gets_super_boring/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Reddit</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.quora.com/Do-you-like-DevOps-work-Is-it-boring-or-interesting" data-type="URL" data-id="https://www.quora.com/Do-you-like-DevOps-work-Is-it-boring-or-interesting" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Quora</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.zippia.com/answers/is-devops-a-boring-job/" data-type="URL" data-id="https://www.zippia.com/answers/is-devops-a-boring-job/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Zippa</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.fishbowlapp.com/post/is-devops-a-boring-job-what-are-the-pros-and-cons" data-type="URL" data-id="https://www.fishbowlapp.com/post/is-devops-a-boring-job-what-are-the-pros-and-cons" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Fishbowl</a></li>
</ul>



<p>I don&#8217;t think any of these links have gotten it right.  DevOps, if adopted completely, is meant to be boring due to the <a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/benefits-of-devops/consistency/" data-type="page" data-id="1734">stability and consistency</a> that DevOps brings.  Let&#8217;s explore why this happens and what you can do about it below!</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>What Does DevOps Mean?</h2>



<p>The term DevOps, or “development operations,” first appeared in the tech world in the early 2000s. It was a term used to describe a certain type of organization that was responsible for the entire application and software development lifecycle, from ideation to production.</p>



<p>Teams would be responsible for both the development and operations workflows, providing a more efficient way of working. As DevOps has grown in popularity, it has expanded beyond just operations teams.</p>



<p>Now, people are interested in speeding up their software development process using the term DevOps to describe the combined usage of infrastructure automation tools and best practices for team collaboration and communication.</p>



<p>There are two main components within DevOps that drive the culture. They are infrastructure as code and automated delivery. IaC is really just a way of organizing your code and infrastructure so that it is easily reproducible and shareable. Automated delivery is a method for automatically deploying applications and configurations without human intervention.</p>



<p>With the increase in automation, engineers may find themselves wondering when the next exciting change event may present itself. They may also wonder if they are automating themselves out of a job.</p>



<p>As a basis for understanding DevOps, you must understand that this practice exists to remove the excitement of a chaotic technology delivery process. DevOps is meant to be boring by nature.</p>



<p>As a side effect of DevOps being stable and consistent, organizations must look for other ways to keep their software engineers and DevOps engineers engaged through other means of excitement.</p>



<h2>Why is DevOps Boring?</h2>



<p>As companies begin implementing modern DevOps practices, some people may notice a lull in excitement. The tools, processes, and overall culture of DevOps may feel exciting at first but quickly turn into monotony. Why?</p>



<p>DevOps becomes boring because people approach it as a checklist. They focus on the tools and processes and completely ignore the culture and mindset that lies behind the methodology.</p>



<p>These people don’t understand why they are implementing certain tools or why they are following specific processes. They are just doing it because they read an article that said their company should be adopting DevOps, or they read a book that talked about the “predictable flow of value”.</p>



<p>What makes DevOps exciting is the culture behind it. The practices and tools are just the means of achieving a certain culture. If you try to implement DevOps but don’t adopt the correct mindset and culture behind it, then you are going to end up with a boring and ineffective implementation.</p>



<h3>Fewer Natural Learning and Growth Opportunities</h3>



<p>A stable DevOps lifecycle will inherently bring a lower number of emerging technologies and opportunities to integrate emerging technologies. Sure, early on in DevOps adoption, the emerging tech will be all the rage, but that will subside as stability and consistency are driven into the pipeline.</p>



<p>Since continuous improvement is a fundamental principle of DevOps, teams should be encouraged to do some data-driven analysis looking for opportunities to become more efficient in their delivery cycles.</p>



<p>Pivots can also be made within the team. Someone who is primarily focused on ops should be put in a position to both share what they are doing and also be presented with opportunities to look at other fields like coding or security. This is true for all specialties that make up a function DevOps team.</p>



<h3>Comfort in Previous Success</h3>



<p>All too often, I see companies in the industry falling back on the comfort of their successes as an excuse to not rapidly evolve. DevOps should be putting companies in a position where pivots are much easier to pull off. Secondarily keeping a DNA of being lean and nimble should be a focus of any company.</p>



<p>Any company sitting back on its heels thinking it can keep doing what they are doing forever is going to be consumed by its competitors operating at a different level. Break that cycle by listening to the opportunities being presented by your DevOps Engineers and your Software Engineers to keep DevOps from becoming boring and your company from stagnating.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Make DevOps Exciting Again!</h2>



<p>We’ve covered why DevOps can become boring, but what can you do about it? If you want to make DevOps exciting again, then you have to understand why it is exciting in the first place!</p>



<p>The reason DevOps is exciting for most companies is because of the focus on drastically improving your software development process. It’s a way of improving communication, collaboration, and the overall quality of your software. It’s a way of adopting a culture of automation.</p>



<p>Automation is important in DevOps because it directly impacts the speed of your software release cycles. It can also help improve the overall quality of your software as well as your organization.</p>



<p>Automation is a core component of DevOps. When you make automation a core part of your development process, you are able to reduce the number of repetitive tasks your organization has to perform. This means you can put less focus on manual tasks, and more focus on things that actually improve your software and the company as a whole.</p>



<h3>Provide Growth Opportunities</h3>



<p>Some companies confuse growth with &#8220;opportunities to become a manager&#8221;. Most of the really good engineers and architects that I have met will &#8220;manage&#8221; a project because they want to see it succeed not because they want to be a manager.</p>



<p>Providing opportunities for growth in knowledge, automation, systems, development, operations, platforms, consulting, or any other area that your services or products may not be fully taking advantage of today.</p>



<p>As an example, if you have an awesome set of pipelines that obfuscate some of the complexities of doing automated delivery, challenge your team to package that up and white-label it. Have them use those packages to consult with other teams in your organization to level their automation skills up.</p>



<h3>Inject Failures</h3>



<p>We are always focused on delivering key projects, functionality, or needs of the business. With a narrow view of the world being delivered first, that does not leave a lot of room to poke at the softer edges of your products.</p>



<p>Introduce automated failure models like a chaos monkey. Start with planned times and have your chaos monkey start to take down some low criticality services and review the characteristics of what that means. There may be impacts in areas that you were not expecting.</p>



<p>This provides an opportunity to add some advanced troubleshooting to an area that the DevOps methodology took away through its inherent consistency and stability.</p>



<h2>A Culture of Automation and Continuous Improvement</h2>



<p>The two main components of DevOps &#8211; automation and continuous improvement &#8211; are closely related. Both are part of the core values of DevOps and are critical to the success of the culture overall.</p>



<p>If you want to truly adopt a culture of continuous improvement, you need to make sure that your team is constantly learning and improving their knowledge. This means your team should be continually looking for new books, podcasts, and ways that they can expand their skill set, improve their knowledge, and learn new things.</p>



<p>You should encourage your team to read books, attend conferences, and listen to podcasts so they can keep up with the latest trends in technology. This can also help them discover new topics they are interested in and allow them to find new ways of applying their skills to different areas of business.</p>



<h2>Continuously Test Features and New Releases</h2>



<p>As you work to improve your software, you will eventually want to release new features and functionality to your customers. But before you do, you need to ensure that the new features work exactly as they should.</p>



<p>Therefore, you need to implement a strategy for continuously testing new releases and features. You need to do this across multiple stages in your software development lifecycle.</p>



<p>The first stage is called continuous integration, where you build and test new features as soon as developers create them.</p>



<p>The second stage is continuous delivery, where you get the OK to release the new features to internal users and then finally to customers.</p>



<p>You want to make sure you are using the same automated tools and processes across every stage so you don’t have to start from scratch when you get to the next stage.</p>



<h2>Incorporate User Feedback Into DevOps Processes</h2>



<p>User feedback is important to any business because it allows you to understand your customers and discover ways to improve your product. However, user feedback is hard to come by because customers don’t usually interact with businesses on a consistent basis.</p>



<p>In order to incorporate user feedback into your software development lifecycle, you need to be able to get consistent feedback from customers. There are two main ways to do this:</p>



<ul>
<li>Use survey tools to let customers provide feedback on your product, team, and company.</li>



<li>Let customers interact with your team using live chat tools.</li>
</ul>



<p>Both of these tools are easy to implement and can help you get useful and consistent feedback from customers.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>DevOps is not boring. It is an exciting change in the way that organizations approach software development. However, it is only exciting if you fully commit to the culture of DevOps and all the benefits it has to offer.</p>



<p>If you just implement the tools and processes without the culture and mindset, then you are only doing half the work and missing out on the benefits of the fully implemented DevOps culture.</p>



<p>If you want to make DevOps exciting again, you must ensure that you are fully committed to the culture. Only then will you be able to make the most of everything that DevOps has to offer.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>DevOps Cycle Times: The Difference Between Good and Bad Performance</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/devops-cycle-time/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 14:12:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops cycle time]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sdlc]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1700</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The performance of the DevOps cycle is a crucial measure of your success. If it’s good, you are on track to meet your objectives; if it’s bad, you need to make some changes. The DevOps cycle performance has three main&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The performance of the <a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> cycle is a crucial measure of your success. If it’s good, you are on track to meet your objectives; if it’s bad, you need to make some changes. The DevOps cycle performance has three main factors: lead time, cycle time, and throughput.</p>



<p>You can use these metrics to inform your team about where there may be issues in your process that need addressing. Each of these factors indicates a different part of the DevOps cycle:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Lead time</strong> refers to the total length of time from when an order is placed until it is sent out for delivery.</li>



<li><strong>Cycle time</strong> is how long it takes from when a new version of code is checked in to when it becomes available for production users. It measures how much time elapses between every phase of production and points out potential bottlenecks in your process.</li>



<li><strong>Throughput</strong> measures how many units are produced within a specific timeframe (e.g., the number of orders per hour).</li>
</ul>



<p>When monitoring the performance of these metrics, it is important to keep them balanced across all three categories; if one value falls too low or high, adjustments may need to be made.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Lead Time</h2>



<p>The lead time is the length of time it takes from when an order is placed until it is sent out for delivery. To improve this, you can look at two aspects of your process: Shipping and Demand management.</p>



<p>If shipping is taking a long time, check that your team is following a strict process for shipping that is as streamlined as possible. This way, it will be much easier to track and make improvements. If demand management is the issue, you might need to review your sales strategy.</p>



<p>How many orders are being placed per day is the first thing to look at. If demand is low, you can consider ways to increase it, such as marketing campaigns. If orders are high, you might have trouble meeting them due to the length of time it takes to process them. If it is taking a long time to fulfill orders, you can use a kanban board to track them and make sure they don’t get stuck in the process.</p>



<h2>Cycle Time</h2>



<p>Cycle time is the time it takes from when a new version of code is checked in to when that code becomes available for production users. It measures how much time elapses between every phase of production and points out potential bottlenecks in your process.</p>



<p>To improve this, you can look at two aspects of your process: Code deployment and Testing. If it is taking a long time to deploy code, check the tools you are using; they may not be working as efficiently as they could. If testing is taking too long, you might need to add more resources to your testing team.</p>



<h2>Throughput</h2>



<p>Throughput is the number of units produced within a specific timeframe. If throughput is low, you may have too high a lead time for your cycle time. This can be corrected by improving your shipping process or by reducing the time it takes to produce the product.</p>



<p>If throughput is high, you may have too low a cycle time for your lead time. This can be corrected by reducing the time it takes to produce the product or by increasing the time it takes to send it out.</p>



<h2>Continuous Improvement Strategies</h2>



<p>There are several strategies you can employ to improve the efficiency of your DevOps cycle, including:</p>



<ul>
<li>Reducing the time it takes to complete all processes, such as testing and deployment.</li>



<li>Reallocating employees to where they are needed most, such as adding more people to your testing team if testing is taking too long.</li>



<li>Streamlining processes, such as using a kanban board to improve visibility and reduce bottlenecks.</li>



<li>Improving software quality, such as using automated tests and code reviews to catch issues early.</li>



<li>Improving your customer experience, such as tracking customer complaints and addressing them promptly.</li>
</ul>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>The performance of the DevOps cycle is a crucial measure of your success. If it’s good, you are on track to meet your objectives; if it’s bad, you need to make some changes. The DevOps cycle performance has three main factors: lead time, cycle time, and throughput.</p>



<p>You can use these metrics to inform your team about where there may be issues in your process that need addressing. Each of these factors indicates a different part of the DevOps cycle:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Lead time </strong>refers to the total length of time from when an order is placed until it is sent out for delivery.</li>



<li><strong>Cycle time</strong> is how long it takes from when a new version of code is checked in to when it becomes available for production users. It measures how much time elapses between every phase of production and points out potential bottlenecks in your process.</li>



<li><strong>Throughput</strong> measures how many units are produced within a specific timeframe (e.g., the number of orders per hour).</li>
</ul>



<p>When monitoring the performance of these metrics, it is important to keep them balanced across all three categories; if one value falls too low or high, adjustments may need to be made.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Importance of Constant Monitoring and Feedback</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/devops-monitoring/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2022 20:39:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[day2ops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops monitoring and feedback]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tools]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1674</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[DevOps is an approach to software development and operation, where teams are able to collaborate more effectively and accelerate software releases from development to production. As a result, organizations can release new features faster and with higher quality. The need&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> is an approach to software development and operation, where teams are able to collaborate more effectively and accelerate software releases from development to production. As a result, organizations can release new features faster and with higher quality.</p>



<p>The need for speed and collaboration across departments is what’s driving many organizations toward DevOps. But it’s not just about faster software releases; it’s about releasing better software faster by enabling the people who build and support applications (known as operators) to react to changing conditions quickly, proactively, and directly.</p>



<p>In this blog post, we will discuss why monitoring and feedback are critical in accelerating your path toward DevOps while maintaining your company’s high standards for quality.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>What is DevOps?</h2>



<p>DevOps is a set of principles and practices that promotes collaboration between software developers and Operations engineers/IT professionals. It is a cultural change that advocates for a focus on automation, continuous testing, and bringing software development and IT operations together so that you create a more stable application environment.</p>



<p>Because the application lifecycle is shorter, it makes the need for monitoring even more important. Monitoring provides visibility into the application environment and alerts when things are not running as expected. Achieving the right balance between operational efficiency and customer experience is key in the DevOps world. DevOps is a journey and not a destination.</p>



<p>You are always improving and tweaking. The organizations that truly embrace DevOps culture are the ones that see the most benefits. Companies that have a strong engineering culture, a high bar for quality, and a strong set of values are the organizations that have the best chance of succeeding in the DevOps world.</p>



<h2>The Importance of Monitoring in a DevOps Environment</h2>



<p>As we’ve discussed, there are many benefits to implementing a DevOps model versus a traditional software development lifecycle. But what exactly does monitoring have to do with DevOps? It’s no coincidence that monitoring is one of the core components of DevOps.</p>



<p>The mere act of monitoring software, infrastructure, and network performance is the important first step in taking advantage of the benefits of DevOps. And when you’re monitoring, you’re also able to analyze and gain insight into your current state based on real-time data.</p>



<p>While companies are in the process of implementing a DevOps approach, monitoring becomes even more important as it can help you identify potential bottlenecks in your software delivery pipeline.</p>



<h2>Why is Monitoring so Important in a DevOps Environment?</h2>



<p>All organizations should be monitoring their software and the underlying infrastructure on which their applications run. But when you’re implementing a DevOps approach, monitoring becomes even more important because it provides visibility into the application environment and alerts when things are not running as expected.</p>



<p>With a traditional software development lifecycle, engineers would build the application, test it, and then push it out to a staging server environment where operations professionals would monitor it to make sure it’s up and running. When the app was determined to be good to go, the operations team would then push it out to production.</p>



<p>In a DevOps environment, the handoff between development and operations happens much more frequently. In some cases, developers may be responsible for deploying to production or at the very least, testing their code on staging servers before operations engineers deploy it to production.</p>



<h2>Benefits of monitoring in a DevOps environment</h2>



<ul>
<li><strong>Increased insight into the current state: </strong>Monitoring gives you the ability to see and understand the current state of your applications, network, and infrastructure. Without monitoring, you would have no visibility into the current state, which makes it more difficult to identify issues and resolve them.</li>



<li><strong>Sensitivity to application issues: </strong>When you’re monitoring, you’re able to quickly detect issues, both big and small, that disrupt the flow of your business. This includes issues such as a website or app outage, poor performance, increased latency, security issues, and more.</li>



<li><strong>Ability to resolve issues quickly: </strong>When monitoring is part of your software delivery pipeline and you’re able to recognize and resolve issues quickly, you’re able to decrease the amount of time it takes to restore normal operations.</li>



<li><strong>Predictability: </strong>Monitoring also gives you the ability to predict what will happen next, which can be helpful when planning for upcoming events such as conferences or holidays. By understanding the current state, you can predict what might happen next and prepare for it.</li>
</ul>



<h2>Monitor constantly to understand the current state continuously</h2>



<h3>Machine Data</h3>



<p>Data points that are generated and collected by application and infrastructure monitoring tools are known as machine data. Machine data is a fantastic source of data to understand the current state of your applications. Machine data is generated and collected at the application level, which gives you an accurate representation of what is happening in your environment.</p>



<h3>Human-Generated Data</h3>



<p>As you’re monitoring, you also capture human-generated data, which is data that is entered into the system manually. For example, if you receive a ticket about a performance issue, this would be recorded as human-generated data. Although human-generated data is not as accurate as machine data, it gives insight into what is happening in the application environment.</p>



<h2>Monitor constantly to understand why something happened</h2>



<p>Monitoring gives you the ability to understand why something happened, which can be beneficial when it comes to debugging issues and resolving them quickly.</p>



<h3>Application Logs</h3>



<p>Application logs are a fantastic source of why something happened because they show a timeline of events. This can help you identify bottlenecks in your application, when various events occur, when errors are thrown, and much more.</p>



<h3>Tracing</h3>



<p>Tracing is another source of why something happened. Tracing is a way to visualize the path that packets take as they move through the network. This can be helpful if you notice something in the application logs, but you’re not sure where the problem is.</p>



<h2>Monitor Constantly to Predict What Will Happen Next</h2>



<p>Monitoring gives you the ability to predict what will happen next by giving you insight into the current state as well as why certain things happened. This can be helpful when planning for upcoming events such as conferences or holidays.</p>



<h3>Application Performance</h3>



<p>By understanding the current state, you can predict what will happen next with application performance. This can help you proactively prepare for upcoming events that require a heavier lift, such as sales or Black Friday events.</p>



<h3>Network Performance</h3>



<p>Monitoring also allows you to understand the current state of network performance. This can help you predict what will happen next by allowing you to proactively prepare for higher levels of network traffic.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>Monitoring is one of the core components of DevOps and is the important first step in taking advantage of the benefits of DevOps. By implementing a DevOps approach, monitoring becomes even more important because it provides visibility into the application environment and alerts when things are not running as expected.</p>



<p>Machine data is a fantastic source of data to understand the current state of your applications. Monitoring also gives you the ability to understand why something happened, which can help you debug issues and predict what will happen next.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Achieve Rapid Application Delivery with DevOps</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/devops-rapid-delivery/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greer Shepherd]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2022 20:19:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sdlc]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1668</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[DevOps has become a powerful set of tools, processes, and cultural norms for improving the deployment and operation of the software. As businesses grow more reliant on software applications, DevOps becomes even more important as it aids in accelerating the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> has become a powerful set of tools, processes, and cultural norms for improving the deployment and operation of the software. As businesses grow more reliant on software applications, DevOps becomes even more important as it aids in accelerating the delivery of new features to production.</p>



<p>Instead of relying on lengthy manual processes or testing stages to release updates, DevOps helps you streamline your QA process so you can get new features out faster than ever before.</p>



<p>The success of any organization relies on its ability to scale quickly and efficiently react to market demands. The demand for fast-paced change has forced many companies to reevaluate their current operational strategies. In response, organizations are now adopting a new culture for developing software and continuous integration processes that support rapid application development and application delivery cycles.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>The Benefits of DevOps in Software Development</h2>



<p>DevOps is often used to describe the relationship between software development and operations that have evolved over the last couple of years. The term was first used in The Phoenix Project, a novel about bringing together IT and business leaders to fix a failing production system. It’s an abbreviation of “software development” and “operations”.</p>



<p>Its main goal is to get better collaboration between IT departments and software development teams. The DevOps movement gained momentum in the 2010s, as organizations looked for ways to improve application deployment and management while meeting growing customer demands.</p>



<p>The software development process includes several stages, like planning, designing, and testing the product. In an Agile project, these stages happen in very short iterations, and organizations work in a continuous flow. DevOps is the way of organizing work at scale and is about breaking down silos between teams and finding ways for them to work more closely together.</p>



<p>Rapid application development is also an early cornerstone in any kind of digital transformation.</p>



<h2>Continuous Integration in DevOps</h2>



<p>The ability to test new code is a key component for DevOps to work effectively. Continuous integration (CI) is the practice of integrating new code with existing code on a frequent basis. CI triggers the creation of new versions of software after every new code deployment.</p>



<p>Modules are integrated with other modules based on their dependency relationships. By using automated CI tools, developers can continuously test code against a production-like environment while they are responsible for writing code.</p>



<h2>Continuous Delivery in DevOps</h2>



<p>Organizations that have embraced CI are now looking to accelerate the deployment process further by implementing continuous delivery (CD). CD can be described as the automation of the entire delivery process. It includes automating the build and test process, setting up the necessary infrastructure, and using a deployment tool to deploy new application versions to production.</p>



<h2>Continuous Testing in DevOps</h2>



<p>Finally, continuous testing is the practice of the entire software development and testing team executing automated tests together. It is achieved through the use of CI tools that allow the team to run tests against the code and infrastructure in a single console.</p>



<p>By adopting CI/CD and embracing a DevOps culture, companies can reduce the time it takes to deliver new features to customers by 50 percent, according to research by CA Technologies.</p>



<h2>What is Rapid Application Delivery?</h2>



<p>Rapid application delivery is the practice of producing, testing, and deploying applications quickly from ideation to implementation — usually within days or even hours, rather than months or even years.</p>



<p>The point of it all is to speed up the entire software development process, with the ultimate goal of helping businesses bring their products or services to market faster. Organizations that are able to rapidly deliver new applications can respond more quickly to market conditions and customer needs, and therefore retain a competitive advantage.</p>



<h2>Why is Application Delivery Speed Important?</h2>



<p>Fast delivery of new applications is critical to keeping up with customer expectations and staying ahead of competitors. In today&#8217;s business environment, customers want goods and services faster than ever before. Consumers expect to be able to click a button and have their goods delivered to their doorsteps in just a few days.</p>



<p>Rapid application development means you can meet these expectations of speed and customer service. If you’re able to bring a new product or service to market quickly, you can generate greater revenue than if your offerings are delayed by months or even longer.</p>



<p>Speed is a major factor in customer decision-making. Moreover, if you’re behind the curve, you’ll most likely be out-competed by other companies that are able to get products or services to market quicker than you. If you’re slower than your competitors, you could lose market share and customers, which could damage your brand and profitability.</p>



<h2>Benefits of Rapid Delivery</h2>



<p>If you’re able to deliver apps quickly, you’ll see benefits in many areas, including the following:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Higher Revenue:</strong> If you’re able to get products or services to market faster, you’ll be able to generate more revenue than if your offerings are delayed by months or years.</li>



<li><strong>Increased Brand Awareness: </strong>If you’re able to get products or services to market faster, you’ll be able to increase brand awareness, which can help you to grow your customer base.</li>



<li><strong>Improved Customer Engagement:</strong> More rapid app delivery means increased customer engagement, which leads to greater customer retention.</li>



<li><strong>Reduced Costs:</strong> By accelerating the software development process and cutting out unnecessary steps, you can reduce costs.</li>
</ul>



<h2>How to Achieve Rapid Application Delivery in the Enterprise</h2>



<p>There are many steps you can take to achieve rapid application delivery in your organization, including the following:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Identify the Business Problem:</strong> Before you do anything else, you have to identify the business problem that you’re trying to solve. What is the company trying to accomplish? Once you know what business problem you’re trying to solve, you can create an application backlog.</li>



<li><strong>Create an Effective Solution: </strong>You must then create an effective solution that will meet the needs of the business problem you’re trying to solve. You can achieve this by using a collaborative approach to software development in order to build an application with input from all stakeholders.</li>



<li><strong>Test the Solution:</strong> The next step is to test the solution to ensure that it will solve the business problem in the way that you intended. You can do this by using automated testing and continuous integration/continuous delivery (CI/CD) to maximize quality control and minimize the time to release.</li>
</ul>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>As businesses grow more reliant on software applications, DevOps becomes even more important as it aids in accelerating the delivery of new features to production. The adoption of DevOps can significantly reduce the time it takes to deliver new features to customers by automating the build, test, and deployment processes. By accelerating the deployment process, DevOps helps organizations meet growing customer demands while reducing risk.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>7 Tips for Landing a DevOps Position Without a Degree</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/devops-without-education/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greer Shepherd]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 21:28:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops resource]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1645</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[DevOps is hot right now. The demand for professionals with the skills to bridge the gap between software development and information technology operations is growing significantly. It’s not difficult to understand why. DevOps is a methodology that optimizes processes, removes&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> is hot right now. The demand for professionals with the skills to bridge the gap between software development and information technology operations is growing significantly.</p>



<p>It’s not difficult to understand why. DevOps is a methodology that optimizes processes, removes barriers, and improves collaboration between software developers and information technology (IT) operations teams. Because of its benefits, it’s becoming an increasingly attractive option for IT professionals who want to stand out from the crowd.</p>



<p>In this blog post, you will learn about the types of roles available in DevOps, how you can land your first DevOps job, and what you need to succeed in your new role as a DevOps engineer or specialist.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>What Is DevOps?</h2>



<p>DevOps is short for &#8220;software development operations.&#8221; It describes a set of best practices related to transforming the relationship between software developers and information technology (IT) operations personnel.</p>



<p>DevOps aims to improve collaboration, increase efficiency, and reduce waste. This organizational transformation is commonly referred to as cultural transformation.</p>



<p>Achieving cultural transformation requires employees in both departments to change their perspectives and expectations of each other. This is why DevOps is often seen as an ongoing journey, not a destination. DevOps is often associated with agile software development methodologies, such as Kanban, Scrum, and others.</p>



<h2>What do DevOps Engineers do Day to Day?</h2>



<p>A day in the life of DevOps engineers is not all that different than a day in any other technology career. A DevOps Engineer&#8217;s primary responsibility is centered around the health of the systems under their supervision. Those activities will include:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Look for anomalies:</strong> Despite our best efforts trying to completely cover a system in monitoring and visibility, sometimes things go bump in the night. These things could be reported by end users or other business units. Anytime something like that shows up, a DevOps Engineer should chase those anomalies down to something actionable.</li>



<li><strong>Review new releases:</strong> Just because you have an awesome pipeline that utilizes GitOps to move code directly from commit to production does not mean that you should trust your technology stack. Take time daily to review what has been making its way out to production to both understand the changes, but also suggest improvements.</li>



<li><strong>Review observability:</strong> Metrics and monitoring don&#8217;t do any good if nobody is looking at them. Anyone from systems administration through product owners should be reviewing these frequently looking for trends. Real-world usage of a system will always be different than what we thought it was going to be in the engineering phase and we should be validating, disproving, or augmenting our base assertions through data-driven decision-making.</li>



<li><strong>Manage risks:</strong> Successful systems grow over time. DevOps engineers should be looking at a complete ecosystem to help promote long-term health and manage risk. There is no free lunch and growing capacity means that costs will also be going up. Helping the team understand this relationship and educating the product owners of the business on investment opportunities is a critical activity that cannot be overlooked.</li>



<li><strong>Communicate with the team: </strong>Being in constant communication with your team is one of the core principles of DevOps. Since work units are broken down much farther than normal, rapid change is constantly being introduced. By promoting good synchronous and asynchronous communication patterns, teams will stay informed about what is important and urgent along with ensuring everyone is able to consume less urgent current events at their leisure.</li>



<li><strong>Watch industry trends:</strong> Because of the speed that a DevOps team brings to the industry, trends and patterns are changing faster than ever. When looking to become a DevOps engineer, you should be ready to keep your RSS feeds hot and ready to consume.</li>



<li><strong>Log new tickets: </strong>As you are doing your daily surveys of systems, undoubtedly you will run across either existing issues or issues that are sure to crop up in the near future. To help promote good planning, ensure that you are logging tickets into your ticket management system to ensure those issues do not get lost.</li>



<li><strong>Develop the skills you need:</strong> DevOps engineers are lifelong learners. The specific practices of cloud, data, coding, Linux, programming, <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="14" title="AWS" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">AWS</a>, culture, web, <a href="https://kubernetes.io/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="4" title="Kubernetes" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Kubernetes</a>, tools, etc. are constantly being changed to promote more fluid delivery models. Take time to sit back and absorb new concepts and techniques to help level up your career and your team.</li>



<li><strong>Promote continuous improvement:</strong> Any tech company that is not embracing a culture of continuous improvement will quickly be outperformed by companies that do. By taking a little bit of time out of your day to focus on improving something that needs attention, you are contributing to a cleaner and safer technology product!</li>



<li><strong>Have some fun:</strong> DevOps doesn&#8217;t need to be a grind. Make it a point to leave work behind and have some fun with your team.</li>
</ul>



<p>As you can see, DevOps Engineers have a lot of responsibility for running and maintaining technology.</p>



<h2>Types of Jobs in DevOps</h2>



<p>DevOps is a methodology that requires several different disciplines to fully adopt and become proficient in. In my opinion, I don&#8217;t think anyone technical should be asking &#8220;Can I become a DevOps Engineer?&#8221; because you are more than likely already qualified to be one! Let&#8217;s look at a few different roles in DevOps to see how the market is segmenting labor in this space.</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Software Engineer:</strong> Software engineers are responsible for building software products and services against a set of requirements. This role usually has some kind of computer science background, but some of the best developers and engineers I have met started their careers with no formal degree.</li>



<li><strong>Operations Engineer:</strong> Responsible for managing the lifecycle of technology ensuring the stability and reliability of systems. Anyone with a passion for learning technology and growing in the tech space should be searching the job market for entry-level operations jobs.</li>



<li><strong>Quality Assurance:</strong> Responsible for validating the quality of software being developed through automated testing. Also responsible for making testing available to an entire DevOps team.</li>



<li><strong>DevOps Engineer:</strong> Let’s start with the basics. If you’re looking to work as a DevOps engineer, you’ll need to be able to understand and work with code, have an excellent knowledge of server environments, and be able to think on the fly and find solutions to new problems.</li>



<li><strong>DevOps Engineer Manager:</strong> In this capacity, you’ll need to be able to work with both technical and non-technical staff. You’ll be responsible for ensuring that the team is working effectively and efficiently. So, it goes without saying that you’ll need strong communication skills.</li>



<li><strong>DevOps Architect:</strong> A DevOps architect is responsible for designing and implementing the organization’s software delivery system. This is often a challenging role that requires a great deal of experience, knowledge and a strong understanding of organizational needs.</li>



<li><strong>DevOps Manager:</strong> As a DevOps manager, you’ll be responsible for overseeing the entire DevOps process, including hiring, training, and managing staff. You’ll need to be able to understand and communicate the needs of multiple stakeholders. You’ll also need to be able to manage the entire lifecycle of products, from development to delivery and ongoing maintenance.</li>
</ul>



<p>As you can see, normal everyday engineering roles can join a DevOps team. Don&#8217;t immediately exclude yourself because you have not been a DevOps engineer in the past. Most of us have started out in software engineering or system operations roles anyway.</p>



<h2>How to Land a DevOps Job Without a Degree</h2>



<p>In today’s job market, it is not enough to just have a good education and experience from your previous job. You must also know how to write a resume that highlights your skills and experience in a way that shows you as the best candidate for the job.</p>



<p>This can be done by taking some time to research and learn about the particular industry you are interested in working in, as well as the company and the specific role you want to apply for.</p>



<p>When you have this information in hand, you can then create a resume that places your skills, experience, and values at the top of the list. This will make it easy for hiring managers to see what makes you different than other candidates and more likely to be hired.</p>



<p>With these things in mind, it is important to keep your resume updated as new jobs become available. You should also stay on top of employment trends so that you are ready when opportunities arise. By doing this, you will increase your chances of landing an interview and ultimately getting hired.</p>



<p>Here are a few additional steps you can take to increase your odds of landing a DevOps Engineering position:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Research the role you want</strong>: Blindly showing up to a job interview for a DevOps position is not going to go well. Take some time to learn and understand the DevOps methodology and what it is trying to accomplish. Any of the technical skills needed can be acquired on the job so do let that be a limiting factor.</li>



<li><strong>Network</strong>: The single best way to land a job in DevOps without a degree is to network, network, network. It’s one of the most effective ways to find out about new opportunities, learn about the industry, and connect with people who can help you advance your career.</li>



<li><strong>Identify Your Skills</strong>: Before you can network effectively, you need to know what your skills are. Doing this will help you identify which organizations are best for you, as well as identify skill gaps. Furthermore, it will help you understand how to position yourself as the best candidate for a given role.</li>



<li><strong>Join a DevOps Community:</strong> DevOps communities, like meetup groups and online forums, are excellent ways to find out about new opportunities and connect with people who can help you advance your career.</li>



<li><strong>Create an Online Portfolio:</strong> Online portfolios can be incredibly powerful tools for job seekers without a degree. You should include examples of your work and information about your projects and roles.</li>



<li><strong>Network with Employers</strong>: When you’re networking with employers, don’t sell yourself short. Be sure to highlight your skills, background, and experience.</li>
</ul>



<p>Regardless of your experience in development and operations, if you have any kind of tech experience, you should be looking to land a job in the DevOps engineering space. Entry-level positions are generally going to be a bit more focused on operations.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>3 Steps to Landing Any Job You Want</h2>



<p>If you’re looking to find a job, landing any kind of position is a big deal. You can start by proactively searching for the positions you want, or by going through a recruiter or headhunter if they have a specific role you’re interested in.</p>



<p>When you land a new job, you have to be prepared for all kinds of situations. You might have to move across the country if the company has an office there, and you may also have to learn new skills or take on new responsibilities.</p>



<p>Making yourself ready for these situations can help you land any kind of job. For example, you could build up your résumé and online presence by completing online courses or volunteering at local organizations. This will show that you are ready for a new position and will also make it easier to find work once you are ready.</p>



<p>Another option is to join professional organizations like Toastmasters or other networking groups where you can meet people who can help you land a new job. Just remember: Landing any kind of job takes time, so be prepared by taking steps now that will make it easier in the future!</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Define What You Want</strong>: Before you embark on your job search, you need to make an honest assessment of what you want. Do you want a full-time position, or will a contract position work for you? How many hours do you want to work per week? What is your salary range? These are just a few of the questions you’ll need to answer.</li>



<li><strong>Identify Your Strengths: </strong>Once you’ve identified what you want, you need to assess what you have to offer. What are your strengths? What are your weaknesses? This will help you identify which employers will be best for you.</li>



<li><strong>Write a Great Resume</strong>: Once you’ve assessed your skills and talents, you need to translate them into action for your resume. This is your first opportunity to impress a prospective employer.</li>
</ul>



<h2>Why do Employers Value Degrees?</h2>



<p>In the job market, it is no secret that you will very frequently see X level of degree or equivalent experience. I have noticed that this will generally disenfranchise individuals who are in the tech space from searching for a job at a particular company.</p>



<p>As a hiring manager, I am generally looking for individuals who have an aptitude and are lifelong learners for any of the jobs I am looking to fill. People who are passionate about quality delivery, consistency, and passionate about personal development are always great candidates. When looking for a new job, make sure you focus on those key areas about yourself to really wow a future employer.</p>



<p>Employers are also interested in standardized skills in software development, computer science, cloud, systems administration, etc. When someone graduates from higher education in the United States, there is a general sense that those individuals have learned and developed themselves enough to be effective from day 1, which is rarely the case in my experience.</p>



<p>A Junior DevOps engineer position can be filled by anyone who is passionate about automation, CI/CD, cloud, programming, Linux, AWS, and other technical spaces regardless of their background. The key is to do your research and understand the goals of what DevOps is trying to accomplish and make sure you are ready for interview questions about the DevOps Methodology.</p>



<p>When I am evaluating candidates, I bank on people first, not their skills. Even someone who may appear weak in a particular technology may be an incredible person that I want to work with. Some companies take the far more brutal leger-based approach on this. By only interviewing candidates who have a college degree, they are able to defer some of the cost of training. I would argue that is not a company that I want to work for.</p>



<p>There is an old saying, &#8220;Nobody ever gets fired for choosing IBM&#8221;. This translates into, if you are choosing the best, there is no reason for anyone to second guess your decisions. A degree has a similar stigma behind it. If a hiring manager is betting on someone with a degree, they probably won&#8217;t regret their decision. As a candidate, you just need to make sure you give a prospective employer a reason to bet on you.</p>



<p><strong>TLDR;</strong> Standardized skills, training, problem-solving, and risk mitigation.</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>If you want a job as a DevOps Engineer, you’ll need to be prepared to show what you have to offer and sell yourself to prospective employers. Remember, though, that there are many different types of jobs in DevOps.</p>



<p>So, before you start your search, it’s important to understand what you are looking for and how to stand out in a competitive hiring landscape. If you want a job in DevOps, you’ll need to be prepared to show what you have to offer and sell yourself to prospective employers.</p>



<p>Remember, though, that there are many different types of jobs in DevOps: DevOps engineer, architect, engineer manager, and manager. Target what you want to be doing, and start applying. You are probably more qualified than you initially thought!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why You Need to Build A Culture of Trust and Respect in DevOps</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/devops-trust/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 22:45:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops trust]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1657</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Trust and respect are essential ingredients in any healthy working environment. When trust and respect are present, team members feel safe to give their best, collaborate openly, and challenge one another constructively. When trust and respect are absent, team members&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Trust and respect are essential ingredients in any healthy working environment. When trust and respect are present, team members feel safe to give their best, collaborate openly, and challenge one another constructively.</p>



<p>When trust and respect are absent, team members feel insecure about their performance, withhold ideas for fear of judgement or worry about repercussions if they speak up.</p>



<p>There is an inherent risk in bringing together people from different backgrounds with different skill sets. And in the context of <a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a>, you’re also putting together people who likely have very different roles within your organization as well. The potential for discord is high.</p>



<p>So how do you create a culture of trust and respect when working with so many new and different people? Here’s why you need to build a culture of trust and respect in your DevOps initiative.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>It’s the Foundation for Good Communication</h2>



<p>Communication is the foundation for everything in DevOps. You have to be able to openly share what’s working, what isn’t, and why without judgement, without fear of repercussions, and without ego getting in the way.</p>



<p>What happens when, in a meeting, someone says they aren’t getting the information they need from a team member? Or that they feel rushed to get their job done? Or that they aren’t seeing the value in the continuous integration process?</p>



<p>Without a culture of trust and respect, communication will be strained. Team members will be hesitant to speak up, and afraid of judgement. They’ll feel anxious like they don’t have permission to be honest with the team.</p>



<p>And if they don’t feel safe speaking up, the communication breaks down, and the DevOps initiative will suffer as a result.</p>



<h2>It Builds Confidence for Everyone</h2>



<p>One of the biggest challenges in DevOps is building trust between different people, and different parts of the organization. But if you lack the confidence to speak up, you’ll never be able to build that trust missing out on the opportunity to learn from your colleagues and grow yourself as a result.</p>



<p>In a culture where trust and respect are absent, people are less likely to share their ideas, and more likely to either shut down and not try at all, speak up in ways that create discord, and don’t encourage others to respond.</p>



<p>You need to feel confident to share your ideas, challenge others, and learn from both your successes and your mistakes. Without trust and respect, you won’t feel confident enough to do any of these things, and again, the DevOps initiative will suffer as a result.</p>



<h2>It Creates a Safe Environment For Learning</h2>



<p>A healthy DevOps culture needs to create a safe environment for learning. This means not only being transparent about what’s working and what isn’t, but also being open to feedback without fear of judgement.</p>



<p>This is the best way to identify pain points and areas where improvement is needed. When team members feel safe to share their feedback, they can do so in a way that doesn’t create any sense of judgement, but rather, encourages the team to look at the information objectively and decide how to act on it.</p>



<p>But when a team is operating in a culture where trust and respect aren’t present, this kind of feedback is very tricky to navigate. Because team members are likely to feel anxious about sharing their true feelings and experiences, and will likely speak up in ways that are designed to minimise judgement. This can lead to misunderstood feedback, and squashing the open and objective dialogue that is needed for improvement.</p>



<h2>DevOps is About People and Culture</h2>



<p>All of the above leads us to one important conclusion: building a healthy DevOps culture is about people and trust. Building trust and respect is never a one-time thing, and it requires a sustained effort from all members of the team, regardless of their backgrounds.</p>



<p>When you see a team member struggling to find their footing, or growing frustrated at their role, you have to be willing to lend a helping hand. And to do this, you must first be aware of your own behaviour and how you’re modelling the behaviour you want to see.</p>



<p>You must be willing to confront your own behaviours that are likely to be creating a culture that is lacking in trust and respect. And you must be willing to take ownership of your own feelings and be open about how they are impacting your work and the team as a whole.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>DevOps is all about collaboration, communication and cooperation. When everyone on the team trusts and respects each other, they are much more likely to collaborate effectively. This can only happen when everyone feels safe to give their opinion and be open about their needs. Building a culture of trust and respect will take time and effort. However, it is well worth the effort as it will lead to better communication, a healthier team, and ultimately better results for your organization.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How do Agile and DevOps Interrelate?</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/devops-and-agile/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 20:49:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[delivery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops and agile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1264</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[DevOps (an abbreviation of developer operations) is the marriage between software development and IT operation. It’s a term used to describe practices and technologies aimed at bringing together software engineers and IT professionals to produce software more efficiently. In this&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> (an abbreviation of developer operations) is the marriage between software development and IT operation. It’s a term used to describe practices and technologies aimed at bringing together software engineers and IT professionals to produce software more efficiently.</p>



<p>In this blog post, we’ll cover the main principles of DevOps and its interrelation with Agile. It can be challenging for teams that are new to both concepts at the same time, but they really make sense when taken in their entirety. In other words, by following these steps, you’ll be able to create an effective DevOps culture within your organization.</p>



<p>So, how do agile and DevOps interrelate?</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>What is DevOps?</h2>



<p>DevOps is a transformation aimed at integrating the software development and operations teams from a business perspective. It’s a combination of techniques found in Lean and Agile methodologies, and it’s used to transform the way organizations produce software.</p>



<p>DevOps merges the disciplines of development and operations to create a more efficient process that successfully addresses the challenges faced by businesses today. DevOps is an umbrella term that describes a set of processes aimed at bridging the gap between software development and IT operations.</p>



<p>I think this is the first key to explaining how agile and DevOps interrelate. In a more traditional approach, there are generally a series of handoffs between different responsibilities in an organization. When trying to understand how agile and DevOps work together, start by visualizing a world where handoffs do not happen anymore. This will immediately produce savings over the life cycle of your products.</p>



<p>Agile teams are also unique in their own right when compared to a more traditional organizational structure. An agile team is going to consistently be reviewing their development processes for areas of improvement. This is going to allow for meaningful growth and promote a model focused on continuous integration and continuous delivery.</p>



<h2>What Makes DevOps Different from Other Methodologies?</h2>



<p>DevOps integrates the development and operations teams into a single functional delivery team. From a business perspective, it focuses on creating product delivery cycles that solve real problems instead of just churning out code for the sake of producing code.</p>



<p>By combining these disciplines developers can spend less time dealing with the complexities of big bang releases and more time creating new rapidly developed incremental features. This is because the process is automated.</p>



<p>This helps organizations achieve high software quality, fast delivery, and easier adaptation to the market. To end-users, DevOps looks like this: When a team of developers wants to create a new feature, they can rapidly plan, prototype, adjust, and release that feature to start realizing the value of that work.</p>



<p>Agile development methodologies are usually found with any functional DevOps team. When looking at a more traditional project management methodology like Waterfall, anyone trying to implement DevOps will generally stop short at automating infrastructure as code. A project utilizing the Agile DevOps methodology will take that several steps further.</p>



<p>An Agile DevOps team will focus on automating the entire process. Continuous integration will be utilized as a cornerstone to build a robust framework to test and deploy their software. The end goal is to transition into a model of continuous delivery to enable many releases to production in a single day.</p>



<p>Day 2 operations will be integrated into their technology pipelines as well. Tools and automation will be built to take care of more routine tasks such as certificate renewals or auto-remediation. Because DevOps pipelines are test-driven, future unexpected changes are also quickly identified and fixed much more easily.</p>



<h2>What Makes a More Traditional SDLC Risky?</h2>



<p>When working in a more traditional software methodology software moves down an assembly line with bigger changes leading to larger risk.</p>



<p>New features are approved and then tested, followed by regression, and finally deployed to production. This is the most traditional way to work with code. However, it is not always the most efficient way to work with code.</p>



<p>Changes to the code base should be approached from the perspective of the risk involved with any change. When working with big changes in the code base, it is important to look at the big picture of the software. If you are only focused on one aspect of the software, even though it might be the most crucial aspect, you risk overlooking something else that is just as important.</p>



<p>Big-picture thinking is achieved by working with the whole software. If you are building a new feature, you need to start with a new branch of the code base. Without testing the new code, you risk breaking something else in the software. Once you are sure there are no errors in the new code, you can start the testing process. After you are certain the new code has no bugs, you can release it to your production environment.</p>



<p>When the process relies on larger changes, with more complex processes, and more opinions about quality in every decision being made down the assembly line there is a higher likelihood that project timelines will slip or never be delivered at all.</p>



<h2>The Importance of Collaboration in DevOps</h2>



<p>DevOps is the marriage between software development and IT operations. It’s a term used to describe practices and technologies aimed at bringing together software engineers and IT professionals to produce software more efficiently.</p>



<p>In this marriage, there must be a collaboration between the teams involved. This collaboration allows for a better understanding of each other’s roles, and for the shared goal of creating better software with minimal time and effort.</p>



<p>DevOps is key to transforming the operations side of an organization and allowing everyone involved to create high-quality, reliable software. And collaboration between the teams is what allows for this.</p>



<h2>Establishing a Culture of Collaboration for Success in DevOps</h2>



<p>Before you can start implementing DevOps in your organization, you need to establish a culture of collaboration between the teams involved. DevOps is a marriage between teams, and successful marriages are built on communication and a mutual understanding of what both parties bring to the table.</p>



<p>To create this culture, you’ll want to start by determining which members of your organization are involved in the transformation. You can do this by identifying the individuals who are responsible for bringing the different teams together (such as product managers, architects, developers, and operations staff).</p>



<p>You can also do a deeper dive into how the teams interact with each other. Ask yourself:</p>



<ul>
<li>What information does each team need from the other?</li>



<li>What do they do with that information?</li>



<li>What are their roles and responsibilities?</li>
</ul>



<p>This will help you determine where the gaps are between the teams and what needs to change.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>What is Agile?</h2>



<p>Agile has been used in the software development community for a long time, but DevOps has brought it to the forefront.</p>



<p>Agile is a collection of methodologies based on rapid, evolutionary development. It’s about understanding your business needs and developing products and services to meet them.</p>



<p>This type of development is often referred to as evolutionary development, and it’s meant to be a continuous process. This means that in order to adjust to changes in your business, you’ll need to adjust your processes accordingly.</p>



<p>Evolutionary development has many advantages over traditional methods of development, such as waterfall. Waterfall is a method that focuses on a single target release date, and it’s often used in traditional methodologies.</p>



<h2>The Importance of Agility in Digital Development</h2>



<p>Agile development emphasizes the need for constant communication and collaboration between the teams responsible for product development. This communication is key to the success of the transformation, and it’s achieved by bringing together architects, product managers, developers, and operations staff.</p>



<p>By bringing everyone together, you’ll be able to understand their roles and responsibilities and make adjustments as necessary. And, most importantly, you’ll be able to communicate better and collaborate.</p>



<p>By developing products and services that respond to the needs of your customers, you’ll be able to create better software with minimal effort.</p>



<p>When you develop products that your customers actually want, they’re going to be much happier with your software. It’s important to remember that creating customer value is the goal of every business process. Finding ways to make your own business process more efficient is important, but it’s even more critical to focus on customer value.</p>



<h2>Interaction Between Agile and DevOps Principles</h2>



<p>Many people are under the assumption that DevOps and Agile are two different methods, when, in fact, they’re both about rapid, continuous improvement. There are some differences between them, but both focus on bringing the best out of their team members.</p>



<p>Both DevOps and Agile are about collaboration between teams, and both aim to create high-quality, reliable software. But clearly, there are differences between the two. Let’s take a look at some of the similarities between the two methodologies.</p>



<p>Both DevOps and Agile work best when they are integrated. The goal of an integrated approach is to produce high-quality software as quickly as possible. Through the collaboration between developers, testers, operations staff, and other members of the team, you can achieve a faster turnaround time for your software.</p>



<p>To make this collaboration possible, teams must adhere to certain principles such as communication, consistency, and agility.</p>



<p>Additionally, an integrated DevOps and Agile approach can help to reduce the risk of software defects. To accomplish this, you must work with your team to create automated tests for your software.</p>



<p>By integrating DevOps and Agile development processes, you can increase your team’s overall quality. Through testing, you can catch problems before they are shipped to customers. Operations can also be integrated into the process, reducing bottlenecks and increasing the speed of software releases.</p>



<p>These principles aren’t rigid rules; rather, they’re guidelines for implementing good practices for developing software and delivering it more efficiently. They aren’t meant to replace traditional methods of doing business or IT operations; rather, they complement them in order to achieve greater results as quickly as possible.</p>



<h3>Being Agile with DevOps</h3>



<p>DevOps is based on an Agile mindset. It’s an approach to agile software development and software delivery. This means developers and operations professionals must collaborate closely to create a better product in the shortest amount of time possible.</p>



<h3>Being Lean with DevOps</h3>



<p>Lean principles are also important in DevOps, but they are used differently than they are in traditional lean methodologies. These principles focus on continuous improvement, continuous learning, and continuous feedback. The overall goal is to make the process more efficient by minimizing waste and increasing quality.</p>



<h2>Limitations of Traditional Methods of Software Development</h2>



<p>Traditional methodologies are focused on creating a single version of the truth, which can be a limitation if you want to adapt to changing business needs. DevOps, on the other hand, is all about continuous change, so it can be challenging to adapt to that. While related, the need to be agile is a significant difference between DevOps and traditional methodologies.</p>



<h2>Advantages of DevOps over Traditionally practiced methodologies</h2>



<p>The main advantage of DevOps over traditional methodologies is that it helps organizations create better software with minimal effort. With traditional methodologies, such as Waterfall, there is a high probability that the software will not be delivered on time and within budget, and that can be a significant problem. With DevOps, on the other hand, it’s important to note that there’s a difference between creating better software and just producing more of it.</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>DevOps is a transformation aimed at bringing together the disciplines of development and operations to produce high-quality software. It’s a marriage between the teams involved, and it needs to be built on communication and collaboration. DevOps is key to transforming operations and allowing everyone to create high-quality, reliable software. And collaboration between teams is what allows for this. DevOps is the marriage between software engineers and IT professionals.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What is Automation Testing in DevOps</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/devops-testing/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greer Shepherd]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 19:39:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[automated devops testing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[testing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tools]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1239</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Automation Testing in DevOps is generally relegated to the software being released to production. Environmental testing is performed by manual testing practices or high-level smoke tests. Test automation should cover the full CI/CD pipeline including infrastructure, delivery tools, software, UI,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Automation Testing in <a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> is generally relegated to the software being released to production. Environmental testing is performed by manual testing practices or high-level smoke tests.</p>



<p><strong>Test automation should cover the full CI/CD pipeline including infrastructure, delivery tools, software, UI, and any other technology that is included in the pipeline. Automated tests should not be relegated to the land of software development.</strong></p>



<p>Let&#8217;s explore what automation testing in DevOps really means when you are looking to stabilize your delivery process and accelerate your business!</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Automated Testing in DevOps</h2>



<p>Generally, developers tend toward coding unit tests to validate that the code is running the way they expected. At the same time, quality practitioners create automated user tests that validate the end-to-end user experience.</p>



<p>Quality practitioners can arrange explorative testing sessions in which teams manually look at various application area issues.</p>



<p>DevOps&#8217; best practice for the automation of CI/CD pipelines is to run automatic testing whenever possible. This means deploying automatic test UIs to production to detect and proactively address user experience concerns.</p>



<p>I generally like to take this a step further when looking at environmental conditions. Tests for environments can also be thought about in the context of monitoring and observability. A pipeline should be qualified through the use of testing tools in an automated test process. The tests should also be composed in a way that they are usable as part of your monitoring system.</p>



<p>For example, if you are willing to validate that a certificate is valid as part of your testing framework, you should also be willing to run continuous testing to validate that the certificate does not expire between releases.</p>



<h2>The Importance of Test Automation</h2>



<p>Test automation improves reliability, continuity, and productivity within teams of developers and products. DevOps teams have a better chance of staying within budget without disrupting crucial debugging or problem-shooting processes.</p>



<p>Test automation can be quicker than manual testing. It helps to avoid costly errors by eliminating communication barriers and saves money in teams by eliminating unnecessary work. Testing automation provides new forms of flexibility that enable the development team to reuse test scripts across the testing software.</p>



<p>As a business leader, do not be fooled by the short-term investment cost of introducing automated testing into your environment. Testing automation is not new and sexy functionality that you can provide to the market which is why I believe it is skipped by many businesses. Automated testing, continuous integration, and continuous delivery are critical investments to the longevity of your products.</p>



<p>Each release is always going to end up being more complex than the previous release. Employing a good testing process ensures that your products are being introduced to the market in a reliable and expected way. Because of the increased complexity, any manual testing process will need to scale to meet that complexity. Automated testing does not scale in cost the same way that manual testing does.</p>



<h2>What is test automation?</h2>



<p>Test Automation enables users to automate their software testing to ensure that they meet specified quality standards. Different types of testing are often depicted in pyramids. As you ascend the pyramid, the number of testing types decreases, and the costs of creating and operating the test increase. The most traditional tests were conducted using manual methods in the Pyramids in the past. It was a slow and costly procedure until automated testing tooling came into effect.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://www.headspin.io/blog/the-testing-pyramid-simplified-for-one-and-all" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img src="https://global-uploads.webflow.com/619e15d781b21202de206fb5/6316d9e765cd53d9937e2b6a_The-Testing-Pyramid-Simplified-for-One-and-All.webp" alt="The Testing Pyramid"/></a><figcaption>Headspin: The Testing Pyramid: Simplified for One and All</figcaption></figure>



<h2>Common Test Automation Pitfalls</h2>



<p>Below are some of the most common issues when adding automated testing to your technology products:</p>



<ul><li>Developers not participating in testing</li><li>Unit tests not being written with code</li><li>Testing tools are not being used to their fullest potential</li><li>No standard for code coverage</li><li>Best practices not being employed for a specific technology stack</li><li>Tests are not being run in the proper places of a pipeline.</li></ul>



<h2>How Automated Testing Powers DevOps?</h2>



<p>One of the core goals of DevOps is to improve delivery flow. Test automation is one of the core strategies used to help smooth out both flow and quality expectations. A cultural pillar of DevOps is continuous improvement.</p>



<p>Due to the shortened feedback loop of your continuous delivery pipeline, smaller and more nimble software testing and release cycles can be achieved by the development team. This means that your applications will be less prone to errors due to robust testing.</p>



<p>When issues are discovered in production they are not turned into a grandiose response event. A DevOps team is able to get adjustments made to both code and tests and re-release the software quickly back into production.</p>



<p>Without automating releases and tests, teams will scramble to recertify software before being ready to push it back to production with bug fixes. Worse, if your software teams do not employ any testing, you may never know about critical issues before customers bring them up.</p>



<h2>How Can I Improve Continuous Testing?</h2>



<p>Continuous testing is one of the most important things you can do to improve your success rates. If you’re doing it right, continuous testing will help you catch bugs at the earliest stages of development and make sure that problems don’t creep up in production.</p>



<p>Continuous testing helps to keep projects on track and ensure that they stay on schedule, which means that your customers get their products sooner.</p>



<p>A good way to start building a continuous test strategy is by creating an automated integration test pipeline. It should consist of a series of tests that are run automatically when new code is added to your application.</p>



<p>Automated integration tests can be especially useful when you have a large team developing multiple applications that share common code libraries or frameworks. They can also be useful for large-scale applications with many users and complex data models.</p>



<p>Continuous testing also allows developers to build trust with their customers by letting them know that their products are being continuously tested and improved. This can help to increase customer confidence in your product and boost retention rates.</p>



<h2>How Does Automated Testing Change the Role of Quality Assurance?</h2>



<p>Automated testing is a way to evaluate the quality of software. The basic idea is that you write automated tests, or scripts, to check for unexpected behaviors or errors in the code.</p>



<p>Automated testers can run these scripts automatically, which saves time and effort for both developers and QA staff. When you have automated testing in place, you can focus on other tasks, like exploring new features or fixing bugs, without worrying about whether your application is running correctly.</p>



<p>There are two types of automated testing: static and dynamic. Static testing checks for basic issues like syntax errors, security holes, and database integrity. Dynamic testing checks for unexpected behaviors such as out-of-order execution, race conditions, and timeout issues.</p>



<p>QA teams use automated testing to maintain high standards of quality throughout the development process. They can catch issues early on in the development cycle and communicate findings effectively with developers and stakeholders.</p>



<p>By reducing bugs and improving overall quality, automated testing can help organizations achieve their goals more quickly and cost-effectively.</p>



<p>A Quality Assurance Engineers&#8217; role changes when embracing test automation testing. Their role will now be to enable the entire team to contribute tests to the automation pipeline. Test cases should be developed and run as part of the normal delivery process.</p>



<p>By making this transition, Quality Assurance Engineers can now focus on higher value work like covering edge cases, improving testing tools and methodology, and leveling up team members&#8217; skills in testing.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Test Automation Stages</h2>



<p>Test Automation includes several fundamental automation techniques that should be followed for quality testing. Testing automation systems are presented in stages atop test pyramids based on their hierarchy.</p>



<h3>Integration testing</h3>



<p>Integration tests measure whether logical integration is effective across all systems and can be achieved without unavoidable errors in integration. Incorporated testing is designed to test compliance with systems to determine how different modules interact.</p>



<h3>Unit testing</h3>



<p>Unit Testing means isolating your Application into unit testing and then checking its behavior independently of external parties or database configuration. Unit tests are often conducted throughout the build period and are considered the primary test phase.</p>



<h3>End-to-end testing</h3>



<p>Test frameworks for the testing of applications simulate user requirements to ensure they meet the needs of users at all levels. The final purpose is to ensure the application can be validated and checked by all the users.</p>



<h3>Exploratory testing</h3>



<p>Exploration testing can be regarded as a more advanced software testing strategy that involves learning, checking, and reviewing functional and visual components for users.</p>



<h3>Environmental Testing</h3>



<p>Building tests to validate the consistency that your software will be running in after deployment.</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>As you can see, automated testing is a cornerstone to DevOps. Most focus is generally put on running automated testing against software being developed. There are a lot of advantages to developing automated testing which also looks at environmental conditions as well. Accelerate your business by introducing automated testing tools today!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Modify VMWare ESXi Guest Files with Ansible</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/ansible-modify-vmware-esxi-guest-file/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 01:25:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ansible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[howto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tools]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1232</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This post will help anyone who is attempting to use ansible to modify files on VMs running on ESXI via automation when Practicing DevOps. This method assumes that you have cloned out a machine, but do not yet have network&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>This post will help anyone who is attempting to use <a href="https://www.ansible.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="7" title="Ansible">ansible</a> to modify files on VMs running on ESXI via automation when <a href="https://www.valewood.org/practicing-devops/">Practicing DevOps</a>.  This method assumes that you have cloned out a machine, but do not yet have network access to that machine meaning you would need to utilize native ESXi methods to get communication setup.  </p>



<p>I use methods like this in my home lab to help stay current with new trends in <a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> Not everyone is going to be fortunate enough to have cloud playgrounds to test out new things, and home labs are a great way to make a one-time investment in your future.</p>



<p>The code for the project can be found <a href="https://github.com/gwagner/ansible-examples/tree/main/modify-vmware-esxi-guest-file" target="_blank" data-type="URL" data-id="https://github.com/gwagner/ansible-examples/tree/main/modify-vmware-esxi-guest-file" rel="noreferrer noopener">here</a>!</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Prerequisites</h2>



<p>This article is going to assume that you already have VMWare running in a home lab somewhere. This also assumes that you have some familiarity with VMware and networking.</p>



<p>This post will also assume that you have already installed a baseline OS running open-vm-tools. <a href="https://www.packer.io/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="17" title="Packer" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Packer</a><a href="https://www.packer.io/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"></a> is a good tool to use to automate your baseline operating system installation to create a reusable disk image.</p>



<p>You may also want to read <a href="https://www.valewood.org/ansible-create-vmware-esxi-vm/" data-type="post" data-id="1213">this post</a> to get a good feeling about how to automate cloning images when vSphere or Center are not available solutions.</p>



<h2>The Playbook</h2>



<p>Below is the full code to copy SSH keys to a newly cloned machine, and set an IP address with a NetworkManager restart.</p>



<p>The general idea is to run <code>ansible-playbook modify-vmware-esxi-guest-file.yaml -i inventory.yaml</code> from your command line.  The playbook will then connect to ESXi and create a .ssh folder on your fresh machine.  It will then copy your local <code>/home/user/.ssh/id_rsa.pub</code> file to the remote machine.  Finally, it will run <code>/bin/nmcli </code>commands to get a static IP address set on the VM.</p>



<p>A majority of this playbook is also setup with <code>delegate_to: localhost</code>. This means that the computer running the ansible script will also execute anything with the defined <code><code>delegate_to</code>: localhost</code>. Since the remote machine from inventory exists but is not yet able to be connected to <code><code>delegate_to</code>: localhost</code> is necessary of you would immediately receive an ansible connection error.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>---
- name: Modify VMWare ESXi VM File
  hosts: all
  gather_facts: false
  tasks:
    - include_vars: config.yaml
      delegate_to: localhost

    - include_vars: creds.yaml # Remember, this should be in a vault
      delegate_to: localhost   # These creds are for example use only

    - name: Create .ssh folder
      community.vmware.vmware_guest_file_operation:
        validate_certs: false
        hostname: "{{ vmware_host }}"
        username: "{{ vmware_user }}"
        password: "{{ vmware_password }}"
        datacenter: ha-datacenter
        vm_id: "{{ vmware.name }}"
        vm_username: "{{ centos_template_user }}"
        vm_password: "{{ centos_template_password }}"
        directory:
          path: "/home/user/.ssh/"
          operation: create
          recurse: no
      delegate_to: localhost

    - name: Copy RSA to VM
      community.vmware.vmware_guest_file_operation:
        validate_certs: false
        hostname: "{{ vmware_host }}"
        username: "{{ vmware_user }}"
        password: "{{ vmware_password }}"
        datacenter: ha-datacenter
        vm_id: "{{ vmware.name }}"
        vm_username: "{{ centos_template_user }}"
        vm_password: "{{ centos_template_password }}"
        copy:
          src: "/home/user/.ssh/id_rsa.pub"
          dest: "/home/user/.ssh/authorized_keys"
          overwrite: yes
      delegate_to: localhost

    - name: Run command inside a virtual machine
      community.vmware.vmware_vm_shell:
        hostname: "{{ vmware_host }}"
        username: "{{ vmware_user }}"
        password: "{{ vmware_password }}"
        datacenter: ha-datacenter
        vm_id: "{{ vmware.name }}"
        vm_username: "{{ centos_template_user }}"
        vm_password: "{{ centos_template_password }}"
        vm_shell: "{{ item.shell }}"
        vm_shell_args: "{{ item.args }}"
      loop:
        - { shell: "/bin/nmcli", args: "connection modify ens192 IPv4.ignore-auto-dns yes" }
        - { shell: "/bin/nmcli", args: "connection modify ens192 IPv4.address \"{{ vmware.ip_address }}/24\"" }
        - { shell: "/bin/nmcli", args: "connection modify ens192 IPv4.gateway \"{{ vmware.gateway_address }}\"" }
        - { shell: "/bin/nmcli", args: "connection modify ens192 IPv4.dns \"{{ vmware.dns_address }}\"" }
        - { shell: "/bin/nmcli", args: "connection modify ens192 IPv4.method manual" }
        - { shell: "/bin/systemctl", args: "NetworkManager restart" }
      delegate_to: localhost

</code></pre>



<h2>Task By Task Breakdown</h2>



<p>To not rehash details I have gone through in other articles, you can find a breakdown of the inventory, credentials, and config in <a href="https://www.valewood.org/ansible-create-vmware-esxi-vm/#penci-A-Task-By-Task-Breakdown" data-type="URL" data-id="/ansible-create-vmware-esxi-vm/#penci-A-Task-By-Task-Breakdown">this post.</a></p>



<p>The first step of this playbook is to create a users .ssh folder so an authorized_keys file can be created.  The playbook makes an assumption that your user is named&#8230; user, but that could be modified and turned into a configuration parameter pretty quickly.  I will break down each of the config parameters below:</p>



<ul><li>validate_certs is set to false because most of us are not going to be using trusted 3rd party certs in our VMware environment. If you are doing this in a professional environment, ensure you have valid certs installed and leave validate_certs set to the default of true.</li><li>validate_certs should also be set to false if you are connecting to your VMWare server via IP address since your cert will not match an IP address.</li><li>vmware_user and vmware_password should be set to a user that has SSH access to your VMWare server. I would not recommend that you do this in any sort of production environment, but it is perfectly fine for a home lab.</li><li>datacenter is set to ha-datacenter. This is the default name of a “datacenter” in ESXi. There is no reason to change this.</li><li>vm_id is either the exact case-sensitive name of the virtual machine being configured.  If you created your machine using ansible, then make sure you map the name you gave it here via variables.</li><li>vm_username and vm_password is in reference to the user you setup when creating your template or disk image.  ESXi needs this to effectively run an interactive login to the server to perform your commands.</li><li>directory is signifying that our action is going to be taken on a directory.  In the next task you will see that we use the copy key instead of directory but we are utilizing the exact same module.</li><li>directory.path is the path on the ESXi guests that you want to take action on.</li><li>directory.operation denotes what we want to have happen.  In this case, we are going to create a directory.</li><li>directory.recurse tells ansible if it should send a command that recursively creates directories.  If your default user is not named user, you would end up with a /home/user/.ssh directory that will be fairly useless.</li></ul>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>    - name: Create .ssh folder
      community.vmware.vmware_guest_file_operation:
        validate_certs: false
        hostname: "{{ vmware_host }}"
        username: "{{ vmware_user }}"
        password: "{{ vmware_password }}"
        datacenter: ha-datacenter
        vm_id: "{{ vmware.name }}"
        vm_username: "{{ centos_template_user }}"
        vm_password: "{{ centos_template_password }}"
        directory:
          path: "/home/user/.ssh/"
          operation: create
          recurse: no
      delegate_to: localhost</code></pre>



<p>This next task does a copy of a file from the machine you executed the ansible playbook from onto the ESXi guest that we are configuring.  In the interest of brevity, I am not going to rehash the duplicate keys from above.  Here are the specific keys of interest in this task:</p>



<ul><li>copy denotes that we want to copy a file.  The file needs to exist on your source system and will be copied to the ESXi guest.</li><li>copy.src is the path to the source file.  As you can see, we are targeting the public key here.</li><li>copy.dest is the full path to the destination.   As you can see we are targeting an authorized_keys file as the destination.  This could be dangerous if that file already exists as it will be overwritten.</li><li>copy.overwrite ensures that we will clobber whatever exists on the destination system with the file from our source system.</li></ul>



<pre class="wp-block-code yaml"><code>    - name: Copy RSA to VM
      community.vmware.vmware_guest_file_operation:
        validate_certs: false
        hostname: "{{ vmware_host }}"
        username: "{{ vmware_user }}"
        password: "{{ vmware_password }}"
        datacenter: ha-datacenter
        vm_id: "{{ vmware.name }}"
        vm_username: "{{ centos_template_user }}"
        vm_password: "{{ centos_template_password }}"
        copy:
          src: "/home/user/.ssh/id_rsa.pub"
          dest: "/home/user/.ssh/authorized_keys"
          overwrite: yes
      delegate_to: localhost</code></pre>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<p>This last task is composed a bit differently.  Effectively it is being used to run a series of nmcli commands along with a single systemctl command to set a static IP address for this machine.  I have this task composed this way to clean up ansible code.  This could be written as six fully independent tasks in ansible, but remember to stay DRY and don&#8217;t repeat yourself.  Here is a breakdown of the specific keys of interest:</p>



<ul><li>vm_shell represents the exact path to the command that is going to be run on the ESXi guest.  Do not include command arguments in this field, the documentation specifically states that it wants a full path to an executable.</li><li>vm_shell_args represents the arguments to the vm_shell command.  </li><li>loop controls how the task will loop through the data defined underneath.  I have the keys setup as dictionary objects so that we get both shell executables and arguments from the loop.</li></ul>



<pre class="wp-block-code"><code>    - name: Run command inside a virtual machine
      community.vmware.vmware_vm_shell:
        hostname: "{{ vmware_host }}"
        username: "{{ vmware_user }}"
        password: "{{ vmware_password }}"
        datacenter: ha-datacenter
        vm_id: "{{ vmware.name }}"
        vm_username: "{{ centos_template_user }}"
        vm_password: "{{ centos_template_password }}"
        vm_shell: "{{ item.shell }}"
        vm_shell_args: "{{ item.args }}"
      loop:
        - { shell: "/bin/nmcli", args: "connection modify ens192 IPv4.ignore-auto-dns yes" }
        - { shell: "/bin/nmcli", args: "connection modify ens192 IPv4.address \"{{ vmware.ip_address }}/24\"" }
        - { shell: "/bin/nmcli", args: "connection modify ens192 IPv4.gateway \"{{ vmware.gateway_address }}\"" }
        - { shell: "/bin/nmcli", args: "connection modify ens192 IPv4.dns \"{{ vmware.dns_address }}\"" }
        - { shell: "/bin/nmcli", args: "connection modify ens192 IPv4.method manual" }
        - { shell: "/bin/systemctl", args: "NetworkManager restart" }
      delegate_to: localhost</code></pre>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>As you can see, with a fairly concise set of steps, you can level up your DevOps automation game by rapidly configuring virtual machines in your home lab.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
