<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>DevOps &#8211; A DevOps Blog</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.valewood.org/devops/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.valewood.org/</link>
	<description>Occasionally a developer makes an Ops!</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 17:43:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.valewood.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/A-DevOoops-1-e1660773390219.png</url>
	<title>DevOps &#8211; A DevOps Blog</title>
	<link>https://www.valewood.org/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>How ChatGPT Can Speed Up DevOps by Writing Ansible</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/how-chatgpt-can-speed-up-devops-by-writing-ansible/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 16:33:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[howto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syntax-highlight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tools]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2103</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Did you know that ChatGPT can help you write Ansible? ChatGPT utilizes the same OpenAI that GitHub Copilot uses to generate code on the fly in your favorite IDE or code editor. You can ask ChatGPT questions about how to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Did you know that <a href="https://openai.com/blog/chatgpt/" data-type="URL" data-id="https://openai.com/blog/chatgpt/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">ChatGPT</a> can help you write <a href="https://www.ansible.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="7" title="Ansible">Ansible</a>?  ChatGPT utilizes the same <a href="https://openai.com/" data-type="URL" data-id="https://openai.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">OpenAI</a> that <a href="https://github.com/features/copilot" target="_blank" data-type="URL" data-id="https://github.com/features/copilot" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">GitHub Copilot</a> uses to generate code on the fly in your favorite IDE or code editor.  You can ask ChatGPT questions about how to write code, and to the best of its ability, it will send back an answer that is usually pretty good.  This is especially useful when writing automation as part of a team focused on the <a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> methodology.</p>



<p>In DevOps you will be hit with many unfamiliar and abstract contexts simply because the space is rapidly evolving and new stuff is being introduced daily.  ChatGPT is trained on information up to 2021, so you will not get anything up the minute, but there are already a lot of problems that have been solved on the internet, but searching for them may be problematic.  </p>



<p>ChatGPT is really good, almost scary, at understanding your request and returning working code examples for you to consume.  Better yet, it is excellent at also providing descriptions about the code it just wrote to help you understand it using natural language.</p>



<p>Let&#8217;s talk about the good, the bad, and the ugly side of AI-generated code and how to use chat GPT to write some Ansible!</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>The Good: Asking ChatGPT to Create an ESXi Virtual Machine with Ansible</h2>



<p>I posted an article a few months back about the flow that I use to <a href="https://www.valewood.org/ansible-create-vmware-esxi-vm/" data-type="post" data-id="1213">create an ESXi virtual machine</a> using native ansible.  This example comes directly from my home lab setup where I have automated a complete end-to-end <a href="https://kubernetes.io/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="4" title="Kubernetes" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Kubernetes</a> deployment utilizing Ansible and kubespray.  This bit of code was extracted and abstracted to provide that example on my website.</p>



<p>Let&#8217;s see if ChatGPT could answer the question:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>Using Ansible, how would i create a virtual machine in ESXi?</p>
</blockquote>



<p>And here is the response that I got back:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>To create a virtual machine in ESXi using Ansible, you would need to use the <code>vmware_guest</code> module. This module allows you to manage virtual machines in VMware vSphere.</p>



<p>Here is an example of how you can use this module to create a new virtual machine:</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code language-yaml"><code>- name: Create a new virtual machine
  vmware_guest:
    hostname: "{{ vsphere_hostname }}"
    username: "{{ vsphere_username }}"
    password: "{{ vsphere_password }}"
    datacenter: "{{ datacenter_name }}"
    cluster: "{{ cluster_name }}"
    name: "{{ vm_name }}"
    folders: "{{ folder_name }}"
    template: "{{ template_name }}"
    state: present
    networks:
    - name: "{{ network_name }}"
      ip: "{{ ip_address }}"
      netmask: "{{ netmask }}"
      gateway: "{{ gateway }}"
      domain: "{{ domain_name }}"
</code></pre>



<p>In the above example, we are creating a new virtual machine with the specified <code>name</code> and <code>template</code> on the specified <code>datacenter</code> and <code>cluster</code>. We are also specifying the network settings for the virtual machine, such as the <code>ip</code> address, <code>netmask</code>, and <code>gateway</code>.</p>



<p>Keep in mind that this is just an example, and you may need to adjust the parameters and settings based on your specific environment and requirements.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>This is an excellent example of how to perform this task.  If you search google for this exact same search query &#8220;Using Ansible, how would I create a virtual machine in ESXi?&#8221;, the first thing that you get is some obscure ansible documentation that does not really answer the question you were after.  ChatGPT understood exactly what I was looking for and returned a good relevant explanation along with code and a description of variables that you need to define to utilize this code.</p>



<p>Now; ChatGPT is not connected to the internet, or so they claim, so you are unable to ask it for references to relevant documentation, but anyone savvy enough to read this should be able to utilize the provided code to perform a much more detailed search on google to hone in on what they want.</p>



<h3>Extending the Search</h3>



<p>I went back to ChatGPT to ask:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>How would I integrate that utilizing an existing disk image?</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Unfortunately, ChatGPT returned the exact same response as it did to my original question.  This is going to be where ChatGPT will fall short.  The example code that I linked above assumes that you have an existing disk image that you are looking to copy and register as a new virtual machine.  ChatGPT, using OpenAI v3, won&#8217;t really be able to contextually understand that use case today, but might in the future!</p>



<h3>How else could I use this?</h3>



<p>I asked ChatGPT this question next:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>How would I do that with GoLang?</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Please take note, I have not asked any other questions than what I have put in this thread.  ChatGPT is contextually understanding the conversation that we are having and is deriving its responses based on that context.  This means that it still knows that I am trying to clone out an ESXi virtual machine even though that was 2 messages back.</p>



<p>Here is the response that I got back:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>To create an ESXi virtual machine using GoLang, you would need to use the vSphere API provided by VMware. The vSphere API allows you to manage and interact with ESXi hosts and their virtual machines.</p>



<p>Here is an outline of the steps you would need to follow to create an ESXi virtual machine using GoLang:</p>



<ol>
<li>Install and configure the GoLang programming language on your computer.</li>



<li>Use the vSphere API to connect to your ESXi host and authenticate with the host.</li>



<li>Use the vSphere API to create a new virtual machine on the ESXi host. This will involve specifying the hardware configuration for the virtual machine, such as the amount of memory and CPU resources to allocate, as well as the virtual disk size and format.</li>



<li>Use the vSphere API to configure the network settings for the virtual machine, such as the network adapter type and network settings.</li>



<li>Use the vSphere API to install an operating system on the virtual machine. This will involve booting the virtual machine from an ISO image and installing the operating system according to the instructions provided by the operating system vendor.</li>



<li>Use the vSphere API to start the virtual machine and verify that it is running correctly.</li>
</ol>



<p>Overall, creating an ESXi virtual machine using GoLang will require a good understanding of both the GoLang programming language and the vSphere API. It may also require some knowledge of virtualization and ESXi host management.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>This response is interesting.  With the Ansible response, code was provided.  With the GoLang response, steps were provided.  This shows a bit of the inconsistency still left to shake out of the system.</p>



<p>I pivoted a bit and asked:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>How would I do this with Code?</p>
</blockquote>



<p>And the response looks much better!</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote go">
<p>Here is an example of how you might use the vSphere API in GoLang to create a new virtual machine on an ESXi host:</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code language-go"><code>import "github.com/vmware/govmomi/vim25/types" // Import the vSphere API package

// Connect to the ESXi host and authenticate
client, err := govmomi.NewClient(ctx, esxiURL, true)
if err != nil {
    // Handle error
}

// Create a new virtual machine on the ESXi host
vm, err := object.NewVirtualMachine(client.Client, vmConfig)
if err != nil {
    // Handle error
}

// Configure the virtual machine's hardware settings
err = vm.WaitForIP(ctx)
if err != nil {
    // Handle error
}

// Install an operating system on the virtual machine
err = vm.Create(ctx, pool, spec)
if err != nil {
    // Handle error
}

// Start the virtual machine and verify that it is running
err = vm.PowerOn(ctx)
if err != nil {
    // Handle error
}
</code></pre>



<p>This is just an example of how you might use the vSphere API in GoLang to create an ESXi virtual machine. There may be other ways to accomplish this task using the vSphere API, and your specific implementation may vary depending on your specific requirements and use case. I recommend consulting the vSphere API documentation and GoLang documentation for more information and guidance.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Pretty impressive that you can get 2 different results for the same tasks in different programming languages all provided by the same AI language model.  Now this response is extremely basic and I would not run it in production anywhere without a lot more inspection and real error handling, but it is perfect to get someone going in a space they are unfamiliar with!</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>The Bad: Asking ChatGPT to Write Some Ansible</h2>



<p>Things here get a little bit messier. I have an article <a href="https://www.valewood.org/ansible-text-to-json/" data-type="post" data-id="1187">here</a> to help people understand how to convert a text file to JSON using ansible.  This post was inspired by someone asking the exact same question over on Reddit, and rather than answering it there, I figured it was a good opportunity to write something a bit more long-form that was easier to find that an obscure Reddit thread.  </p>



<p>Let&#8217;s see if ChatGPT could answer this relatively simple question on doing the exact same conversion.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>Using Ansible, how would i convert a text file to JSON and write it to a new file?</p>
</blockquote>



<p>And here is the response that I got back:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>To convert a text file to JSON using Ansible, you can use the <code>json_query</code> filter to extract the desired data from the text file and then use the <code>to_json</code> filter to convert it to JSON format. You can then use the <code>file</code> module to write the JSON data to a new file.</p>



<p>Here is an example playbook that shows how this can be done:</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code language-yaml"><code>---
- hosts: localhost
  tasks:
    - name: Read the text file
      delegate_to: localhost
      slurp:
        src: "path/to/text/file"
      register: text_file

    - name: Convert the text file to JSON
      delegate_to: localhost
      set_fact:
        json_data: "{{ text_file.content | json_query(query) | to_json }}"

    - name: Write the JSON data to a new file
      delegate_to: localhost
      file:
        path: "path/to/new/file.json"
        mode: "0644"
        state: "touch"
        content: "{{ json_data }}"
</code></pre>



<p>In this example, the <code>json_query</code> filter is used to extract the desired data from the text file using the <code>query</code> variable. You can use any valid JSON query to extract the data you need. The extracted data is then converted to JSON format using the <code>to_json</code> filter and saved in a variable called <code>json_data</code>.</p>



<p>Finally, the <code>file</code> module is used to create a new file called <code>file.json</code> and write the JSON data to it. You can customize the path, permissions, and other attributes of the file as needed.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Pretty neat!  Breaking this down a bit, ChatGPT first provides a text-based description of what it is going to do.  The problem is, <code>query</code> is currently not a defined variable meaning that this code is not actually going to run.  </p>



<p>Structurally, this code looks awesome and looks fully functional, but in the end, is not a good representation of a working Ansible that will actually produce the result you are looking for.  If you are looking for a more correct example, please follow the link that I provided above.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>The Ugly: The Evolving Landscape</h2>



<p>Right now ChatGPT is a bit slow to respond and is very popular meaning that it is overloaded frequently.  There is also no guarantee that ChatGPT will remain free and open forever.  It is currently pulling from a dataset that is powering a paid product called <a href="https://www.github.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="6" title="Github" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">GitHub</a> CoPilot meaning that OpenAI has the incentive to lock this functionality down in the future.  </p>



<p>While working on this piece, I had to put things down and come back the next day to finish up.  I decided to run a few questions against ChatGPT again to see what kind of response I would get.  The reality is, they had changed.  ChatGPT engineers are constantly doing training tweaks to the AI to better respond to requests, meaning you will get different responses each time you use it.</p>



<p>I think that this is a very fun toy while it lasts, but I would not consider wrapping this into any kind of mission-critical environment just yet.  But, if you are an aspiring engineer that is having trouble sourcing any kind of kickstart material, or you are just curious, ride this train while the ride is free!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Solve Your Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff Woes in No Time</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/kubernetes-crashloopbackoff-error/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 17:29:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[howto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kubernetes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tools]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2065</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you are running a Kubernetes cluster, chances are you&#8217;ve come across the dreaded &#8216;CrashLoopBackoff&#8217; error. This error can be incredibly frustrating, as it can be difficult to troubleshoot and solve. In this article, we&#8217;ll be discussing everything you need&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>If you are running a <a href="https://kubernetes.io/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="4" title="Kubernetes" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Kubernetes</a> cluster, chances are you&#8217;ve come across the dreaded &#8216;CrashLoopBackoff&#8217; error. This error can be incredibly frustrating, as it can be difficult to troubleshoot and solve.</p>



<p>In this article, we&#8217;ll be discussing everything you need to know about Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff, including what causes it, how to troubleshoot it, and how to solve it.</p>



<p>So, if you&#8217;re ready to get your Kubernetes cluster back up and running in no time, read on!</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Understanding Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff</h2>



<p>Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff is an error that occurs when an application running in a Kubernetes cluster fails to start or restart successfully. The issue you are having is right in the name; your application is crashing in a loop and Kubernetes is using a backoff algorithm so that it doesn&#8217;t try to restart your failing app at lightspeed.</p>



<p>CrashLoopBackoff is an algorithmic protection mechanism for Kubernetes clusters. A backoff loop usually happens due to an issue with the application itself, or underlying infrastructure. When this error occurs, Kubernetes will try to restart the application several times, and if it fails all of those attempts, it will log the &#8216;CrashLoopBackoff&#8217; error.</p>



<p>At its core, Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff is simply a way for Kubernetes to notify you that something is wrong with an application in your cluster. It is not necessarily an indication of a problem with Kubernetes itself, so it is important to understand what is causing the issue in order to properly troubleshoot and solve it.</p>



<h2>What Causes Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff?</h2>



<p>Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff can be caused by a number of different issues, ranging from application issues to underlying infrastructure issues. The most common causes of Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff are:</p>



<ul>
<li>Application issues such as bugs, memory leaks, or incompatible configurations.</li>



<li>Infrastructure issues such as insufficient resources, networking issues, or misconfigured storage.</li>



<li>Failing dependencies can cause a backoff loop to happen as well. If your app requires a database, but the database server is down the app may fail rapidly and Kubernetes will report a CrashLoopBackoff error.</li>



<li>An incorrect or missing API key or authentication credentials.</li>



<li>Issues with the Kubernetes API server or the Kubernetes control plane.</li>
</ul>



<p>It is important to understand what is causing the CrashLoopBackoff in order to properly troubleshoot and solve the issue.</p>



<h2>How to Troubleshoot Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff</h2>



<p>When it comes to troubleshooting Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff, the first step is to identify what is causing the issue.</p>



<p>To do this, you should start by looking at the logs for the application. The logs should provide insight into what is causing the CrashLoopBackoff, such as an application bug or a misconfigured resource. Once you have identified the cause of the issue, you can begin troubleshooting the problem.</p>



<p>Next, check if the application has been configured correctly, if the resource allocations are sufficient, and if the application is running in the correct environment. You should also check for any networking or storage issues that could be causing the CrashLoopBackoff.</p>



<p>Here is a list of checks to work through when diagnosing CrashLoopBackoff errors:</p>



<ol>
<li><strong>App logs: </strong>When experiencing a CrashLoopBackoff, there are a few things you can look for in the application logs that may help you troubleshoot the issue. First, you can check for any error messages that may indicate what is causing the CrashLoopBackoff. This could be anything from a syntax error in your code to an issue with a specific dependency or resource that your application is trying to access. These resources could be services such as databases or API endpoints where access may not be properly configured.</li>



<li><strong>Kubernetes Events: </strong>When experiencing a CrashLoopBackoff scenario in Kubernetes, there are a few events that you should evaluate to help troubleshoot the issue. First, you should check the events for your pod to see if there are any error messages that indicate what is causing the CrashLoopBackoff. This could be anything from a syntax error in your code to an issue with a specific dependency or resource that your application is trying to access. Additionally, you should check the events for the kubelet on the node where your pod is running to see if there are any messages related to the CrashLoopBackoff itself, such as a message indicating that the kubelet is restarting your pod due to the CrashLoopBackoff condition. Finally, you should check the events for the Kubernetes control plane components, such as the API server and the scheduler, to see if there are any messages that could provide insight into the cause of the CrashLoopBackoff.</li>



<li><strong>Run the command &#8220;kubectl describe pod -n &lt;namespace> &lt;pod name>&#8221;</strong>: <code>kubectl describe pod</code> provides detailed information about a specific Kubernetes pod. This information includes the pod&#8217;s name, namespace, and status, as well as the node on which it is running and the containers that are included in the pod. Additionally, <code>kubectl describe pod</code> provides metadata about the pod, such as labels and annotations, and it also displays any events that have been associated with the pod. This can be useful for troubleshooting issues with your Kubernetes clusters, as it provides a detailed view of the pod and its components.</li>



<li><strong>Enable pod debugging:</strong> This may not be applicable everywhere, but if the application supports debugging environment variables then you should enable this to get more logs from the pod itself. This may show what is causing the CrashLoopBackoff errors to occur.</li>



<li><strong>Investigate pod replicas: </strong>If you have multiple replicas, you may have a running replica pod that you can investigate to compare with your pod that is in a CrashLoopBackoff state. In my experience, if there is at least one running replica, then you would be looking for something more environmental such as improperly configured PVCs, networking, resource allocation, etc.</li>



<li><strong>kube-dns:</strong> To troubleshoot issues with kube-dns in Kubernetes, you can use the <code>kubectl</code> command-line tool to check the status of the kube-dns service and its associated components. First, you can use the <code>kubectl get pods</code> command to see if the kube-dns pods are running and to check their status. If the pods are not running, you can use the <code>kubectl describe pod</code> command to get more information about the issue and to see if there are any error messages that can help you diagnose the problem. Additionally, you can use the <code>kubectl logs</code> command to view the logs for the kube-dns pods and look for any error messages that may provide insight into the issue.</li>



<li><strong>Environment variables: </strong>When investigating CrashLoopBackoff errors, environment variable misconfiguration is a quick and easy place to validate. Ensure that all of the correct environment variables are set for your application. Check the case (uppercase and lowercase) of the variable names if your application is case-sensitive. Check that secrets are mapped properly to env vars if you are mapping secrets.</li>



<li><strong>Secrets:</strong> Keeping secrets safe in Kubernetes is very important. Out of the box, secrets are base64 encoded strings which is not very secure. There are a lot of great mechanisms out there to provide better security. Most of these will require definitions around access to secrets to ensure only resources with delegated access can decrypt and utilize them. Check the documentation for the provider you are using to ensure things delegation are configured correctly.</li>



<li><strong>Ports:</strong> If you are experiencing CrashLoopBackoff errors and suspect that the issue may be related to your port configuration, there are a few steps you can take to diagnose the problem. First, you can check the logs for your application to see if there are any messages that indicate a problem with the port configuration. For example, if your application is unable to bind to the specified port, you may see an error message in the logs indicating this issue. Additionally, you can use the <code>netstat</code> command to view a list of the currently open ports on your system and see if the port that your application is trying to use is already in use by another process. If the port is already in use, you will need to either configure your application to use a different port or stop the other process that is using the port in order to resolve the issue.</li>



<li><strong>Health Probes:</strong> If you are experiencing CrashLoopBackoff errors and suspect that the issue may be related to health probes, there are a few steps you can take to diagnose the problem. First, you can check the logs for your application to see if there are any messages that indicate a problem with the health probes. For example, if your application is failing the health probe because it is unable to connect to a required dependency, you may see an error message in the logs indicating this issue. Additionally, you can use the <code>kubectl</code> command-line tool to view the status of the health probes for your application. For example, you can use the <code>kubectl</code> describe pod command to see the results of the health probes for your pod, and you can use the <code>kubectl</code> describe deployment command to see the overall health of your deployment. This information can help you determine whether the health probes are failing and why, which can provide insight into the root cause of the CrashLoopBackoff errors.</li>



<li><strong>Readiness Probes:</strong> If you are experiencing CrashLoopBackoff errors and suspect that the issue may be related to readiness probes, there are a few steps you can take to diagnose the problem. First, you can check the logs for your application to see if there are any messages that indicate a problem with the readiness probes. For example, if your application is failing the readiness probe because it is unable to connect to a required dependency, you may see an error message in the logs indicating this issue. Additionally, you can use the <code>kubectl</code> command-line tool to view the status of the readiness probes for your application. For example, you can use the <code>kubectl</code> describe pod command to see the results of the readiness probes for your pod, and you can use the <code>kubectl</code> describe deployment command to see the overall readiness of your deployment. This information can help you determine whether the readiness probes are failing and why, which can provide insight into the root cause of the CrashLoopBackoff errors.</li>



<li><strong>Node Health: </strong>To check the health of a Kubernetes worker node, you can use the kubectl command-line tool to view the status of the node and its associated components. First, you can use the <code>kubectl</code> get nodes command to see a list of all the nodes in your cluster, along with their status. This will let you see which nodes are healthy and which ones may be experiencing issues. You can then use the <code>kubectl</code> describe node command to get more detailed information about a specific node, including its overall status and any events that have occurred on the node. This information can help you determine whether the node is healthy and identify any potential issues that may be affecting its performance.</li>
</ol>



<p>Once you have identified and resolved the underlying issue, you can attempt to restart the application. If the restart is successful, the CrashLoopBackoff should be resolved. If the restart is unsuccessful, you may need to look into other potential issues.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Step-by-Step Guide for Solving Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff</h2>



<p>If you&#8217;re looking for a step-by-step guide for solving Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff, here&#8217;s what you need to do:</p>



<ol>
<li>Identify the cause of the CrashLoopBackoff by looking at the application logs.</li>



<li>Check if the application has been configured correctly, if the resources are sufficient, and if the application is running in the correct environment.</li>



<li>Check for any networking or storage issues that could be causing the CrashLoopBackoff.</li>



<li>Attempt to restart the application.</li>



<li>If the restart is unsuccessful, look into other potential issues.</li>
</ol>



<p>By following these steps, you should be able to resolve the CrashLoopBackoff in no time.</p>



<h2>Common Mistakes to Avoid when Troubleshooting Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff</h2>



<p>When troubleshooting Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff, there are a few common mistakes that you should avoid.</p>



<p>First, it is important to avoid making assumptions about the cause of the CrashLoopBackoff. It is easy to jump to conclusions and assume that the issue is caused by a particular issue, but it is important to look into all potential causes before attempting to solve the issue.</p>



<p>Second, it is important to avoid making changes to the application or the Kubernetes cluster without first understanding the cause of the issue. Making changes without understanding the issue can lead to further complications and make the issue more difficult to troubleshoot.</p>



<p>Finally, it is important to avoid blindly restarting applications or the Kubernetes cluster. Restarting applications or the cluster without understanding the cause of the CrashLoopBackoff can mask the issue and make it more difficult to troubleshoot.</p>



<h2>Tools for Troubleshooting Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff</h2>



<p>Fortunately, there are a number of tools available to help you troubleshoot Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff.</p>



<p>The most useful tool for troubleshooting CrashLoopBackoff is the Kubernetes Dashboard. The Dashboard provides a graphical view of the cluster, allowing you to quickly identify and diagnose the issue. Additionally, the Dashboard provides helpful resources such as logs, metrics, and events that can be used to further investigate the cause of the CrashLoopBackoff.</p>



<p>Other useful tools for troubleshooting Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff include kubectl, the Kubernetes CLI, and the Kubernetes API server. These tools provide detailed information about the cluster, allowing you to quickly identify and diagnose the issue.</p>



<h2>Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff Solutions</h2>



<p>If you&#8217;ve been able to identify and resolve the underlying issue, the CrashLoopBackoff should be resolved. However, if you are still unable to resolve the issue, there are a few solutions that you can try.</p>



<p>One solution is to scale up the resources for the application. By scaling up the resources, you can ensure that the application has enough resources to run properly.</p>



<p>Another solution is to use a Kubernetes-native application such as Kubeless or Knative. These applications are designed to run on Kubernetes and can help to reduce the chances of the CrashLoopBackoff occurring.</p>



<p>Finally, you can also use a managed service such as Google Kubernetes Engine or <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/get-started/azure-portal" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="20" title="Azure" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Azure</a> Kubernetes Service. These services provide managed Kubernetes clusters that are optimized for performance and reliability, reducing the chances of the CrashLoopBackoff occurring.</p>



<h2>How to Avoid Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff</h2>



<p>The best way to avoid Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff is to ensure that the applications and infrastructure are configured correctly and that the resources are sufficient. Additionally, it is important to use Kubernetes-native applications or managed services to ensure optimal performance and reliability.</p>



<p>Additionally, it is important to monitor the applications and the Kubernetes cluster for any issues. By monitoring the applications and the cluster, you can quickly identify and diagnose any issues that could lead to the CrashLoopBackoff.</p>



<p>Finally, it is important to keep the applications and the Kubernetes cluster up-to-date with the latest patches and updates. Outdated applications and clusters can lead to instability and can increase the chances of the CrashLoopBackoff occurring.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Q&amp;A Section</h2>


<div id="rank-math-faq" class="rank-math-block">
<div class="rank-math-list ">
<div id="faq-question-1670693281509" class="rank-math-list-item">
<h3 class="rank-math-question "> What is Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff?</h3>
<div class="rank-math-answer ">

<p>Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff is an error that occurs when an application running in a Kubernetes cluster fails to start or restart successfully. This usually happens due to an issue with the application itself, or an underlying infrastructure issue.</p>

</div>
</div>
<div id="faq-question-1670693291066" class="rank-math-list-item">
<h3 class="rank-math-question ">What causes Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff?</h3>
<div class="rank-math-answer ">

<p>Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff can be caused by a number of different issues, ranging from application issues to underlying infrastructure issues. The most common causes of Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff are application issues such as bugs, memory leaks, or incompatible configurations; infrastructure issues such as insufficient resources, networking issues, or misconfigured storage; an incorrect or missing API key or authentication credentials; and issues with the Kubernetes API server or the Kubernetes control plane.</p>

</div>
</div>
<div id="faq-question-1670693303994" class="rank-math-list-item">
<h3 class="rank-math-question ">How do I troubleshoot Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff?</h3>
<div class="rank-math-answer ">

<p>When troubleshooting Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff, the first step is to identify what is causing the issue. To do this, you should start by looking at the logs for the application. The logs should provide insight into what is causing the CrashLoopBackoff, such as an application bug or a misconfigured resource. Once you have identified the cause of the issue, you can begin troubleshooting the problem.</p>

</div>
</div>
<div id="faq-question-1670693313441" class="rank-math-list-item">
<h3 class="rank-math-question ">How do I solve Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff?</h3>
<div class="rank-math-answer ">

<p>If you have identified and resolved the underlying issue, the CrashLoopBackoff should be resolved. If you are still unable to resolve the issue, you can try scaling up the resources for the application, using a Kubernetes-native application such as Kubeless or Knative, or using a managed service such as Google Kubernetes Engine or Azure Kubernetes Service.</p>

</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>


<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff can be a frustrating and confusing error to troubleshoot and solve. However, with the right knowledge and tools, it is possible to quickly identify and resolve the issue.</p>



<p>In this article, we discussed everything you need to know about Kubernetes CrashLoopBackoff, including what causes it, how to troubleshoot it, and how to solve it. We also discussed some of the common mistakes to avoid when troubleshooting CrashLoopBackoff, and some of the tools that can be used to troubleshoot the issue.</p>



<p>If you follow the steps outlined in this article, you should be able to quickly identify and resolve the CrashLoopBackoff in no time. Good luck!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>DevOps Interview with ChatGPT</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/devops-interview-with-chatgpt/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 20:15:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[interview]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2040</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[ChatGPT is a chatbot built on top of OpenAI. Using information from various sources, OpenAI is a language-processing model which can &#8216;learn&#8217; from natural language and provides responses in a variety of different formats. ChatGPT is an implementation of OpenAI&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://openai.com/blog/chatgpt/" data-type="URL" data-id="https://openai.com/blog/chatgpt/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">ChatGPT</a> is a chatbot built on top of OpenAI.  Using information from various sources, <a href="https://openai.com/" data-type="URL" data-id="https://openai.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">OpenAI</a> is a language-processing model which can &#8216;learn&#8217; from natural language and provides responses in a variety of different formats.  ChatGPT is an implementation of OpenAI which is meant to hold a natural conversation via chat about any topic.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>We’ve trained a model called ChatGPT which interacts in a conversational way. The dialogue format makes it possible for ChatGPT to answer followup questions, admit its mistakes, challenge incorrect premises, and reject inappropriate requests. ChatGPT is a sibling model to <a href="https://openai.com/blog/instruction-following/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">InstructGPT</a>, which is trained to follow an instruction in a prompt and provide a detailed&nbsp;response.</p>
<cite>https://openai.com/blog/chatgpt/</cite></blockquote>



<p>Below is the interview I conducted with ChatGPT about <a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a>!  All questions were asked exactly how they are displayed below.  Answers were taken directly from ChatGPT without any modifications.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>The ChatGPT DevOps Interview</h2>



<h3>Question: I was wondering if I could interview you about DevOps?</h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote block-quote-gray">
<p>Sure! I&#8217;d be happy to answer any questions you have about DevOps. DevOps is a software development methodology that combines software development (Dev) and information technology operations (Ops) to shorten the development life cycle and provide continuous delivery with high software quality. This approach aims to bring development and operations teams together to improve collaboration, automate processes, and speed up the delivery of new software features. Some of the key principles of DevOps include automation, continuous integration and delivery, collaboration, and monitoring.</p>



<p>Would you like to know more about specific aspects of DevOps? I can provide more information on topics such as the benefits of DevOps, common DevOps tools and practices, and how to get started with DevOps in your organization. Let me know if there&#8217;s anything specific you&#8217;d like to know!</p>
</blockquote>



<h3>Question: Yes, let&#8217;s start by talking about the benefits of DevOps. What do you think are the major benefits of adopting DevOps into an organization&#8217;s software development life cycle?</h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>Some of the major benefits of adopting DevOps into an organization&#8217;s software development life cycle include:</p>



<ul>
<li>Improved collaboration and communication: DevOps brings together development and operations teams to work closely together, improving collaboration and communication. This can lead to better alignment between teams and a more efficient software development process.</li>



<li>Faster time to market: By automating processes and integrating development and operations, DevOps can help organizations deliver new software features faster. This can give organizations a competitive advantage and allow them to quickly respond to changing market conditions.</li>



<li>Increased software quality: DevOps emphasizes continuous testing and monitoring, which can help identify and fix bugs and other issues early in the development process. This can result in higher-quality software and fewer issues in production.</li>



<li>Increased agility and flexibility: DevOps enables organizations to quickly and easily adapt to changing business needs and market conditions. By automating processes and integrating development and operations, organizations can quickly respond to new opportunities and challenges.</li>
</ul>



<p>Overall, the benefits of DevOps can help organizations improve collaboration, deliver new software features faster, increase software quality, and increase agility and flexibility. These benefits can help organizations stay competitive and respond quickly to changing market conditions.</p>
</blockquote>



<h3>Question: How does DevOps improve collaboration and communication?</h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>DevOps improves collaboration and communication by bringing together development and operations teams to work closely together. In a traditional software development process, these teams often work in silos, with little collaboration or communication. This can lead to misalignment, misunderstandings, and delays in the development process.</p>



<p>With DevOps, development and operations teams work together from the start of the development process. They share the same goals and work towards a common vision. This can improve collaboration and communication, and help teams align their efforts towards a common goal.</p>



<p>Additionally, DevOps emphasizes collaboration and communication throughout the development process. This can include regular meetings, real-time communication tools, and other collaborative practices. These practices can help teams stay aligned and on track, and quickly resolve any issues that arise.</p>



<p>Overall, by bringing development and operations teams together and emphasizing collaboration and communication, DevOps can help organizations improve collaboration and communication throughout the development process.</p>
</blockquote>



<h3>Question: What methods or ceremonies can a DevOps team use to improve collaboration and communication?</h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>There are several methods or ceremonies that a DevOps team can use to improve collaboration and communication. Some examples include:</p>



<ul>
<li>Regular meetings: One of the most effective ways to improve collaboration and communication is to hold regular meetings. These meetings can be used to discuss progress, share updates, and resolve any issues that arise. They can be held daily, weekly, or at other intervals, depending on the needs of the team.</li>



<li>Collaborative tools: Collaborative tools can also be used to improve collaboration and communication. These tools can include real-time communication platforms, project management tools, and other tools that enable teams to work together and share information.</li>



<li>Pair programming: Pair programming is a technique in which two developers work together on the same code. This can help improve collaboration and communication, as well as promote knowledge sharing and mentoring.</li>



<li>Continuous integration and delivery: Continuous integration and delivery (CI/CD) is a key practice in DevOps that involves automatically building, testing, and deploying code. This can help improve collaboration and communication by enabling teams to quickly and easily share code and integrate their work.</li>
</ul>



<p>Overall, there are many different methods and ceremonies that a DevOps team can use to improve collaboration and communication. These practices can help teams work together more effectively, align their efforts towards a common goal, and quickly resolve any issues that arise.</p>
</blockquote>



<h3>Question: How does DevOps promote a faster time to market?</h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>DevOps promotes a faster time to market by automating processes and integrating development and operations. In a traditional software development process, there are often long delays between the development and deployment of new software features. This can result in slower time to market and reduced competitiveness.</p>



<p>With DevOps, development and operations teams work closely together and automate as many processes as possible. This can include automating the build, testing, and deployment of code. By automating these processes, teams can quickly and easily deliver new software features to market.</p>



<p>Additionally, DevOps emphasizes continuous integration and delivery (CI/CD), which enables teams to regularly and automatically build, test, and deploy code. This can help teams deliver new software features faster, and reduce the time it takes to get new features to market.</p>



<p>Overall, by automating processes and emphasizing continuous integration and delivery, DevOps can help organizations deliver new software features faster and improve their time to market. This can give organizations a competitive advantage and allow them to quickly respond to changing market conditions.</p>
</blockquote>



<h3>Question: How do continuous integration and delivery reduce the time it takes to deliver new features to the market?</h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>Continuous integration and delivery (CI/CD) is a key practice in DevOps that involves automatically building, testing, and deploying code. This can help reduce the time it takes to deliver new features to the market in several ways:</p>



<ul>
<li>Automation: CI/CD automates the build, testing, and deployment of code, which can significantly reduce the time it takes to get new features to market. By automating these processes, teams can quickly and easily deliver new software features, without the need for manual processes and interventions.</li>



<li>Early identification and resolution of issues: CI/CD also enables teams to quickly identify and resolve issues in the code. By automatically building, testing, and deploying code on a regular basis, teams can identify and fix bugs and other issues early in the development process. This can help reduce the time it takes to get new features to market, and improve the overall quality of the software.</li>



<li>Faster feedback and iteration: CI/CD also enables teams to get feedback on new features faster. By automatically building, testing, and deploying code, teams can quickly see how their changes are working in production, and iterate on them based on feedback. This can help teams deliver new features faster, and improve the overall quality of the software.</li>
</ul>



<p>Overall, by automating the build, testing, and deployment of code, CI/CD can help teams deliver new features to market faster, and improve the overall quality of the software. This can give organizations a competitive advantage and allow them to quickly respond to changing market conditions.</p>
</blockquote>



<h3>Question: How does DevOps increase software quality?</h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>DevOps increases software quality by emphasizing continuous testing and monitoring. In a traditional software development process, testing is often done at the end of the development process, which can result in a large number of bugs and other issues being discovered only after the software has been released.</p>



<p>With DevOps, teams continuously test and monitor their code throughout the development process. This can include running automated tests on a regular basis, as well as using tools to monitor the performance and stability of the software in production. By continuously testing and monitoring their code, teams can identify and fix issues early in the development process, before they become major problems.</p>



<p>Additionally, DevOps emphasizes collaboration and communication between development and operations teams. This can help teams quickly identify and resolve issues, and improve the overall quality of the software.</p>



<p>Overall, by emphasizing continuous testing and monitoring, and promoting collaboration and communication, DevOps can help teams deliver higher-quality software and reduce the number of issues in production. This can improve the user experience and the overall success of the software.</p>
</blockquote>



<h3>Question: How do DevOps teams continuously test and monitor their code throughout the development process?</h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>DevOps teams continuously test and monitor their code throughout the development process using a variety of tools and practices. Some examples include:</p>



<ul>
<li>Automated testing: Automated testing is a key practice in DevOps that involves running automated tests on a regular basis. These tests can include unit tests, integration tests, and other types of tests that validate the functionality and performance of the software. By running automated tests on a regular basis, teams can quickly and easily identify and fix issues in the code.</li>



<li>Continuous integration and delivery (CI/CD): Continuous integration and delivery (CI/CD) is a key practice in DevOps that involves automatically building, testing, and deploying code. This can help teams continuously test and monitor their code, by automatically running tests and deploying code on a regular basis.</li>



<li>Monitoring tools: DevOps teams also use monitoring tools to continuously monitor the performance and stability of their software in production. These tools can track key metrics such as response time, error rates, and resource utilization, and alert teams when issues arise. By continuously monitoring their software, teams can quickly identify and resolve issues, and improve the overall quality of the software.</li>
</ul>



<p>Overall, DevOps teams use a combination of automated testing, CI/CD, and monitoring tools to continuously test and monitor their code throughout the development process. This can help teams deliver higher-quality software and reduce the number of issues in production.</p>
</blockquote>



<h3>Question: How does DevOps help an organization increase agility and flexibility with its products?</h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>DevOps helps organizations increase agility and flexibility with their products by automating processes and integrating development and operations. In a traditional software development process, there are often long delays and bottlenecks in the development process, which can make it difficult for organizations to quickly and easily respond to changing business needs and market conditions.</p>



<p>With DevOps, development and operations teams work closely together and automate as many processes as possible. This can include automating the build, testing, and deployment of code, as well as automating other processes such as provisioning and configuration management. By automating these processes, teams can quickly and easily adapt to changing business needs and market conditions.</p>



<p>Additionally, DevOps emphasizes continuous integration and delivery (CI/CD), which enables teams to regularly and automatically build, test, and deploy code. This can help teams quickly and easily iterate on their products, and respond to feedback and changes in the market.</p>



<p>Overall, by automating processes and emphasizing continuous integration and delivery, DevOps can help organizations increase their agility and flexibility with their products. This can enable organizations to quickly and easily respond to changing business needs and market conditions, and stay competitive.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h3>Segue: Thank you for answering my questions so far!</h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>You&#8217;re welcome! I&#8217;m glad I could help. Is there anything else you&#8217;d like to know about DevOps? I&#8217;m here to answer any questions you may have.</p>
</blockquote>



<h3>Question: What are some of the biggest challenges an organization can face when going through a transformation to adopt DevOps as their technology delivery methodology?</h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>Some of the biggest challenges an organization can face when going through a transformation to adopt DevOps as their technology delivery methodology include:</p>



<ul>
<li>Culture and mindset: One of the biggest challenges in adopting DevOps is changing the culture and mindset of the organization. DevOps requires a shift away from siloed teams and towards collaboration and communication. This can be a significant change for organizations, and requires a commitment to embracing new ways of working.</li>



<li>Resistance to change: Another challenge in adopting DevOps is overcoming resistance to change. Many organizations are comfortable with their existing processes and ways of working, and may be resistant to changing them. This can make it difficult to implement DevOps, and may require leadership and management support to overcome.</li>



<li>Lack of skills and expertise: Another challenge in adopting DevOps is a lack of skills and expertise. DevOps requires a combination of development, operations, and other technical skills, and many organizations may not have the necessary expertise in-house. This can require organizations to invest in training and hiring new talent, or partnering with external organizations that have the necessary skills and expertise.</li>



<li>Integration with existing systems and processes: Another challenge in adopting DevOps is integrating it with existing systems and processes. DevOps requires a significant amount of automation and integration, and organizations may have legacy systems and processes that are difficult to integrate with. This can require organizations to invest in new technologies and tools, and may require significant planning and coordination to implement successfully.</li>
</ul>



<p>Overall, there are many challenges that organizations can face when going through a transformation to adopt DevOps. These challenges can include cultural and mindset changes, resistance to change, a lack of skills and expertise, and integration with existing systems and processes. Organizations need to carefully plan and manage their DevOps transformation in order to overcome these challenges and achieve success.</p>
</blockquote>



<h3>Question: Why are culture and mindset important when adopting DevOps?</h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>Culture and mindset are important when adopting DevOps because DevOps requires a significant shift in how organizations approach software development. In a traditional software development process, teams often work in silos, with little collaboration or communication. This can lead to misalignment, misunderstandings, and delays in the development process.</p>



<p>DevOps, on the other hand, emphasizes collaboration and communication between development and operations teams. This requires a shift in culture and mindset, from siloed teams to cross-functional teams that work together towards a common goal. This can be a significant change for organizations, and requires a commitment to embracing new ways of working.</p>



<p>Additionally, DevOps requires a mindset of continuous improvement and experimentation. This means that teams need to be open to trying new approaches and learning from failures, in order to continually improve the software development process. This can be a significant change for many organizations, and requires a commitment to learning and experimentation.</p>



<p>Overall, culture and mindset are important when adopting DevOps because DevOps requires a shift in how organizations approach software development. This requires a commitment to collaboration, communication, and continuous improvement, and can be a significant change for many organizations.</p>
</blockquote>



<h3>Question: What happens to an organization when resistance to change happens in the DevOps adoption process?</h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>When resistance to change happens in the DevOps adoption process, it can make it difficult for organizations to successfully implement DevOps. Resistance to change can come from many different sources, pink flamingos essay reflection.</p>



<p>If resistance to change is not addressed, it can lead to delays and problems in the DevOps adoption process. For example, teams may be reluctant to adopt new practices and tools, or may be resistant to collaborating with other teams. This can lead to misunderstandings, conflicts, and delays in the development process.</p>



<p>Additionally, resistance to change can lead to a lack of buy-in and support for the DevOps adoption process. This can make it difficult to secure the necessary resources and support to successfully implement DevOps, and may require leadership and management support to overcome.</p>



<p>Overall, when resistance to change happens in the DevOps adoption process, it can lead to delays, conflicts, and a lack of support for the adoption process. This can make it difficult for organizations to successfully implement DevOps, and may require leadership and management support to overcome.</p>
</blockquote>



<h3>Question: Why are skill and expertise important when adopting DevOps?</h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>Skills and expertise are important when adopting DevOps because DevOps requires a combination of development, operations, and other technical skills. In a traditional software development process, development and operations teams often have different skills and expertise, and may not be equipped to work together effectively.</p>



<p>DevOps, on the other hand, requires development and operations teams to work closely together, and to have a broad range of skills and expertise. This can include skills in areas such as automation, continuous integration and delivery, and monitoring and observability. Without these skills, teams may struggle to implement DevOps effectively, and may not be able to take full advantage of its benefits.</p>



<p>Additionally, DevOps emphasizes learning and experimentation, which requires teams to have the skills and expertise to quickly learn and adapt to new technologies and approaches. This can be a significant challenge for organizations, and may require them to invest in training and development, or to hire new talent with the necessary skills and expertise.</p>



<p>Overall, skills and expertise are important when adopting DevOps because DevOps requires a broad range of development, operations, and other technical skills. Without these skills, teams may struggle to implement DevOps effectively, and may not be able to take full advantage of its benefits.</p>
</blockquote>



<h3>Question: Why is it important for the DevOps methodology to integrate with existing processes?</h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>It is important for the DevOps methodology to integrate with existing processes because DevOps typically involves significant automation and integration. In a traditional software development process, there are often many manual processes and interventions that can slow down the development process and lead to errors and delays.</p>



<p>DevOps, on the other hand, emphasizes automation and integration, which can help speed up the development process and improve its efficiency. This can involve integrating DevOps tools and practices with existing systems and processes, such as version control systems, build systems, and deployment pipelines. By integrating DevOps with existing processes, organizations can take advantage of its benefits without disrupting their existing operations.</p>



<p>Additionally, integrating DevOps with existing processes can help ensure that the organization is able to take full advantage of its benefits. For example, by integrating DevOps with existing monitoring and alerting systems, organizations can quickly and easily detect and resolve issues in their software. This can help improve the overall quality and reliability of the software, and ensure that the organization is able to take full advantage of DevOps.</p>



<p>Overall, it is important for the DevOps methodology to integrate with existing processes because DevOps typically involves significant automation and integration. By integrating DevOps with existing processes, organizations can take advantage of its benefits without disrupting their existing operations, and ensure that they are able to take full advantage of its benefits.</p>
</blockquote>



<h3>Final Thoughts: Thank you for your time today. In the future, i would like to come back and ask some questions about tools, practices, and how to get started. Would that be ok with you?</h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>Of course! I would be happy to help you with any questions you have about DevOps tools, practices, and how to get started. Just let me know when you&#8217;re ready, and I&#8217;ll be here to assist you. In the meantime, if you have any other questions, feel free to ask. I&#8217;m here to help!</p>
</blockquote>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>The interview was interesting.  Obviously, ChatGPT is not a sentient being with its own original thoughts so I am not entirely surprised that the answers that were provided were holistically academic in nature.</p>



<p>The most interesting point is the fact that most of the freely available information about the DevOps methodology and its implementation in an organization is entirely academic in nature.  It is aspirational content that speaks to a better way of delivering technology but really lacks many real tactics for getting there.</p>



<p>This blog is looking to solve that.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Solve Your Kubernetes Pod Stuck in Terminating Status Woes in no Time</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/kubernetes-pod-stuck-terminating/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 02:17:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Kubernetes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[day2ops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[howto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tools]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2031</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Kubernetes is a powerful tool for managing complex containerized applications. It helps developers quickly deploy, scale, and manage their applications. However, with great power comes great responsibility and Kubernetes has its share of issues that can cause headaches for developers.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://kubernetes.io/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="4" title="Kubernetes" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Kubernetes</a> is a powerful tool for managing complex containerized applications. It helps developers quickly deploy, scale, and manage their applications.</p>



<p>However, with great power comes great responsibility and Kubernetes has its share of issues that can cause headaches for developers. One of the most dreaded issues is the Kubernetes &#8220;pod stuck terminating&#8221; issue.</p>



<p>In this article, we’ll discuss what this issue is, the common causes, how to diagnose a stuck pod, strategies for solving the issue, a step-by-step guide to solving the issue, best practices for avoiding the issue in the future, troubleshooting tips for Kubernetes pods, useful tools for monitoring and managing Kubernetes pods, courses and tutorials on Kubernetes pod management, and more.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>What is the Kubernetes &#8220;Pod Stuck Terminating&#8221; Issue?</h2>



<p>The Kubernetes pod stuck terminating issue occurs when a pod remains in the “Terminating” state for an extended period of time. This can be caused by a number of different issues and can be quite frustrating for developers.</p>



<p>The issue can manifest itself in a number of ways. For example, you may see that your pod is stuck in the “Terminating” state and never fully terminates and continues to consume resources. You may check the host to which the pod was assigned, and the <a href="https://www.docker.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="16" title="Docker" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Docker</a> container and underlying PID have been terminated, but Kubernetes is reporting it as stuck in a terminating state.</p>



<p>Regardless of the issue, the Kubernetes pod stuck terminating issue can be a major headache for developers and can cause serious delays in deploying applications.</p>



<h2>Common Causes of Pods Becoming Stuck</h2>



<p>The Kubernetes pod stuck terminating issue can be caused by a number of different issues. The most common causes include:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Not enough resources:</strong> Kubernetes pods require sufficient resources in order to function properly. If there aren’t enough resources available, the pod may get stuck in the “Terminating” state. It is important to look at the state of your worker node at the time the pod went unresponsive. If all system resources were consumed, like a disk filling up, then Kubernetes may not actually be the core issue to diagnose.</li>



<li><strong>Contention for resources:</strong> If there are multiple pods competing for resources, one of the pods may get stuck in the “Terminating” state as it waits for resources to become available.</li>



<li><strong>Problems with the pod: </strong>If there is something wrong with the pod itself, it may get stuck in the “Terminating” state. This could be due to an issue with the code, configuration, or other problems.</li>



<li><strong>Issues with the Kubernetes cluster:</strong> If there is something wrong with the Kubernetes cluster itself, it may cause the pod to get stuck in the “Terminating” state. This can happen when cluster communications become disconnected from a blip or network partition. The worker node may be functioning as expected, but cannot tell the Kubernetes API that it is working properly.</li>
</ul>



<h2>How to Diagnose a Stuck Pod</h2>



<p>If you find that your Kubernetes pod is stuck in the “Terminating” state, there are a few steps you can take to diagnose the issue.</p>



<p>The first thing you should do is check the logs. Check the logs for the pod to see if there are any error messages or warnings that could indicate the cause of the issue.</p>



<p>Next, you should check the resource utilization of the pod. If the pod is consuming too many resources, it could be causing issues.</p>



<p>After that, you should check the resource utilization on the server at the time the pod became stuck in a terminating state. If the server ran out of disk, the pod became stuck, but now system resources look fine; the reality is that the processes on the server itself may be in an unknown or unrecoverable state without a reboot.</p>



<p>Finally, you should check the status of the node from kubectl. If the node is not reporting itself as healthy via `kubectl get nodes` then that node should be drained, which may not be possible, and subsequently rebooted and its health re-reviewed.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Strategies for Solving the Issue</h2>



<p>Once you’ve identified the cause of the issue, there are a few strategies you can use to solve the issue.</p>



<h3>Check the Worker Node</h3>



<p>First, check the worker node that was running the pod to see what state the underlying container is in via <code>ctr</code>. If the container is no longer running, the next thing to check is for running PIDs on the system that matches the process being run by the container. If there are no relevant PIDs, then you can run <code>kubectl delete pod --force=true --grace-period=0 -n &lt;NAMESPACE&gt; &lt;STUCK POD NAME&gt;</code> to forcibly remove the pod from the Kubernetes API.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/2139.png" alt="ℹ" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Depending on your version of Kubernetes, you may have Docker or Container.io as a container runtime.  If you have docker, use <code>docker ps</code> to check container status.  If you have Container.io you will use <code>runc</code> or <code>ctr</code> to check the status of your pods.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>In this scenario, a pod was successfully terminated on the worker system, but the Kubernetes worker or the API is out of sync with each other and neither of them really knows the state of the pod.</p>



<p>Signs may point to the issue being fixed after this, but in my experience, you should go ahead and do a full health check of your cluster as this is an edge case caused by some underlying issue somewhere else.</p>



<h3>Keep Checking the Worker Node</h3>



<p>I am cheating here slightly. This is an extension of &#8220;Check the Worker Node&#8221;, but we will assume that the pod is actually still running and has not terminated.</p>



<p>When a pod is stuck in a terminating state this way, the PID that the pod was managing may not be terminating properly. Checking logs here should be the first step. I have run into issues in the past where applications are not properly listening to system signals like SIGHUP to know it is time to terminate.</p>



<p>If you are running internally developed software, check with your development teams to see how the application responds to system signals.</p>



<h3>Rolling Reboots</h3>



<p>The worker node may be perfectly healthy in some instances. Working backward, there could be a problem with either the Kubernetes API receiving update information from worker nodes, a network partition / other network issues, or the ETCd cluster may not be synchronizing properly across all nodes and refusing new write operations.</p>



<p>If you are in a highly resilient state in your Kubernetes cluster, load-balanced masters with multiple ETCd nodes, then a rolling reboot should not hurt anything. Your rolling reboot at that layer should be properly communicated to any parties that could be impacted.</p>



<p>In my experience, this may fix a multitude of issues that may not even be presenting themselves. This is why communication is important. There may be resources that are suddenly rebooted or changed in a way that your business partners were not expecting.</p>



<h2>A Step-By-Step Guide to Solving the Issue</h2>



<p>If you find that your Kubernetes pod is stuck in the “Terminating” state, here’s a step-by-step guide to solving the issue:</p>



<ol>
<li>Check the worker node for signs of stuck PIDs or stuck containers through `ctr`</li>
</ol>



<p>If the node has stuck PIDs or a stuck container, the process running inside of the container is not properly listening to system signals like SIGHUP. File a bug report with the application developers for guidance or bug fixes.</p>



<ol>
<li>Check the worker kubelet process logs for signs errors</li>



<li>Check the master&#8217;s kubelet process logs for signs of errors</li>



<li>Check the master&#8217;s kube-scheduler process logs for signs of errors</li>



<li>Check the master&#8217;s kube-controller-manager process logs for signs of errors</li>



<li>Check the master&#8217;s kube-apiserver process logs for signs of errors</li>
</ol>



<p>If any of these checks present an issue, it is time to start rolling reboots of nodes in your cluster. Start with the impacted worker and move your way back to the masters. Other workers in the cluster probably do not need a reboot.</p>



<ol>
<li>Check server resources at the time the pod became stuck in a terminating state.</li>
</ol>



<p>If this is the case, look for both a root cause of why the server filled up, and perform a reboot on the server. Servers become very unhappy when resources like disks become inaccessible due to capacity issues.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Best Practices for Avoiding the Issue in the Future</h2>



<p>Once you’ve solved the Kubernetes pod stuck terminating issue, it’s important to take steps to avoid the issue in the future. Here are some best practices for avoiding the issue:</p>



<ul>
<li>Monitor your pods: Monitor your pods to make sure they’re not consuming too many resources.</li>



<li>Set limits on resources: Set limits on the resources that your pods can consume to avoid resource contention.</li>



<li>Check your code: Make sure your code is correct and that your pods are properly configured.</li>



<li>Test your pods: Test your pods before deploying them to make sure they’re functioning properly.</li>



<li>Upgrade your cluster: Make sure your Kubernetes cluster is up-to-date to avoid issues.</li>
</ul>



<h2>Troubleshooting Tips for Kubernetes Pods</h2>



<p>If you’re having issues with your Kubernetes pods, here are some troubleshooting tips to help you identify and solve the issue:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Check the logs:</strong> Check the logs for your pod to see if there are any error messages or warnings.</li>



<li><strong>Check the resource utilization:</strong> Check the resource utilization of your pod to make sure it’s not consuming too many resources.</li>



<li><strong>Check the status of the pod:</strong> Check the status of the pod to make sure it’s not stuck in the “Terminating” state.</li>



<li><strong>Try scaling up the resources: </strong>Try scaling up the resources for the pod to see if that helps to resolve the issue.</li>



<li><strong>Try restarting the pod:</strong> Try restarting the pod to see if that helps to resolve the issue.</li>



<li><strong>Try deleting the pod:</strong> Try deleting the pod and recreating it to see if that helps to resolve the issue.</li>
</ul>



<h2>Useful Tools for Monitoring and Managing Kubernetes Pods</h2>



<p>There are a number of useful tools that can help you monitor and manage your Kubernetes pods. These tools can help you identify and solve issues with your pods.</p>



<p>Some of the most popular tools include:</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://kubernetes.io/docs/tasks/access-application-cluster/web-ui-dashboard/" target="_blank" data-type="URL" data-id="https://kubernetes.io/docs/tasks/access-application-cluster/web-ui-dashboard/" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Kubernetes Dashboard</a>: This open-source dashboard allows you to monitor and manage your Kubernetes pods.</li>



<li><a href="https://prometheus.io/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="2" title="Prometheus" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Prometheus</a>: This open-source monitoring tool allows you to monitor your Kubernetes clusters and pods.</li>



<li><a href="https://aquasecurity.github.io/kube-hunter/" target="_blank" data-type="URL" data-id="https://aquasecurity.github.io/kube-hunter/" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Kube-Hunter</a>: This open-source security tool allows you to scan your Kubernetes clusters for security issues.</li>



<li><a href="https://helm.sh/" target="_blank" data-type="URL" data-id="https://helm.sh/" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Helm</a>: This open-source package manager allows you to easily install and manage applications on your Kubernetes cluster.</li>
</ul>



<h2>Courses and Tutorials on Kubernetes Pod Management</h2>



<p>If you’re looking to learn more about managing Kubernetes pods, there are a number of courses and tutorials available. Here are some of the best courses and tutorials:</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.udemy.com/course/the-complete-guide-to-kubernetes-3-course-bundle/" target="_blank" data-type="URL" data-id="https://www.udemy.com/course/the-complete-guide-to-kubernetes-3-course-bundle/" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Kubernetes The Complete Guide</a>: This course covers everything you need to know about managing Kubernetes pods.</li>



<li><a href="https://training.linuxfoundation.org/training/kubernetes-fundamentals/" target="_blank" data-type="URL" data-id="https://training.linuxfoundation.org/training/kubernetes-fundamentals/" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Kubernetes Fundamentals</a>: This tutorial covers the basics of managing Kubernetes pods.</li>



<li><a href="https://kubernetesbootcamp.github.io/kubernetes-bootcamp/" target="_blank" data-type="URL" data-id="https://kubernetesbootcamp.github.io/kubernetes-bootcamp/" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Kubernetes Bootcamp</a>: This course covers the fundamentals of managing Kubernetes clusters and pods.</li>



<li><a href="https://kubernetes.io/docs/concepts/configuration/manage-resources-containers/" target="_blank" data-type="URL" data-id="https://kubernetes.io/docs/concepts/configuration/manage-resources-containers/" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Kubernetes Pod Management</a>: This tutorial covers the basics of managing Kubernetes pods.</li>
</ul>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>The dreaded Kubernetes &#8220;pod stuck terminating&#8221; issue can be a major headache for developers and systems administration teams.</p>



<p>In this article, we’ve discussed what this issue is, the common causes, how to diagnose a stuck pod, strategies for solving the issue, a step-by-step guide to solving the issue, best practices for avoiding the issue in the future, troubleshooting tips for Kubernetes pods, useful tools for monitoring and managing Kubernetes pods, courses and tutorials on Kubernetes pod management, and more.</p>



<p>If you’re having issues with your Kubernetes pods, try following the steps outlined in this article. And remember, if you’re looking to learn more about managing Kubernetes pods, there are a number of courses and tutorials available to help you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Unlock the Power of DevOps Shift-Left Testing</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/devops-shift-left-testing/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 21:56:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[delivery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[howto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sdlc]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2014</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Are you looking for ways to accelerate the development process and reduce costs? Shifting testing to the left should be on your radar. Automated testing is a practice that helps accelerate your flow of value to the market, and if&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Are you looking for ways to accelerate the development process and reduce costs? Shifting testing to the left should be on your radar.  <a href="https://www.valewood.org/devops-testing/" data-type="post" data-id="1239">Automated testing </a>is a practice that helps accelerate your <a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/benefits-of-devops/devops-flow/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="28" title="Understanding the DevOps Process Flow in 2022" target="_blank" rel="noopener">flow of value</a> to the market, and if you haven&#8217;t started building automated testing yet, you should start ASAP!</p>



<p>Shift-left testing is a practice of testing earlier in the development lifecycle, allowing teams to catch bugs before they become costly and time-consuming issues.</p>



<p>In this blog, I&#8217;ll explain what <a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> shift-left testing is, the benefits and challenges of the practice, and how to implement it. I&#8217;ll also provide tips for effective shift-left testing, best practices for automation, and advice on monitoring and analyzing this type of testing.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Introduction to DevOps Shift-Left Testing</h2>



<p>DevOps shift-left testing is the practice of shifting testing activities to the left in the software development process. It involves testing at each stage of the software development lifecycle (SDLC) instead of waiting until the end. This shift-left approach enables teams to catch and address any issues much earlier in the process, saving time and money.</p>



<p>To give some context on the difference between shifting testing to the left and a more traditional testing process, think about a Waterfall project flow. In the waterfall, delivery steps are completed and moved down the assembly line to the next station to get validated or integrated. If there is an issue, it can bring the entire assembly line to a halt.</p>



<p>By moving testing activities earlier in the development cycle, aka shifting left on a delivery timeline, your quality engineering staff are proactively defining the conditions for success through automation. This turns the tables around where quality issues are discovered and remediated causing fewer impacting blockages in your pipelines.</p>



<p>By moving testing activities to the left, teams can find and fix bugs and other issues before they become costly and time-consuming problems. This is crucial for any organization that wants to succeed in the ever-changing world of technology. With DevOps shift-left testing, organizations can reduce the time and cost associated with testing, speed up the development process, and improve the overall quality of their products.</p>



<h2>What is Shift-Left Testing?</h2>



<p>Shift-left testing is the practice of testing earlier in the software development process and shifting activities to the left on a product delivery timeline. It involves testing at each stage of the SDLC, rather than waiting until the end. This shift-left approach enables teams to catch and address any issues much earlier in the process, saving time and money.</p>



<p>Organizations that do proactive planning and discovery on requirements, architecture, and design should also be conceptualizing their quality controls early and often.</p>



<p>Through years of continuous improvement, auto manufacturers have made huge strides to integrate test automation into every stage of their delivery processes. They have done this to reduce their time to market and increase their overall quality.</p>



<p>Shift-left testing helps technology organizations reduce the time and cost associated with testing, speed up the development process, and improve the overall quality of their products. It also allows teams to gain better visibility into their development process, identify potential issues before they become costly problems, and ensure that the quality of their product meets customer expectations.</p>



<p>Shifting Left with testing is also a core tenant of practicing Agile DevOps. Complex systems become easier to manage over the long term when automated testing is integrated early in the development lifecycle.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Benefits of Shift-Left Testing</h2>



<p>Shift-left testing offers many benefits for organizations that are looking to accelerate the development process and reduce costs. Here are some of the key benefits of this practice:</p>



<ol>
<li>It reduces the time and cost associated with testing. By shifting testing activities to the left, teams can catch and address issues much earlier in the process, saving time and money.</li>



<li>It speeds up the development process. With shift-left testing, teams can quickly identify and address any issues, reducing the amount of time it takes to develop a product.</li>



<li>It improves the overall quality of the product. By testing earlier in the process, teams can ensure that the product meets customer expectations and has fewer bugs.</li>



<li>It allows teams to gain better visibility into their development process. With shift-left testing, teams can identify potential issues before they become costly problems.</li>



<li>It increases customer satisfaction. By testing earlier in the process and ensuring that the quality of the product meets customer expectations, organizations can improve customer satisfaction.</li>
</ol>



<h2>Challenges of Shift-Left Testing</h2>



<p>Although shift-left testing offers many benefits, it also comes with certain challenges. Here are some of the key challenges of this practice:</p>



<ol>
<li>It requires a change in mindset. Organizations must shift their mindset from testing at the end of the development process to testing at each stage of the SDLC.</li>



<li>It requires a shift in resource allocation. Organizations must allocate more resources to testing activities earlier in the process.</li>



<li>It requires more collaboration between teams. Organizations must ensure that all teams involved in the development process are collaborating effectively to ensure that shift-left testing is effective.</li>



<li>It requires a shift in tools and technologies. Organizations must ensure that they have the right tools and technologies in place to support shift-left testing.</li>



<li>It requires more communication. Organizations must ensure that all stakeholders are kept informed of any changes or issues related to shift-left testing.</li>
</ol>



<h2>How to Implement Shift-Left Testing</h2>



<p>If you&#8217;re looking to implement shift-left testing, there are several steps you can take to ensure success. Here are some tips to help you get started:</p>



<ol>
<li>Align your goals. Before you begin, make sure that all stakeholders have a clear understanding of the goals of shift-left testing and how it will benefit the organization.</li>



<li>Develop a plan. Develop a plan that outlines how you will implement shift-left testing, including which tools and technologies you will use and how you will measure success.</li>



<li>Train your teams. Ensure that all teams involved in the development process are trained on the principles of shift-left testing and how to use the tools and technologies.</li>



<li>Monitor progress. Monitor the progress of shift-left testing and identify any issues that need to be addressed.</li>



<li>Adjust as needed. Adjust the plan as needed to ensure that the process of shift-left testing is effective and efficient.</li>
</ol>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Best Practices for Shift-Left Testing</h2>



<p>When it comes to shift-left testing, there are several best practices that organizations should follow to ensure success. Here are some of the key best practices:</p>



<ol>
<li>Automate whenever possible. Automation can help reduce the time and cost associated with shift-left testing, so it should be used whenever possible.</li>



<li>Set clear goals and timelines. Make sure that all stakeholders have a clear understanding of the goals of shift-left testing and how long it will take to implement.</li>



<li>Focus on quality. Shift-left testing should be used to ensure that the product meets customer expectations and has fewer bugs.</li>



<li>Monitor performance. Monitor the performance of shift-left testing and adjust the plan as needed to ensure that it is effective and efficient.</li>



<li>Communicate with stakeholders. Make sure that all stakeholders are kept informed of any changes or issues related to shift-left testing.</li>
</ol>



<h2>Automation of Shift-Left Testing</h2>



<p>Automation is a key component of shift-left testing. Automation can help reduce the time and cost associated with testing, and it can also help teams identify and address any issues much earlier in the process. Here are some tips for automating shift-left testing:</p>



<ol>
<li>Use the right tools and technologies. Make sure that you have the right tools and technologies in place to support shift-left testing.</li>



<li>Identify which tasks to automate. Identify which tasks can be automated and which tasks require manual testing.</li>



<li>Monitor progress. Monitor the progress of automation and adjust the plan as needed to ensure that it is effective and efficient.</li>



<li>Test the automation. Make sure to test the automation to ensure that it is working as expected.</li>



<li>Communicate with stakeholders. Make sure that all stakeholders are kept informed of any changes or issues related to automation.</li>
</ol>



<h2>Tips for Effective Shift-Left Testing</h2>



<p>If you&#8217;re looking to make shift-left testing effective, here are some tips to help you:</p>



<ol>
<li>Prioritize testing activities. Make sure that testing activities are prioritized and that they are aligned with the goals of the organization.</li>



<li>Automate whenever possible. Automation can help reduce the time and cost associated with shift-left testing, so it should be used whenever possible.</li>



<li>Monitor performance. Monitor the performance of shift-left testing and adjust the plan as needed to ensure that it is effective and efficient.</li>



<li>Communicate with stakeholders. Make sure that all stakeholders are kept informed of any changes or issues related to shift-left testing.</li>



<li>Measure success. Ensure that you have a way to measure the success of shift-left testing so that you can make adjustments if needed.</li>
</ol>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Monitoring and Analyzing Shift-Left Testing</h2>



<p>Once you&#8217;ve implemented shift-left testing, it&#8217;s important to monitor and analyze the results. Here are some tips for monitoring and analyzing shift-left testing:</p>



<ol>
<li>Track progress. Track the progress of shift-left testing to identify any issues that need to be addressed.</li>



<li>Analyze results. Analyze the results of shift-left testing to determine if it is effective and efficient.</li>



<li>Make adjustments. Make adjustments to the plan as needed to ensure that shift-left testing is effective and efficient.</li>



<li>Measure success. Ensure that you have a way to measure the success of shift-left testing so that you can make adjustments if needed.</li>



<li>Communicate with stakeholders. Make sure that all stakeholders are kept informed of any changes or issues related to shift-left testing.</li>
</ol>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>Shift-left testing is a powerful practice that can help organizations accelerate the development process and reduce costs. By shifting testing activities to the left, teams can catch and address any issues much earlier in the process, saving time and money. However, shift-left testing is not without its challenges. Organizations must shift their mindset, allocate more resources to testing activities, and ensure that all teams involved in the development process are collaborating effectively.</p>



<p>If you&#8217;re looking to make the move to shift-left testing, there are several steps you can take to ensure success. You should align your goals, develop a plan, train your teams, monitor progress, and adjust as needed. You should also prioritize testing activities, automate whenever possible, and measure success. Finally, you should monitor and analyze the results of shift-left testing to determine if it is effective and efficient.</p>



<p>So, if you&#8217;re looking to accelerate the development process and reduce costs, shift-left testing is the way to go. With shift-left testing, you can reduce the time and cost associated with testing, speed up the development process, and improve the overall quality of your products. So, what are you waiting for? Take the plunge and make the move to shift-left testing today!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>6 Common Misconceptions about Agile and DevOps</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/devops-and-agile-misconceptions/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 14:20:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[agile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sdlc]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1966</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In this blog, we discuss&#160;DevOps and Agile at great length. DevOps is a methodology for technology delivery while Agile is a methodology for project management. The two pair together quite well to increase the&#160;flow of value&#160;to the market. They can&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In this blog, we discuss&nbsp;<a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> and Agile at great length. DevOps is a methodology for technology delivery while Agile is a methodology for project management. The two pair together quite well to increase the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/benefits-of-devops/devops-flow/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="28" title="Understanding the DevOps Process Flow in 2022" target="_blank" rel="noopener">flow of value</a>&nbsp;to the market.</p>



<p>They can also be intertwined and confusing leading to misconceptions if one isn&#8217;t careful in their adoption journey. Let&#8217;s dive in and discuss the most common misconception about DevOps and Agile!</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>What Are the Most Common Misconceptions About Agile and DevOps?</h2>



<p>There are several common misconceptions that surface quickly when businesses are evaluating DevOps and Agile either independently or together. It is not entirely unreasonable to assume that anyone in the software development space could quickly make the jump from hearing about how awesome DevOps and Agile are into these misconceptions.</p>



<p>Below are a few of those misconceptions.</p>



<h3>Common Misconception #1</h3>



<div style="height:12px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<figure class="wp-block-pullquote has-border-color has-background has-small-font-size" style="border-color:#abb7c266;border-width:1px;border-radius:8px;background-color:#abb7c20d;font-style:normal;font-weight:500"><blockquote><p>DevOps and Agile can fill gaps in my poorly running delivery process</p></blockquote></figure>



<div style="height:28px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<p>DevOps and Agile are commonly viewed as a tool to fill a gap in software development delivery activities. If delivery cycles are variable in length, inconsistent, and filled with twists and turns; companies will look for some quick outs to patch up their delivery to ship something.</p>



<p>The problem with this approach is low&nbsp;<a href="https://valewood.org/topics/devops/benefits-of-devops/devops-culture-of-quality" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>quality</strong></a>.</p>



<p>While borrowing from DevOps and Agile might work in the short term, it does not work over the long term. Companies or projects looking to step up their delivery processes need to look at things holistically and make some choices about how they want to engage in the market with their customers.</p>



<h3>Common Misconception #2</h3>



<div style="height:12px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<figure class="wp-block-pullquote has-border-color has-background has-small-font-size" style="border-color:#abb7c266;border-width:1px;border-radius:8px;background-color:#abb7c20d;font-style:normal;font-weight:500"><blockquote><p>DevOps and/or Agile can be purchased off the shelf and implemented</p></blockquote></figure>



<div style="height:28px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<p>DevOps and/or Agile cannot be purchased. There is no singular toolset, workbook, or process that can be purchased and put in place to shortcut the adoption of these methodologies. Both of these methodologies are a fundamental transformation of delivery and need to be adopted fully in order to be effective.</p>



<p>This transformation is also cross-cutting throughout all technical and non-technical roles. A sales team cannot assume that groups delivering technology are delivering in a different way than they are selling.</p>



<p>Account management cannot build plans with customers on their future technology state and expect that planning to look different than the overall delivery workflows. Technology groups cannot adopt a different way of delivering if it is at odds with business expectations.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h3>Common Misconception #3</h3>



<div style="height:12px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<figure class="wp-block-pullquote has-border-color has-background has-small-font-size" style="border-color:#abb7c266;border-width:1px;border-radius:8px;background-color:#abb7c20d;font-style:normal;font-weight:500"><blockquote><p>DevOps can be implemented without Agile</p></blockquote></figure>



<div style="height:28px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<p>Now, that statement is a little clickbaity. You can indeed implement DevOps inside of other project management frameworks.</p>



<p>I would make the argument that you cannot fully realize the benefits of delivery transformation unless you adopt both DevOps and Agile. DevOps practices do not lend themselves well to Waterfall, but it can be done. You really lose out on all of the continuous improvement facets of DevOps which really means you are adopting some automation and calling it “DevOps”.</p>



<h3>Common Misconception #4</h3>



<div style="height:12px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<figure class="wp-block-pullquote has-border-color has-background has-small-font-size" style="border-color:#abb7c266;border-width:1px;border-radius:8px;background-color:#abb7c20d;font-style:normal;font-weight:500"><blockquote><p>When DevOps and Agile are combined, you can foregoe planning</p></blockquote></figure>



<div style="height:28px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<p>Software development always needs a great deal of planning. DevOps and agile do not let you get away without planning.</p>



<p>Agile in this case is formal agile delivery which I would argue consists of more planning, market research, feedback, and pivots than any other project management framework.</p>



<p>DevOps focuses on continuous improvement and automation which need a significant amount of planning to ensure the right areas of focus are being worked on.</p>



<p>The truth is this; development teams, operations teams, infrastructure teams, quality assurance teams, account management teams, and members of any other team benefit from having a good plan that is backed up by principles, culture, and a centralized philosophy.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h3>Common Misconception #5</h3>



<div style="height:12px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<figure class="wp-block-pullquote has-border-color has-background has-small-font-size" style="border-color:#abb7c266;border-width:1px;border-radius:8px;background-color:#abb7c20d;font-style:normal;font-weight:500"><blockquote><p>DevOps and Agile are only for small teams</p></blockquote></figure>



<div style="height:28px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<p>Teams of all sizes can benefit from these delivery methodologies. Software delivery is a complex problem that requires good communication, tools, talent, and principles to drive consistency and quality.</p>



<p>While there are an infinite number of methods that could be used to deliver technology, Agile and DevOps are formalized and prescriptive platforms to solve these complex challenges.</p>



<p>By adopting DevOps and Agile together and bringing a core set of delivery principles to an organization&#8217;s approach to delivering technology, one can actually achieve a much larger scale of delivery more quickly.</p>



<p>All of your teams are on the same page, utilizing the same tools, communicating about the same processes, and driving agile development and operations together as a unified front.</p>



<h3>Common Misconception #6</h3>



<div style="height:12px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<figure class="wp-block-pullquote has-border-color has-background has-small-font-size" style="border-color:#abb7c266;border-width:1px;border-radius:8px;background-color:#abb7c20d;font-style:normal;font-weight:500"><blockquote><p>DevOps and Agile are focused on controlling software development</p></blockquote></figure>



<div style="height:28px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<p>I would argue that this is the farthest idea from the truth. DevOps and Agile aim to democratize the delivery process across an organization&#8217;s many different value streams.</p>



<p>One of the core principles of the Scaled Agile Framework for Enterprises is to get decision-making as close to the work being performed as possible. This means that teams must work together on their high-level planning initiatives to get stories in the hands of implementers leaving them the freedom to deliver those stories any way they want to.</p>



<p>This does not mean that the business does not have a say in what is getting delivered, but how it is delivered is determined by the individuals that know best.</p>



<p>Early on in the adoption of these methodologies, it is not uncommon for a pendulum of decisions making to swing back and forth between IT and the business as everyone tries to figure out this new dynamic. Everyone&#8217;s goal should be to find a new center where everyone is heard and all concerns, no matter their size, are given room to breathe in a conversation about delivery.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>How Should I View DevOps and Agile?</h2>



<p>By fully adopting Agile and DevOps, a lot of doors are opened up for delivery.</p>



<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/benefits-of-devops/devops-flow/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Flow</a>:</strong> Instead of moving from task to task, or project to project, work can be put onto a conveyor belt of delivery. Agile and DevOps offer more of an assembly line-type flow to technology delivery.</li>



<li><strong><a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/benefits-of-devops/devops-culture-of-quality/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Quality</a>:</strong> Context switching impacts quality. By offering more stability in work coming down the pipeline, engineers in various disciplines can focus on quality first.</li>



<li><strong><a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/benefits-of-devops/flexibility/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Flexibility</a>:</strong> Companies need to meet the market where it is at. Sometimes this means quickly pivoting from products that are not working to products that do well in the market.</li>



<li><a href="https://www.valewood.org/devops-cycle-time/"><strong>Release faster and work smarter</strong>:</a> By reducing the size and scope of deliverables, the team can focus on shipping more often.</li>



<li><strong><a href="https://www.valewood.org/why-are-ci-cd-pipelines-part-of-devops/">Simplifies Software Development and Operations Focus</a></strong>: Day-to-day operations can seem like a burden that interrupts delivery frequently. By adopting DevOps, operations are a normal part of everyday life.</li>



<li><strong><a href="https://www.valewood.org/devops-trust/">Responsibility</a>:</strong> Agile helps individual contributors feel like they are part of something bigger by influencing the overall planning and delivery processes. They are not just taking orders from the tower, they are actively delivering value against their vision of great outcomes.</li>



<li><strong><a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/benefits-of-devops/consistency/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Consistency</a>:</strong> Consistency brings predictability and reliability to products and planning</li>



<li><strong>Measurement:</strong> Promote data-driven decision-making into your day-to-day workflows through predictability and consistency in the flow of work.</li>



<li><strong>Security:</strong> Security is no longer a secondary burdensome process that detracts from delivering work to the market. Security is built right into DevOps through automated delivery pipelines.</li>
</ul>



<p>Any of these benefits could be achieved on their own in their own ways. By fully embracing Agile and DevOps, each of these ideals comes with the methodology. There is no need to solve an already-solved problem.</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>When first hearing about DevOps and Agile, it is easy to build some initial blinders and misconceptions about what they really mean when utilized as a symbiotic relationship.  It takes a mindset change, and a full perspective shift to realize the benefits of DevOps and Agile together.  </p>



<p>I would encourage anyone out there to go get some training, watch some YouTube videos, and read as much as you can about the methodologies and what they have to offer.  DevOps and Agile together can really open up a lot of new benefits for your business and your customers.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Helm: Kubernetes Cluster Unreachable </title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/helm-kubernetes-cluster-unreachable/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 02:51:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Kubernetes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[howto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kubernetes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tools]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1924</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Kubernetes, while fairly mature as a platform, is still considered an emerging technology in the business space. Due to this, lots of engineers are spending their free time trying to learn about Helm which can lead to some pretty frustrating&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://kubernetes.io/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="4" title="Kubernetes" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Kubernetes</a>, while fairly mature as a platform, is still considered an emerging technology in the business space.  Due to this, lots of engineers are spending their free time trying to learn about Helm which can lead to some pretty frustrating errors.  </p>



<p>Let&#8217;s discuss why you might be receiving <code>Error: Kubernetes cluster unreachable</code> when trying to connect to your cluster for the first time.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Kubernetes Install</h2>



<p>There are a lot of different mechanisms on the market today to get Kubernetes up and running depending on your environment.  How you installed Kubernetes is important for troubleshooting later.  Review the install methods and make sure you align underneath one of them in some fashion.</p>



<h3>Local Environment</h3>



<p>Local Kubernetes is going to use <a href="https://k3s.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">k3s</a> or <a href="https://minikube.sigs.k8s.io/docs/start/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">minikube</a> to run and install a local version on a standard workstation.  This is a great way to get familiar with Kubernetes because these products will download and install all the requisite dependencies to bootstrap anyone regardless of their skill level.</p>



<h3>On-Prem Environment</h3>



<p>I am differentiating local and on-prem simply from the viewpoint of servers vs desktops.  In a more server-focused environment, many people will use <a href="https://github.com/kubernetes-sigs/kubespray" target="_blank" rel="noopener">kubespray</a> or <a href="https://github.com/kubernetes/kops" target="_blank" rel="noopener">kops</a> to deploy their Kubernetes clusters.  Kubespray will ensure that servers are properly configured through IaC while downloading and installing baseline Kubernetes.  By the time you are done, a fully functional cluster should be available.</p>



<p>Kubespray does come with a lot more knobs and dials since it makes fewer opinionated decisions about what your cluster setup should look like.  In a local environment, ingress is going to be handled in a very specific way.  In an on-prem environment, you may have network appliances that want to handle ingress in a very specific way.  Kubespray should be able to get most of your configurations taken care of for your special circumstances.</p>



<h3>Cloud Environment</h3>



<p>Cloud environments can be configured the same way on-prem environments are through kubespray and kops.  Cloud-based VM instances would be spun up on management networks and tools would be run against them to achieve a functioning cluster.</p>



<p>Most cloud providers will have their own managed Kubernetes to be used as well.  Those are probably a much safer way to get started when just starting to dabble in the Kubernetes space.  </p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://aws.amazon.com/eks/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon EKS</a></li>



<li><a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/products/kubernetes-service/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Azure AKS</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/products/kubernetes" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DigitalOcean</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vultr.com/kubernetes/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Vultr</a></li>
</ul>



<p>These solutions generally are only a few clicks away from a full-stack deployment.  Once you get a bit more comfortable, it would be a good idea to toss out your test cluster and start to move into Terraform, CloudFormation, or <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/get-started/azure-portal" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="20" title="Azure" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Azure</a> Resource Manager automation to ensure your clusters are codified for future upgrades.</p>



<h2>Error: Kubernetes cluster unreachable</h2>



<p>There are going to be a few troubleshooting steps you should take to diagnose this issue.  Each of them is going to be a little bit different depending on your deployment setup.</p>



<h3>Check Your Kubeconfig</h3>



<p>The first thing to check is your <code>$HOME/.kube/config</code> file.  This file contains all of the relevant information for connecting to your Kubernetes cluster.  It is also very important you keep this file safe and secret since it holds credentials for that connection as well.</p>



<h4>My Kubeconfig is Missing!</h4>



<p>If your kubeconfig file is missing, review your Kubernetes installation instructions for anything specific about copying a kubeconfig to the proper folder on your local machine.  The instructions may also walk you through how to create one.  Helm will not work without this file being created and in the proper location.</p>



<h4>My Kubeconfig Exists!</h4>



<p>If you open that file to read it, you will find that it is YAML formatted with connection parameters in it.  These parameters should include some certificate information, which are credentials and cluster identification verification, and a hostname for the cluster management API address.</p>



<p>If you have kubectl installed on the same machine as your kubeconfig, a simple test would be to run <code>kubectl get nodes</code> to see if you get a list of servers back from the kubernetes API.  If you get an error, then either you do not have the right level of access, or your kubeconfig is not properly configured.  See above <strong>&#8220;My Kubeconfig is Missing&#8221;</strong>.</p>



<p>If this works as intended, and you see a list of servers the next step is to ensure that your kubeconfig is on the same computer that you would like to run helm from.  If you are running helm from a local workstation, make sure you have a proper kubeconfig on that workstation.  If you are running helm from a different server, ensure a kubeconfig is provided for that server.  Make sure to re-test.</p>



<h4>Check Networking</h4>



<p>Helm communicates with the Kubernetes API over port 6443.  Using NMap to check ports, ensure that the machine you are intending to run helm from has clear line of sight communication with the Kubernetes cluster over port 6443.  This can be achieved on Linux via this command: nmap –p 6443 {{cluster address/master hostname}}.  You can find the cluster address/master hostname inside of a validated kubeconfig.</p>



<p>If you are using Windows and looking for an example of how to do port scans, I would suggest switching to Linux or Mac.</p>



<p>If ports show closed or filtered, network communication will not be established with the cluster and Helm will not be able to run configurations.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Additional Resources</h2>



<p>The steps outlined above should get you pointed in the right direction when you receive Helm errors when trying to contact your cluster for the first time.</p>



<p>If you did not find the answers you needed via this article, I have added a few additional resources below that may be able to help get you sorted out.  If you have additional information to share on this topic, please <a href="https://www.valewood.org/contact/" data-type="page" data-id="984">contact me</a> and I will update this post to reflect any changes.</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/k3s-io/k3s/issues/1126" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GitHub</a></li>



<li><a href="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/63066604/error-kubernetes-cluster-unreachable-get-http-localhost8080-versiontimeou" target="_blank" rel="noopener">StackOverflow</a></li>



<li><a href="https://pet2cattle.com/2022/07/install-helm-k3s" data-type="URL" data-id="https://pet2cattle.com/2022/07/install-helm-k3s" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Pet2Cattle</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>DevOps Roll-up: November 2022</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/devops-roll-up-novembers-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 22:08:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[roll-up]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1909</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Below is a list of DevOps articles/sites that I discovered over the past month and found interesting. Linux Troubleshooting This is an interesting tool that people can use to test out their Linux troubleshooting skills in a capture-the-flag-style event. Here&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Below is a list of <a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> articles/sites that I discovered over the past month and found interesting.</p>



<h2>Linux Troubleshooting</h2>



<p>This is an interesting tool that people can use to test out their Linux troubleshooting skills in a capture-the-flag-style event.</p>



<p>Here is what the developer has to say about their SadServers:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>There is a collection of scenarios, a description of what&#8217;s wrong, and a test to check if the issue has been solved. Servers are spun up on the spot, users get an &#8220;SSH&#8221; shell via a browser window to an ephemeral server (destroyed after the allotted time for solving the challenge) and then they can try and solve the problem.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Check it out with the link below if you are looking to up your server administration game!</p>



<p><a href="https://github.com/fduran/sadservers" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://github.com/fduran/sadservers</a></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity is-style-wide"/>



<p></p>



<h2>DevOps and Software Engineering Job Board</h2>



<p>This is a job board that is centralizing DevOps and Software Engineering jobs on a single board.  I am a big fan of boards like this because they are more targeted and promote more realistic expectations for jobs you might be looking for.</p>



<p><a href="https://software-engineer-jobs.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://software-engineer-jobs.com/</a></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity is-style-wide"/>



<p></p>



<h2>Golang Network Bus</h2>



<p>An event bus is a core component in a microservices-based architecture.  Application A (in control of Domain A) will register an event on the event bus every time a data change needs to be synchronized by downstream systems.  Application B (which needs to reference data from Domain A) will then be able to store its own local copy of Domain A&#8217;s data to reduce dependencies on an external system.</p>



<p>I love seeing projects like this get introduced into the ecosystem.  Many times, we are relying on highly scaleable systems with a massive amount of configurable knobs and dials to achieve relatively simple tasks.  Tools like this are a great way to get your feet wet and dive into a new architecture without all of the extensive overhead of enterprise tools.</p>



<p><a href="https://github.com/kamalshkeir/kbus" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://github.com/kamalshkeir/kbus</a></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity is-style-wide"/>



<p></p>



<h2>Searchable Asset Directory</h2>



<p>Resmo bills itself as:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>Complete visibility and security for modern teams</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Centralized asset inventory management is a huge deal in DevOps.  By scanning your assets, you can understand what is out of compliance and subsequently investigate where errors may be happening in automation to allow for that noncompliance.  Without this kind of visibility, changes will go unchecked which makes quality suffer.</p>



<p>Another nice feature of a CAIM product like this is; they are a great Single Point of Truth system.  I have utilized these in the past as an API-driven data repository to feed other downstream automation systems with data they need to accomplish their tasks.</p>



<p>Check them out below!</p>



<p><a href="https://www.resmo.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://www.resmo.com/</a></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity is-style-wide"/>



<p></p>



<h2>Kustomize</h2>



<p>Kustomize is a great way to keep your configuration files declarative and free of messy variables and if statements.  Configure your application how you would like and then provide specific override files for different environments.  The video below will teach you how to make production ready <a href="https://kubernetes.io/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="4" title="Kubernetes" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Kubernetes</a> manifests.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Kustomize: The Best Way to Manage Your Kubernetes Configs" width="1170" height="658" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/spCdNeNCuFU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity is-style-wide"/>



<p></p>



<h2>Steampunk Spotter</h2>



<p>Steampunk Spotter is an <a href="https://www.ansible.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="7" title="Ansible">Ansible</a> tool for Development, Quality Assurance, and Operations teams purpose-built to cut down on the management burden of keeping playbooks current.  With built-in upgrade assistance, syntax checking, module assistance, vulnerability identification, and much more!  </p>



<p>If you are interested in super charging your Ansible automation, check them out below!</p>



<p><a href="https://steampunk.si/spotter/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://steampunk.si/spotter/</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/spCdNeNCuFU" medium="video" width="1280" height="720">
			<media:player url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/spCdNeNCuFU" />
			<media:title type="plain">Kustomize: The Best Way to Manage Your Kubernetes Configs</media:title>
			<media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Kustomize is a way to customize your Kubernetes manifests files.  In this video I go over everything you you need to know about the theory of Kustomize as we...]]></media:description>
			<media:thumbnail url="/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/devops-rollup-november.jpg" />
			<media:rating scheme="urn:simple">nonadult</media:rating>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Which Term Accurately Describes Agile and DevOps?</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/which-term-describes-devops-and-agile/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 22:20:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops consistency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opinion]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1796</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[DevOps is a culture and methodology that an organization can prescribe to aid in velocity, consistency, stability, and flow of value to the market. Often confused with &#8220;automation&#8221; being the only benefit of DevOps, the core principles behind DevOps offer&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> is a culture and methodology that an organization can prescribe to aid in velocity, consistency, stability, and <a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/benefits-of-devops/devops-flow/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="28" title="Understanding the DevOps Process Flow in 2022" target="_blank" rel="noopener">flow of value</a> to the market.  Often confused with &#8220;automation&#8221; being the only benefit of DevOps, the core principles behind DevOps offer a common set of ideals that a team can align under and strive to achieve.</p>



<p>Big A Agile is a project management methodology that pairs well with DevOps to aid in rationalizing work delivery against a set of guardrails.  Agile also provides prescriptive visibility to work being performed ensuring engineers are not being overloaded by overwhelming business priorities.</p>



<p>With those descriptions out of the way, what term best describes both Agile and DevOps?</p>



<h2>Consistency</h2>



<p>The goal of any organization going through change is to drive consistency in delivery.  Without consistency, a technology group cannot adapt to change and a business cannot meet the market where it is at.  </p>



<p>By driving consistency, a business gets predictability which is powerful when scoping and planning new work.  By understanding real velocity, not aspirational velocity, a business can invest in its people and products to grow at a more sustainable rate.</p>



<p>By driving consistency, technologists get the predictability that they need to make sound and rational decisions about how to approach work.  When working against an unpredictable cycle, technology groups will quickly get overwhelmed by the rate of change and produce solutions that do not meet the demands of the market.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Why Consistency Matters and How it Influences Velocity</h2>



<p>Consistency is important for a couple of factors.  First, individual contributors like their jobs and are not really interested in consistent interruptions or unplanned requests.  While some people may look at those facets as an everyday part of doing business, they can be avoided if mitigation steps are put in place.</p>



<p>When people are constantly interrupted quality suffers.  There is no way around that.  Technology is complex and people need time to focus and go through their problem-solving routines.</p>



<p>Second, inconsistency in delivery has impacts on customers and their delivery.  In technology, you are generally not just working on your system.  There are consumers of your systems who have expectations of either utilization or integration.  By being inconsistent in delivery, you cannot manage the expectations of your consumers.</p>



<p>Lastly, a lack of consistency means that you will never really understand your velocity.  Velocity is important because it tells you how much of X you can get by spending Y.  Think about it like auto manufacturing, they could turn the manufacturing dials up to 11 in their facilities but then you will end up with cars with 3 wheels or loose nuts and bolts.</p>



<p>A trap that we fall into frequently is confusing aspirational velocity with real velocity.  Aspirational velocity is the speed that someone thinks something should get delivered.  Real velocity is a measurement of what can be delivered at a given speed.</p>



<h3>Real Velocity vs Aspirational Velocity</h3>



<p>Aspirational velocity is when a leader says &#8220;We need this product to launch by X date!&#8221;.  We have either all been in that position or will be in that position sometime in our careers.</p>



<p>Without proper support, investment, and foresight in planning; aspirational velocity will almost always end with sub-standard products that greatly increase the future cost to the business.  Leaning harder on anyone in the delivery space always leads to decisions that are short-sighted toward a narrow goal.</p>



<p>I believe aspirational velocity is firmly rooted in the idea of needing to &#8220;take a shot&#8221;.  Checks are constantly being written that others are expected to cash.  Sometimes this works out and I would say can be necessary for a startup or green field project.  Any organization looking to grow over time should be looking for its tipping point when aspirational velocity needs to transition into real velocity to offer a more reliable work environment for their employees.</p>



<p>Real velocity is based on the idea that you are going to make hard choices about which work is important to feed into a model where delivery is consistent.  When more work needs to be done than can be achieved by the current velocity, hard choices will be made to cut work, increase staff, defer work, or invest in current technology to increase velocity.  </p>



<p>Any business should have a firm goal of understanding its real velocity and do everything in its power to tamp down or extinguish aspirational velocity.</p>



<h2>DevOps and Agile are Closely Related</h2>



<p>I have another article that describes how DevOps and Agile are related to each other.  Primarily, Agile is about lean work being performed against targets and goals with frequent demos of the work being completed to influence pivots.  Agile was in need of a technology delivery methodology that could help realize the fundamental mission of Agile. </p>



<p>You can read more about how <a href="https://www.valewood.org/devops-and-agile/" data-type="post" data-id="1264">DevOps and Agile are related here!</a></p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Runners Up</h2>



<p>This question is also asked on a few official exams.  I want to make sure that my perspective on DevOps does not overshadow exams that do not have as much wiggle room in their answers.</p>



<h3>Brainly.in</h3>



<p><a href="https://brainly.in/" data-type="URL" data-id="https://brainly.in/question/36271184" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Brainly</a> answers the question like this:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>Agile is refers to an interative approuch which focuses on collaboration, costumer feedback,and small rapid releases,DevOps is considered a practice bringing development and operations teams together.</p>
<cite>https://brainly.in/question/36271184</cite></blockquote>



<p>The problem is, I don&#8217;t think this answer refers to a specific term.  We can look at this and assume that they are looking at Agile and DevOps as two holistically different approaches which are getting merged together instead of looking for commonality between the project management methodology and the technology delivery methodology.</p>



<p>While this may sound really good on a test, there are real business influences that come from each of the facets that they list in their answer.</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Collaboration</strong>: Greater collaboration brings more of a hive-mind approach to problem-solving.  Too much collaboration on very large problems can bring analysis paralysis.  By breaking problems down into tiny and lean releases, everyone can stay more focused on achieving goals instead of trying to eat an entire elephant all at once.</li>



<li><strong>Customer Feedback</strong>: Agile focused on getting valuable work products out to the market quickly to reduce investment risk.  Getting feedback from customers is a great way to manage risk and pivot quickly if needed. </li>



<li><strong>Small Rapid Releases</strong>: To further the idea of managing risk, lessening the size of your releases helps you containerize risk into much smaller units.  If something isn&#8217;t working as expected, or the market shifts drastically, it is far less painful to throw that work out and pivot to something more palatable.  Additionally, the risk is lowered on incremental improvements to new features for existing functionality since the introduced change should not pose as great of an impact on an already healthy ecosystem.  This is something <a href="https://blog.cloudflare.com/october-2021-facebook-outage/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Facebook</a> could learn a thing or two about.</li>



<li><strong>Bringing DevOps and Operations Teams Together</strong>: This is the typical textbook definition of DevOps.  The reality is, DevOps and Agile are about breaking down silos and creating fully cross-functional teams who are able to fully deliver work in a highly efficient and lean way.  DevOps and Agile help drive decision-making down as close to the work being performed as possible while offering up a management framework to transparently keep other interested parties informed while work is being completed and shipped.</li>
</ul>



<p>As you can see, there are a lot of nuances packed into each one of those bullet points.</p>



<h3>Intellipaat.com </h3>



<p><a href="https://intellipaat.com/" data-type="URL" data-id="https://intellipaat.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Intellipatt</a> answers the question like this</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>A set of values and principles. Because both follow a set of principles and offer the value that is similar.</p>
<cite>https://intellipaat.com/community/74027/which-term-accurately-describes-agile-and-devops</cite></blockquote>



<p>I believe that this answer is a primarily business-focused answer looking to understand the idea of value in the market.  While it is not an incorrect way to look at things, I do not believe it is the most important way to look at DevOps and Agile.  </p>



<p>Value is a byproduct of DevOps and Agile.  The real benefit to DevOps and Agile is the consistent way that said value gets delivered to the market.  This means that you can calculate and quantify value through data-driven decision-making.  You are also able to manage market expectations and take potentially larger leaps to satisfy your customers.</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>The key to any technology product&#8217;s success is consistency.  DevOps and Agile offer consistency while remaining flexible and focused on common non-functional requirements like reliability and stability.  Other facets of Agile and DevOps like value are byproducts of a team or teams of teams who fully embrace the complementary delivery methodologies.</p>



<p>How would you boil DevOps and Agile down to a single term?  <a href="https://www.valewood.org/contact/" data-type="page" data-id="984">Contact me</a> and let me know!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why DevOps is Boring in 2022?</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/more-like-boringops/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 18:04:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[delivery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1786</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[DevOps is a hot topic in the technology world. It&#8217;s no longer just an isolated set of tools and processes which promise an automated future, it’s an entire culture that’s infiltrating every facet of software development. This post will try&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> is a hot topic in the technology world. It&#8217;s no longer just an isolated set of tools and processes which promise an automated future, it’s an entire culture that’s infiltrating every facet of software development.</p>



<p>This post will try to explain why the DevOps methodology itself is not boring.  We will also try to explain why a feeling of boredom stems from properly implemented tools and processes. We also dive into how you can make DevOps more exciting while keeping your sanity intact.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>What Does DevOps Mean?</h2>



<p>The term DevOps, or “development operations,” first appeared in the tech world in the early 2000s. It was a term used to describe a certain type of organization that was responsible for the entire application and software development lifecycle, from ideation to production.</p>



<p>Teams would be responsible for both the development and operations workflows, providing a more efficient way of working. As DevOps has grown in popularity, it has expanded beyond just operations teams.</p>



<p>Now, people are interested in speeding up their software development process using the term DevOps to describe the combined usage of infrastructure automation tools and best practices for team collaboration and communication.</p>



<p>There are two main components within DevOps that drive the culture. They are infrastructure as code and automated delivery. IaC is really just a way of organizing your code and infrastructure so that it is easily reproducible and shareable. Automated delivery is a method for automatically deploying applications and configurations without human intervention.</p>



<p>With the increase in automation, engineers may find themselves wondering when the next exciting change event may present itself. They may also wonder if they are automating themselves out of a job.</p>



<p>As a basis for understanding DevOps, you must understand that this practice exists to remove the excitement of a chaotic technology delivery process. DevOps is meant to be boring by nature.</p>



<p>As a side effect of DevOps being stable and consistent, organizations must look for other ways to keep their software engineers and DevOps engineers engaged through other means of excitement.</p>



<h2>Why is DevOps Boring?</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Why DevOps is Boring in 2022" width="1170" height="658" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bP5nWWFV2gg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p>As companies begin implementing modern DevOps practices, some people may notice a lull in excitement. The tools, processes, and overall culture of DevOps may feel exciting at first but quickly turn into monotony. Why?</p>



<p>DevOps becomes boring because people approach it as a checklist. They focus on the tools and processes and completely ignore the culture and mindset that lies behind the methodology.</p>



<p>These people don’t understand why they are implementing certain tools or why they are following specific processes. They are just doing it because they read an article that said their company should be adopting DevOps, or they read a book that talked about the “predictable <a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/benefits-of-devops/devops-flow/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="28" title="Understanding the DevOps Process Flow in 2022" target="_blank" rel="noopener">flow of value</a>”.</p>



<p>What makes DevOps exciting is the culture behind it. The practices and tools are just the means of achieving a certain culture. If you try to implement DevOps but don’t adopt the correct mindset and culture behind it, then you are going to end up with a boring and ineffective implementation.</p>



<h3>Fewer Natural Learning and Growth Opportunities</h3>



<p>A stable DevOps lifecycle will inherently bring a lower number of emerging technologies and opportunities to integrate emerging technologies. Sure, early on in DevOps adoption, the emerging tech will be all the rage, but that will subside as stability and consistency are driven into the pipeline.</p>



<p>Since continuous improvement is a fundamental principle of DevOps, teams should be encouraged to do some data-driven analysis looking for opportunities to become more efficient in their delivery cycles.</p>



<p>Pivots can also be made within the team. Someone who is primarily focused on ops should be put in a position to both share what they are doing and also be presented with opportunities to look at other fields like coding or security. This is true for all specialties that make up a function DevOps team.</p>



<h3>Comfort in Previous Success</h3>



<p>All too often, I see companies in the industry falling back on the comfort of their successes as an excuse to not rapidly evolve. DevOps should be putting companies in a position where pivots are much easier to pull off. Secondarily keeping a DNA of being lean and nimble should be a focus of any company.</p>



<p>Any company sitting back on its heels thinking it can keep doing what they are doing forever is going to be consumed by its competitors operating at a different level. Break that cycle by listening to the opportunities being presented by your DevOps Engineers and your Software Engineers to keep DevOps from becoming boring and your company from stagnating.</p>



<h3>Never Being Complete or Finished</h3>



<p>When completing a project, a person can get a huge dopamine rush along with a personal sense of accomplishment. DevOps doesn’t really offer that in large quantities. Work is much more methodical, incremental, and bite-sized meaning a team’s ability to celebrate a big win is less frequent.</p>



<p>If you want to truly adopt a culture of continuous improvement, you need to make sure that your team is constantly learning and improving their knowledge. This means your team should be continually looking for new books, podcasts, and ways that they can expand their skill set, improve their knowledge, and learn new things.</p>



<p>When DevOps is paired with Agile, those opportunities are even more spread apart. Everyone on the team is incrementally feeding their work into a larger integrated system. Resources may be assigned to a larger initiative for only a short period of time before being rolled off to another set of work.</p>



<h3>DevOps Engineers are a Figment of your Imagination</h3>



<p>A DevOps Engineer does not exist. They are not real. Yetis are more real than DevOps Engineers are.</p>



<p>DevOps is a methodology and a culture that does not require a role engineer it. There are many engineering practices that compose a full team practicing DevOps. Confusion about what someone is really intended to be working on will leave those individuals to fend for themselves and miss out on a healthy team dynamic.</p>



<p>When culture is suffering in a team practicing DevOps it can become boring or worse extremely frustrating. There is not a shared vision or goal that team is trying to achieve. This means that the work being performed is being done in isolation and under-appreciated. Let’s face it, we are not doing our jobs for our own health, we do them to contribute to something bigger than ourselves.</p>



<h3>The Hype Train</h3>



<p>I see a lot of posts on <a target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.reddit.com/">Reddit</a> which have individuals from different disciplines looking to make the jump from their current career path over to DevOps. Most of what I read leads me to believe that they are being sold a bill of goods which just isn’t reality.</p>



<p>While I do believe that problem-solving in a space fully embracing DevOps is more complex than in any more traditional space, I do not believe that most companies are embracing DevOps fully. This means that job applicants are applying for and landing DevOps positions that are not actually meeting the spirit of DevOps. Organizations are generally looking for a little bit of help automating some manual processes but stop short of full adoption.</p>



<p>This will lead engineers to be as bored at this new shiny DevOps role as they were in their former system administration role.</p>



<h3>Running out of People to Blame</h3>



<p>Office politics can be entertaining to some. In a fully functioning DevOps culture, everything is treated as code, tested in code, operations happen in code, and releases are automated all of which remove a lot of formal human interaction in the daily development and release cycle.</p>



<p>Game of Thrones was not popular because Joffrey methodically picked apart Rob Stark and his armies. GoT was popular because of the drama, suspense, twists, and turns. Now, the office should not be a Game of Thrones style drama, but; DevOps is very good at transitioning from a culture full of interpersonal conflict into a blameless culture focused purely on technology which can be boring.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>What Are Some Examples of Engineers Boredom Executing DevOps?</h2>



<p>Below are some examples of different roles and how they can become bored with their job when DevOps is being practically utilized for its processes but not viewed as a persistent growth opportunity.</p>



<h3>Debbie Developer has a Case of the Mondays</h3>



<p>Debbie became a software engineer because of her love for puzzles. Solving complex scenarios and producing elegant maintainable code is her passion.</p>



<p>Early on in the DevOps adoption process, she was jazzed that there was a whole host of new problems to solve when transforming a traditional set of build jobs into something that could support CI/CD.</p>



<p>As time has progressed, she is feeling less fulfilled in her day-to-day job. The kinds of work she is performing have become far less complex and much smaller. There is almost no coordination between members of her team since she can just push code at will and let automation take over to push it into production.</p>



<p>It is the same daily slog over and over and over again.</p>



<h3>Simon the Systems Administrator is Running Out of Work To Do</h3>



<p>Servers create themselves. Simon doesn&#8217;t need to log into the <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="14" title="AWS" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">AWS</a> console anymore to check anything because the platform is completely self-service.</p>



<p>When adopting DevOps, systems administrators will often find themselves developing a lot of code around system configurations. This works well because in their specific domain, they want consistency and operational efficiency.</p>



<p>Over time, Simon&#8217;s work has been extremely helpful in level-setting expectations around solid delivery patterns. But what is next for Simon? There does not appear to be any new or related systems on the horizon for Simon to continue to grow his skills. Growth has stagnated and there really isn&#8217;t a path forward for Simon to earn a senior systems administrator position.</p>



<h3>Quintin Feels Like Their Role as a Quality Assurance Engineer is Monotonous</h3>



<p>Developers are writing their own unit, functional, and integration acceptance tests. Quintin is left building some visual testing to be added to the delivery pipeline.</p>



<p>Quality assurance engineers are the glue that holds a development community together. They are well-versed in requirements and testing and they are constantly working with their developer counterparts to ensure their work will be accepted by customers.</p>



<p>DevOps can take away this sense of community in the development process. Individuals are responsible for contributing their own tests while they write code. As tests are passed, the code moves its way into production.</p>



<p>DevOps has effectively worked Quintin out of a job.</p>



<h3>Connie the Cloud Engineer is Struggling to Provide Value</h3>



<p>DevOps pipelines will consist of application code, test automation, system automation, and infrastructure automation (cloud or on-prem). Once developed, engineers will shift focus to day 2 operations. Once day 2 operations are tackled, what&#8217;s left?</p>



<p>Connie felt value and excitement in the early days of DevOps, but is now isolated away from the rest of the team because systems have been stabilized, security is second nature, and AWS is effectively running itself.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>5 Tips to Make DevOps Exciting Again!</h2>



<p>We’ve covered why DevOps can become tedious, but what can you do about it? If you want to make DevOps exciting again, then you have to understand why it is exciting in the first place!</p>



<p>The reason DevOps is exciting for most companies is because of the focus on drastically improving your software development process. It’s a way of improving communication, collaboration, and the overall quality of your software. It’s a way of adopting a culture of automation.</p>



<p>Automation is important in DevOps because it directly impacts the speed of your software release cycles. It can also help improve the overall quality of your software as well as your organization.</p>



<p>Automation is a core component of DevOps. When you make automation a core part of your development process, you are able to reduce the number of repetitive tasks your organization has to perform. This means you can put less focus on manual tasks, and more focus on things that actually improve your software and the company as a whole.</p>



<h3>Provide Growth Opportunities</h3>



<p>Some companies confuse growth with “opportunities to become a manager”. Most of the really good engineers and architects that I have met will “manage” a project because they want to see it succeed not because they want to be a manager.</p>



<p>Providing opportunities for growth in knowledge, automation, systems, development, operations, platforms, consulting, or any other area that your services or products may not be fully taking advantage of today.</p>



<p>As an example, if you have an awesome set of pipelines that obfuscate some of the complexities of doing automated delivery, challenge your team to package that up and white-label it. Have them use those packages to consult with other teams in your organization to level their automation skills up.</p>



<h3>Inject Failures</h3>



<p>We are always focused on delivering key projects, functionality, or needs of the business. With a narrow view of the world being delivered first, that does not leave a lot of room to poke at the softer edges of your products.</p>



<p>Introduce automated failure models like a chaos monkey. Start with planned times and have your chaos monkey start to take down some low criticality services and review the characteristics of what that means. There may be impacts in areas that you were not expecting.</p>



<p>This provides an opportunity to add some advanced troubleshooting to an area that the DevOps methodology took away through its inherent consistency and stability.</p>



<h3>Incorporate User Feedback Into DevOps Processes</h3>



<p>User feedback is important to any business because it allows you to understand your customers and discover ways to improve your product. However, user feedback is hard to come by because customers don’t usually interact with businesses on a consistent basis.</p>



<p>In order to incorporate user feedback into your software development lifecycle, you need to be able to get consistent feedback from customers. There are two main ways to do this:</p>



<ul>
<li>Use survey tools to let customers provide feedback on your product, team, and company.</li>



<li>Let customers interact with your team using live chat tools.</li>
</ul>



<p>Both of these tools are easy to implement and can help you get useful and consistent feedback from customers. Feedback is also a great way to breathe some excitement into an otherwise stagnant work environment.</p>



<h3>Be Realistic with Expectations</h3>



<p>As I stated above, DevOps Engineers are not real. Business leaders need to come to grips with this fact and be very realistic with expectations around roles and work assignments. If you are looking to shortcut full DevOps adoption by hiring some DevOps engineers as a gap fill, you will not be able to provide an exciting environment that keeps your technology groups engaged.</p>



<h3>Celebrate Completion</h3>



<p>Get your teams together to do some good old-fashioned team building. Wins are wins no matter how big or small they are. Recognize your team’s accomplishments because they deserve to be recognized.</p>



<p>The methodical pace of DevOps and Agile do not lend themselves to recognizing big wins or the sheer volume of work that it really takes to get to those wins. Team leads should focus on bringing their teams back to the center by recapping how much success they have had knowing their work is never done.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>DevOps is not boring. It is an exciting change in the way that organizations approach software development. However, it is only exciting if you fully commit to the culture of DevOps and all the benefits it has to offer.</p>



<p>If you just implement the tools and processes without the culture and mindset, then you are only doing half the work and missing out on the benefits of the fully implemented DevOps culture.</p>



<p>If you want to make DevOps exciting again, you must ensure that you are fully committed to the culture. Only then will you be able to make the most of everything that DevOps has to offer.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bP5nWWFV2gg" medium="video" width="1280" height="720">
			<media:player url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bP5nWWFV2gg" />
			<media:title type="plain">Why DevOps is Boring in 2022</media:title>
			<media:description type="html"><![CDATA[DevOps is a hot topic in the technology world. It’s no longer just an isolated set of tools and processes which promise an automated future, it’s an entire c...]]></media:description>
			<media:thumbnail url="/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/devops-boring.jpg" />
			<media:rating scheme="urn:simple">nonadult</media:rating>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
