<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>Greer Shepherd &#8211; A DevOps Blog</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.valewood.org/author/greer-shepherd/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.valewood.org/</link>
	<description>Occasionally a developer makes an Ops!</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 22:04:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.valewood.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/A-DevOoops-1-e1660773390219.png</url>
	<title>Greer Shepherd &#8211; A DevOps Blog</title>
	<link>https://www.valewood.org/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>How to Achieve Rapid Application Delivery with DevOps</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/devops-rapid-delivery/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greer Shepherd]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2022 20:19:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sdlc]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1668</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[DevOps has become a powerful set of tools, processes, and cultural norms for improving the deployment and operation of the software. As businesses grow more reliant on software applications, DevOps becomes even more important as it aids in accelerating the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> has become a powerful set of tools, processes, and cultural norms for improving the deployment and operation of the software. As businesses grow more reliant on software applications, DevOps becomes even more important as it aids in accelerating the delivery of new features to production.</p>



<p>Instead of relying on lengthy manual processes and manual testing stages to release updates, DevOps helps you streamline your release process so you can get new features out faster with higher quality and consistency.</p>



<p>The success of any organization relies on its ability to scale quickly and efficiently react to market demands. The demand for fast-paced change has forced many companies to reevaluate their current operational strategies. In response, organizations are now adopting a new culture for developing software and continuous integration processes that support rapid application development and application delivery cycles.</p>



<p>Let&#8217;s explore rapid application delivery and how it can have a meaningful impact on your business!</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>What is Rapid Application Delivery?</h2>



<p>Rapid application delivery is the practice of producing, testing, and deploying applications quickly from ideation to implementation &#8211; usually within days or even hours, rather than months or even years.</p>



<p>To stay competitive in the market, businesses need to get valuable technology into the market more quickly than their competitors.  Your business may be amazing at executing quality deliverables with an amazing user experience.  If those products are shipped to the market slowly, your competitors have an edge to capture the market faster if they are delivering products with the same quality and amazing user experience more quickly.</p>



<p>Organizations that are able to rapidly deliver new applications can respond more quickly to market conditions and customer needs, and therefore retain a competitive advantage.</p>



<p>I also believe that the barriers to entry on delivery have gotten far more complex over the past several years.  With major incidents like Log4J still looming in the shadows, end users and B2B relationships are requiring more scrutiny over deliverables than they ever have in the past.  </p>



<p>Some individuals may look at this increased scrutiny as a speed bump in the release process but I always encourage companies to embrace this increased scrutiny as a marketable way to show their products have a leg up on their competition.  The reality of the situation is, it can only be a competitive advantage if it is rolled directly into a rapid application delivery cycle.</p>



<h2>Why is Application Delivery Speed Important?</h2>



<p>Fast delivery of new applications is critical to keeping up with customer expectations and staying ahead of competitors. In today&#8217;s business environment, customers want goods and services faster than ever before. Consumers expect to be able to click a button and have their goods delivered to their doorsteps in just a few days.</p>



<p>Rapid application delivery means you can meet these expectations of speed and customer service in a highly competitive environment. If you’re able to bring a new product or service to market quickly, you can generate greater revenue and market share than if your offerings are delayed by months or even longer.</p>



<p>Speed is a major factor in customer decision-making. Moreover, if you’re behind the curve, you’ll most likely be out-competed by other companies that are able to get products or services to market quicker than you. If you’re slower than your competitors, you could lose market share and customers, which could damage your brand and profitability.</p>



<h2>Benefits of Rapid Delivery</h2>



<p>If you’re able to deliver apps quickly, you’ll see benefits in many areas, including the following:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Higher Revenue:</strong> If you’re able to get products or services to market faster, you’ll be able to generate more revenue than if your offerings are delayed by months or years.</li>



<li><strong>Increased Brand Awareness: </strong>If you’re able to get products or services to market faster, you’ll be able to increase brand awareness, which can help you to grow your customer base.</li>



<li><strong>Improved Customer Engagement:</strong> More rapid app delivery means increased customer engagement, which leads to greater customer retention.</li>



<li><strong>Reduced Costs:</strong> By accelerating the software development process and cutting out unnecessary steps, you can reduce costs.</li>
</ul>



<h2>How to Achieve Rapid Application Delivery in the Enterprise</h2>



<p>There are many steps you can take to achieve rapid application delivery in your organization, including the following:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Identify the Business Problem:</strong> Before you do anything else, you have to identify the business problem that you’re trying to solve. What is the company trying to accomplish? Once you know what business problem you’re trying to solve, you can create an application backlog.</li>



<li><strong>Create an Effective Solution: </strong>You must then create an effective solution that will meet the needs of the business problem you’re trying to solve. You can achieve this by using a collaborative approach to software development in order to build an application with input from all stakeholders.</li>



<li><strong>Test the Solution:</strong> The next step is to test the solution to ensure that it will solve the business problem in the way that you intended. You can do this by using <a href="https://www.valewood.org/devops-testing/" data-type="post" data-id="1239">automated testing</a> and continuous integration/continuous delivery (CI/CD) to maximize quality control and minimize the time to release.</li>
</ul>



<p>Adopting DevOps and Agile delivery methodologies account for each of the rapid application delivery considerations holistically.  These two concepts are wrapped up in a clever industry buzzword: <a href="https://www.techtarget.com/searchcio/definition/IT-transformation" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">IT Transformation</a>.</p>



<p>IT Transformation is a full assessment of information technology systems with the intent of increasing efficiency, delivery speed to market, stability, and cost to remain competitive in a digital market.  IT Transformation is not only for Exchange and document storage servers.</p>



<p>While it might be a tough pill to swallow, taking a step back and fully reassessing delivery and emulating organizations that do it very well is the key to success.  Some of these problems are solved problems that are not looking for the next creative solution.</p>



<h2>Why is my Application Delivery Slow?</h2>



<p>Naturally, over time, businesses will add process after process to application delivery cycles as a result of incidents or outages.  While well-intentioned at the time, the organic growth of these processes can lead to a dramatic downturn in both productivity and delivery of valuable products.  </p>



<ul>
<li>Manual Testing</li>



<li>Dependency Management Hell</li>



<li>Custom vs 3rd Party Integrations</li>



<li>Lack of Visibility</li>



<li>Overbearing Visibility</li>



<li>The work environment does not meet the needs of employees</li>



<li>Poor Communication</li>



<li>Misaligned Expectations</li>



<li>Outdated Technology</li>



<li>Too Much Parallel Work In-Progress</li>
</ul>



<p>I believe that the first step is always a recognition that there must be a better way to deliver.  After that, any changes made to this space are going to vary company by company depending on their appetite for risk.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>The Benefits of DevOps in Software Development</h2>



<p>DevOps is often used to describe the relationship between software development and operations that have evolved over the last couple of years. The term was first used in The Phoenix Project, a novel about bringing together IT and business leaders to fix a failing production system. It’s an abbreviation of “software development” and “operations”.</p>



<p>Its main goal is to get better collaboration between IT departments and software development teams. The DevOps movement gained momentum in the 2010s, as organizations looked for ways to improve application deployment and management while meeting growing customer demands.</p>



<p>The software development process includes several stages, like planning, designing, and testing the product. In an Agile project, these stages happen in very short iterations, and organizations work in a continuous flow. DevOps is the way of organizing work at scale and is about breaking down silos between teams and finding ways for them to work more closely together.</p>



<p>Rapid application development is also an early cornerstone in any kind of digital transformation.</p>



<h2>Continuous Integration in DevOps</h2>



<p>The ability to test new code is a key component for DevOps to work effectively. Continuous integration (CI) is the practice of integrating new code with existing code on a frequent basis. CI triggers the creation of new versions of software after every new code deployment.</p>



<p>Modules are integrated with other modules based on their dependency relationships. By using automated CI tools, developers can continuously test code against a production-like environment while they are responsible for writing code.</p>



<h2>Continuous Delivery in DevOps</h2>



<p>Organizations that have embraced CI are now looking to accelerate the deployment process further by implementing continuous delivery (CD). CD can be described as the automation of the entire delivery process. It includes automating the build and test process, setting up the necessary infrastructure, and using a deployment tool to deploy new application versions to production.</p>



<h2>Continuous Testing in DevOps</h2>



<p>Finally, continuous testing is the practice of the entire software development and testing team executing automated tests together. It is achieved through the use of CI tools that allow the team to run tests against the code and infrastructure in a single console.</p>



<p>By adopting CI/CD and embracing a DevOps culture, companies can reduce the time it takes to deliver new features to customers by 50 percent, according to research by CA Technologies.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>As businesses grow more reliant on software applications, DevOps becomes even more important as it aids in accelerating the delivery of new features to production. The adoption of DevOps can significantly reduce the time it takes to deliver new features to customers by automating the build, test, and deployment processes. By accelerating the deployment process, DevOps helps organizations meet growing customer demands while reducing risk.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>7 Tips for Landing a DevOps Position Without a Degree</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/devops-without-education/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greer Shepherd]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 21:28:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops resource]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1645</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[DevOps is hot right now. The demand for professionals with the skills to bridge the gap between software development and information technology operations is growing significantly. It’s not difficult to understand why. DevOps is a methodology that optimizes processes, removes&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> is hot right now. The demand for professionals with the skills to bridge the gap between software development and information technology operations is growing significantly.</p>



<p>It’s not difficult to understand why. DevOps is a methodology that optimizes processes, removes barriers, and improves collaboration between software developers and information technology (IT) operations teams. Because of its benefits, it’s becoming an increasingly attractive option for IT professionals who want to stand out from the crowd.</p>



<p>In this blog post, you will learn about the types of roles available in DevOps, how you can land your first DevOps job, and what you need to succeed in your new role as a DevOps engineer or specialist.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>What Is DevOps?</h2>



<p>DevOps is short for &#8220;software development operations.&#8221; It describes a set of best practices related to transforming the relationship between software developers and information technology (IT) operations personnel.</p>



<p>DevOps aims to improve collaboration, increase efficiency, and reduce waste. This organizational transformation is commonly referred to as cultural transformation.</p>



<p>Achieving cultural transformation requires employees in both departments to change their perspectives and expectations of each other. This is why DevOps is often seen as an ongoing journey, not a destination. DevOps is often associated with agile software development methodologies, such as Kanban, Scrum, and others.</p>



<h2>What do DevOps Engineers do Day to Day?</h2>



<p>A day in the life of DevOps engineers is not all that different than a day in any other technology career. A DevOps Engineer&#8217;s primary responsibility is centered around the health of the systems under their supervision. Those activities will include:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Look for anomalies:</strong> Despite our best efforts trying to completely cover a system in monitoring and visibility, sometimes things go bump in the night. These things could be reported by end users or other business units. Anytime something like that shows up, a DevOps Engineer should chase those anomalies down to something actionable.</li>



<li><strong>Review new releases:</strong> Just because you have an awesome pipeline that utilizes GitOps to move code directly from commit to production does not mean that you should trust your technology stack. Take time daily to review what has been making its way out to production to both understand the changes, but also suggest improvements.</li>



<li><strong>Review observability:</strong> Metrics and monitoring don&#8217;t do any good if nobody is looking at them. Anyone from systems administration through product owners should be reviewing these frequently looking for trends. Real-world usage of a system will always be different than what we thought it was going to be in the engineering phase and we should be validating, disproving, or augmenting our base assertions through data-driven decision-making.</li>



<li><strong>Manage risks:</strong> Successful systems grow over time. DevOps engineers should be looking at a complete ecosystem to help promote long-term health and manage risk. There is no free lunch and growing capacity means that costs will also be going up. Helping the team understand this relationship and educating the product owners of the business on investment opportunities is a critical activity that cannot be overlooked.</li>



<li><strong>Communicate with the team: </strong>Being in constant communication with your team is one of the core principles of DevOps. Since work units are broken down much farther than normal, rapid change is constantly being introduced. By promoting good synchronous and asynchronous communication patterns, teams will stay informed about what is important and urgent along with ensuring everyone is able to consume less urgent current events at their leisure.</li>



<li><strong>Watch industry trends:</strong> Because of the speed that a DevOps team brings to the industry, trends and patterns are changing faster than ever. When looking to become a DevOps engineer, you should be ready to keep your RSS feeds hot and ready to consume.</li>



<li><strong>Log new tickets: </strong>As you are doing your daily surveys of systems, undoubtedly you will run across either existing issues or issues that are sure to crop up in the near future. To help promote good planning, ensure that you are logging tickets into your ticket management system to ensure those issues do not get lost.</li>



<li><strong>Develop the skills you need:</strong> DevOps engineers are lifelong learners. The specific practices of cloud, data, <a href="https://www.valewood.org/do-devops-engineers-need-a-coding-background/" data-type="post" data-id="326">coding</a>, Linux, programming, <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="14" title="AWS" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">AWS</a>, culture, web, <a href="https://kubernetes.io/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="4" title="Kubernetes" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Kubernetes</a>, tools, etc. are constantly being changed to promote more fluid delivery models. Take time to sit back and absorb new concepts and techniques to help level up your career and your team.</li>



<li><strong>Promote continuous improvement:</strong> Any tech company that is not embracing a culture of continuous improvement will quickly be outperformed by companies that do. By taking a little bit of time out of your day to focus on improving something that needs attention, you are contributing to a cleaner and safer technology product!</li>



<li><strong>Have some fun:</strong> DevOps doesn&#8217;t need to be a grind. Make it a point to leave work behind and have some fun with your team.</li>
</ul>



<p>As you can see, DevOps Engineers have a lot of responsibility for running and maintaining technology.</p>



<h2>Types of Jobs in DevOps</h2>



<p>DevOps is a methodology that requires several different disciplines to fully adopt and become proficient in. In my opinion, I don&#8217;t think anyone technical should be asking &#8220;Can I become a DevOps Engineer?&#8221; because you are more than likely already qualified to be one! Let&#8217;s look at a few different roles in DevOps to see how the market is segmenting labor in this space.</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Software Engineer:</strong> Software engineers are responsible for building software products and services against a set of requirements. This role usually has some kind of computer science background, but some of the best developers and engineers I have met started their careers with no formal degree.</li>



<li><strong>Operations Engineer:</strong> Responsible for managing the lifecycle of technology ensuring the stability and reliability of systems. Anyone with a passion for learning technology and growing in the tech space should be searching the job market for entry-level operations jobs.</li>



<li><strong>Quality Assurance:</strong> Responsible for validating the quality of software being developed through automated testing. Also responsible for making testing available to an entire DevOps team.</li>



<li><strong>DevOps Engineer:</strong> Let’s start with the basics. If you’re looking to work as a DevOps engineer, you’ll need to be able to understand and work with code, have an excellent knowledge of server environments, and be able to think on the fly and find solutions to new problems.</li>



<li><strong>DevOps Engineer Manager:</strong> In this capacity, you’ll need to be able to work with both technical and non-technical staff. You’ll be responsible for ensuring that the team is working effectively and efficiently. So, it goes without saying that you’ll need strong communication skills.</li>



<li><strong>DevOps Architect:</strong> A DevOps architect is responsible for designing and implementing the organization’s software delivery system. This is often a challenging role that requires a great deal of experience, knowledge, and a strong understanding of organizational needs.</li>



<li><strong>DevOps Manager:</strong> As a DevOps manager, you’ll be responsible for overseeing the entire DevOps process, including hiring, training, and managing staff. You’ll need to be able to understand and communicate the needs of multiple stakeholders. You’ll also need to be able to manage the entire lifecycle of products, from development to delivery and ongoing maintenance.</li>
</ul>



<p>As you can see, normal everyday engineering roles can join a DevOps team. Don&#8217;t immediately exclude yourself because you have not been a DevOps engineer in the past. Most of us have started out in software engineering or system operations roles anyway.</p>



<h2>How to Land a DevOps Job Without a Degree</h2>



<p>In today’s job market, it is not enough to just have a good education and experience from your previous job. You must also know how to write a resume that highlights your skills and experience in a way that shows you as the best candidate for the job.</p>



<p>This can be done by taking some time to research and learn about the particular industry you are interested in working in, as well as the company and the specific role you want to apply for.</p>



<p>When you have this information in hand, you can then create a resume that places your skills, experience, and values at the top of the list. This will make it easy for hiring managers to see what makes you different than other candidates and more likely to be hired.</p>



<p>With these things in mind, it is important to keep your resume updated as new jobs become available. You should also stay on top of employment trends so that you are ready when opportunities arise. By doing this, you will increase your chances of landing an interview and ultimately getting hired.</p>



<p>Here are a few additional steps you can take to increase your odds of landing a DevOps Engineering position:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Research the role you want</strong>: Blindly showing up to a job interview for a DevOps position is not going to go well. Take some time to learn and understand the DevOps methodology and what it is trying to accomplish. Any of the technical skills needed can be acquired on the job so do let that be a limiting factor.</li>



<li><strong>Network</strong>: The single best way to land a job in DevOps without a degree is to network, network, network. It’s one of the most effective ways to find out about new opportunities, learn about the industry, and connect with people who can help you advance your career.</li>



<li><strong>Identify Your Skills</strong>: Before you can network effectively, you need to know what your skills are. Doing this will help you identify which organizations are best for you, as well as identify skill gaps. Furthermore, it will help you understand how to position yourself as the best candidate for a given role.</li>



<li><strong>Get certified: </strong>Another way to demonstrate your expertise is to get certified in a DevOps-related technology or methodology. There are many certification programs available, such as those offered by AWS, <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/get-started/azure-portal" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="20" title="Azure" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Azure</a>, and <a href="https://www.redhat.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="29" title="Red Hat" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Red Hat</a>.</li>



<li><strong>Join a DevOps Community:</strong> DevOps communities, like meetup groups and online forums, are excellent ways to find out about new opportunities and connect with people who can help you advance your career.</li>



<li><strong>Create an Online Portfolio:</strong> Online portfolios can be incredibly powerful tools for job seekers without a degree. You should include examples of your work and information about your projects and roles.</li>



<li><strong>Gain experience through internships or apprenticeships: </strong>Many companies offer internships or apprenticeships for aspiring DevOps professionals. These programs can provide you with valuable hands-on experience and help you build a network of industry contacts.</li>



<li><strong>Network with Employers</strong>: When you’re networking with employers, don’t sell yourself short. Be sure to highlight your skills, background, and experience.</li>
</ul>



<p>Regardless of your experience in development and operations, if you have any kind of tech experience, you should be looking to land a job in the DevOps engineering space. Entry-level positions are generally going to be a bit more focused on operations.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>How to Become a DevOps Engineer Without Experience?</h2>



<p>If you want to become a DevOps engineer but don&#8217;t have any experience in the field, there are several steps you can take to get started:</p>



<ol>
<li><strong>Learn the basics:</strong> Start by learning the foundational concepts and technologies that are used in DevOps, such as: 
<ul>
<li>Knowledge of version control systems (e.g. Git)</li>



<li>Experience with continuous integration and delivery (CI/CD) tools and practices</li>



<li>Proficiency in one or more programming languages (e.g. Python, Java, C#)</li>



<li>Familiarity with infrastructure as code (IaC) tools (e.g. Terraform, CloudFormation)</li>



<li>Experience with containerization technologies (e.g. <a href="https://www.docker.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="16" title="Docker" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Docker</a>, Kubernetes)</li>



<li>Knowledge of cloud computing platforms (e.g. AWS, Azure, GCP)</li>



<li>Familiarity with monitoring and logging tools (e.g. Splunk, New Relic)</li>



<li>Experience with automated testing and deployment strategies</li>



<li>Strong communication and collaboration skills</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><strong>Gain practical experience: </strong>The best way to learn DevOps is to get hands-on experience by working on projects. There are several ways you can gain practical experience, such as:
<ul>
<li><strong>Work on open source projects:</strong> One way to gain practical experience is to contribute to open source projects. This can involve fixing bugs, adding new features, or improving documentation.</li>



<li><strong>Build your own projects: </strong>Another way to gain experience is to work on your own projects. This could be a simple web application, a service, or a tool that you build from scratch.</li>



<li><strong>Participate in online hackathons or coding challenges: </strong>Online hackathons and coding challenges are a great way to get hands-on experience and learn from others.</li>



<li><strong>Take on internships or apprenticeships:</strong> Many companies offer internships or apprenticeships for aspiring DevOps professionals. These programs can provide you with valuable hands-on experience and help you build a network of industry contacts.</li>



<li><strong>Join a study group or peer learning community:</strong> Consider joining a study group or peer learning community to learn and collaborate with others who are also interested in DevOps.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><strong>Build a strong portfolio:</strong> As you gain experience, start building a portfolio of projects you have worked on. This can include open-source contributions, personal projects, or projects you have completed as part of a boot camp or online course. A strong portfolio can help you stand out when applying for DevOps jobs.
<ul>
<li><strong>Contribute to open source projects:</strong> One way to demonstrate your skills and experience is to contribute to open source projects. This can involve fixing bugs, adding new features, or improving documentation.</li>



<li><strong>Build your own projects:</strong> Another way to build a portfolio is to work on your own projects. This could be a simple web application, a service, or a tool that you build from scratch.</li>



<li><strong>Work on a real-world project:</strong> If you have the opportunity to work on a real-world project, either as part of a team or as an individual, consider documenting your work and adding it to your portfolio. This could include creating diagrams, writing technical documentation, or creating video demonstrations of your work.</li>



<li><strong>Build a personal website:</strong> A personal website is a great way to showcase your portfolio and share your skills and experience with potential employers. Consider including information about your background, your skills and experience, and links to any projects or code you have worked on.</li>



<li><strong>Create a resume:</strong> A well-written resume is an important part of any portfolio. Make sure to include information about your education, skills, and experience, as well as any relevant projects or certifications.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><strong>Get certified:</strong> Another way to demonstrate your expertise is to get certified in a DevOps-related technology or methodology. There are many certification programs available, such as those offered by AWS, Azure, and Red Hat.
<ul>
<li><a href="https://aws.amazon.com/certification/certified-devops-engineer-professional/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="30" title="AWS Certified DevOps Engineer" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">AWS Certified DevOps Engineer</a>: This certification is designed for professionals who have experience with the design, development, and management of systems on the AWS platform.</li>



<li><a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/certifications/devops-engineer/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="31" title="Azure DevOps Engineer Expert" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Azure DevOps Engineer Expert</a>: This certification is for professionals who have expertise in the design and implementation of continuous integration, continuous delivery, and dependency management using Azure DevOps.</li>



<li><a href="https://www.cncf.io/certification/cka/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="32" title="Certified Kubernetes Administrator (CKA)" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Certified Kubernetes Administrator (CKA)</a>: This certification is for professionals who have experience with installing, configuring, and managing Kubernetes clusters.</li>



<li><a href="https://www.scrumalliance.org/get-certified/scrum-master-track/certified-scrummaster" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="33" title="Certified ScrumMaster (CSM)" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Certified ScrumMaster (CSM)</a>: This certification is for professionals who have experience with the Scrum framework and its principles and practices.</li>



<li><a href="https://www.redhat.com/en/services/certification/rhcs-ansible-automation" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="34" title="Red Hat Certified Specialist in Ansible Automation" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Red Hat Certified Specialist in Ansible Automation</a>: This certification is for professionals who have experience with the Ansible automation platform and its use in the deployment and management of infrastructure and applications.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><strong>Network and build relationships:</strong> Building relationships and networking with other professionals in the DevOps community can help you learn about job opportunities and increase your chances of getting hired. Attend meetups, join online communities, and reach out to professionals in the field to learn more about their experiences and get advice.
<ul>
<li><strong>Attend meetups and conferences</strong>: One of the best ways to meet other professionals in the DevOps community is to attend meetups and conferences. These events provide opportunities to learn about new technologies and best practices, as well as to meet and connect with other professionals.</li>



<li><strong>Join online communities: </strong>There are many online communities and forums, such as Reddit, LinkedIn, and Stack Exchange, where you can connect with other professionals and ask questions or share your knowledge.</li>



<li><strong>Participate in online courses or boot camps:</strong> Online courses and boot camps are a great way to learn new skills and connect with other professionals who are interested in the same topics.</li>



<li><strong>Volunteer or mentor others:</strong> Volunteering or mentoring others can be a great way to give back to the community and build relationships. You can volunteer your time to organizations or mentor others who are just starting out in the field.</li>



<li><strong>Build a personal website or blog:</strong> A personal website or blog is a great way to share your knowledge and expertise with others. Consider writing about your experiences, projects, or challenges you have faced and how you overcame them.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>



<p>Remember, becoming a DevOps engineer requires a combination of technical skills and practical experience. It may take time and effort to gain the necessary skills and experience, but with dedication and hard work, you can achieve your goal of becoming a DevOps engineer.</p>



<h2>3 Steps to Landing Any Job You Want</h2>



<p>If you’re looking to find a job, landing any kind of position is a big deal. You can start by proactively searching for the positions you want, or by going through a recruiter or headhunter if they have a specific role you’re interested in.</p>



<p>When you land a new job, you have to be prepared for all kinds of situations. You might have to move across the country if the company has an office there, and you may also have to learn new skills or take on new responsibilities.</p>



<p>Making yourself ready for these situations can help you land any kind of job. For example, you could build up your résumé and online presence by completing online courses or volunteering at local organizations. This will show that you are ready for a new position and will also make it easier to find work once you are ready.</p>



<p>Another option is to join professional organizations like Toastmasters or other networking groups where you can meet people who can help you land a new job. Just remember: Landing any kind of job takes time, so be prepared by taking steps now that will make it easier in the future!</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Define What You Want</strong>: Before you embark on your job search, you need to make an honest assessment of what you want. Do you want a full-time position, or will a contract position work for you? How many hours do you want to work per week? What is your salary range? These are just a few of the questions you’ll need to answer.</li>



<li><strong>Identify Your Strengths: </strong>Once you’ve identified what you want, you need to assess what you have to offer. What are your strengths? What are your weaknesses? This will help you identify which employers will be best for you.</li>



<li><strong>Write a Great Resume</strong>: Once you’ve assessed your skills and talents, you need to translate them into action for your resume. This is your first opportunity to impress a prospective employer.</li>
</ul>



<h2>Why do Employers Value Degrees?</h2>



<p>In the job market, it is no secret that you will very frequently see X level of degree or equivalent experience. I have noticed that this will generally disenfranchise individuals who are in the tech space from searching for a job at a particular company.</p>



<p>As a hiring manager, I am generally looking for individuals who have an aptitude and are lifelong learners for any of the jobs I am looking to fill. People who are passionate about quality delivery, consistency, and passionate about personal development are always great candidates. When looking for a new job, make sure you focus on those key areas about yourself to really wow a future employer.</p>



<p>Employers are also interested in standardized skills in software development, computer science, cloud, systems administration, etc. When someone graduates from higher education in the United States, there is a general sense that those individuals have learned and developed themselves enough to be effective from day 1, which is rarely the case in my experience.</p>



<p>A Junior DevOps engineer position can be filled by anyone who is passionate about automation, CI/CD, cloud, programming, Linux, AWS, and other technical spaces regardless of their background. The key is to do your research and understand the goals of what DevOps is trying to accomplish and make sure you are ready for interview questions about the DevOps Methodology.</p>



<p>When I am evaluating candidates, I bank on people first, not their skills. Even someone who may appear weak in a particular technology may be an incredible person that I want to work with. Some companies take the far more brutal leger-based approach on this. By only interviewing candidates who have a college degree, they are able to defer some of the cost of training. I would argue that is not a company that I want to work for.</p>



<p>There is an old saying, &#8220;Nobody ever gets fired for choosing IBM&#8221;. This translates into, if you are choosing the best, there is no reason for anyone to second guess your decisions. A degree has a similar stigma behind it. If a hiring manager is betting on someone with a degree, they probably won&#8217;t regret their decision. As a candidate, you just need to make sure you give a prospective employer a reason to bet on you.</p>



<p><strong>TLDR;</strong> Standardized skills, training, problem-solving, and risk mitigation.</p>



<h2>Frequently Asked Questions</h2>



<p>Below are some frequently asked questions about becoming a DevOps Engineer:</p>


<div id="rank-math-faq" class="rank-math-block">
<div class="rank-math-list ">
<div id="faq-question-1672177037280" class="rank-math-list-item">
<h3 class="rank-math-question ">Can you be a DevOps engineer without a degree?</h3>
<div class="rank-math-answer ">

<p>Absolutely!  DevOps is a multifaceted technology-focused field of work.  If you have skills in technology from QA through Software Development and beyond; you should be applying for DevOps jobs today!</p>

</div>
</div>
<div id="faq-question-1672177128348" class="rank-math-list-item">
<h3 class="rank-math-question ">How do I become a DevOps engineer without a degree?</h3>
<div class="rank-math-answer ">

<p>DevOps is about the <a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/benefits-of-devops/devops-flow/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="28" title="Understanding the DevOps Process Flow in 2023" target="_blank" rel="noopener">flow of value</a> being delivered with technology.  Study the concepts of DevOps and the goals it is trying to achieve.</p>

</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>


<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>If you want a job as a DevOps Engineer, you’ll need to be prepared to show what you have to offer and sell yourself to prospective employers. Remember, though, that there are many different types of jobs in DevOps.</p>



<p>So, before you start your search, it’s important to understand what you are looking for and how to stand out in a competitive hiring landscape. If you want a job in DevOps, you’ll need to be prepared to show what you have to offer and sell yourself to prospective employers.</p>



<p>Remember, though, that there are many different types of jobs in DevOps: DevOps engineer, architect, engineer manager, and manager. Target what you want to be doing, and start applying. You are probably more qualified than you initially thought!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What is Automation Testing in DevOps</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/devops-testing/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greer Shepherd]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 19:39:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[automated devops testing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[testing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tools]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1239</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Automation Testing in DevOps is generally relegated to the software being released to production. Environmental testing is performed by manual testing practices or high-level smoke tests. Test automation should cover the full CI/CD pipeline including infrastructure, delivery tools, software, UI,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Automation Testing in <a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> is generally relegated to the software being released to production. Environmental testing is performed by manual testing practices or high-level smoke tests.</p>



<p><strong>Test automation should cover the full CI/CD pipeline including infrastructure, delivery tools, software, UI, and any other technology that is included in the pipeline. Automated tests should not be relegated to the land of software development.</strong></p>



<p>Let&#8217;s explore what automation testing in DevOps really means when you are looking to stabilize your delivery process and accelerate your business!</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Automated Testing in DevOps</h2>



<p>Generally, developers tend toward coding unit tests to validate that the code is running the way they expected. At the same time, quality practitioners create automated user tests that validate the end-to-end user experience.</p>



<p>Quality practitioners can arrange explorative testing sessions in which teams manually look at various application area issues.</p>



<p>DevOps&#8217; best practice for the automation of CI/CD pipelines is to run automatic testing whenever possible. This means deploying automatic test UIs to production to detect and proactively address user experience concerns.</p>



<p>I generally like to take this a step further when looking at environmental conditions. Tests for environments can also be thought about in the context of monitoring and observability. A pipeline should be qualified through the use of testing tools in an automated test process. The tests should also be composed in a way that they are usable as part of your monitoring system.</p>



<p>For example, if you are willing to validate that a certificate is valid as part of your testing framework, you should also be willing to run continuous testing to validate that the certificate does not expire between releases.</p>



<h2>The Importance of Test Automation</h2>



<p>Test automation improves reliability, continuity, and productivity within teams of developers and products. DevOps teams have a better chance of staying within budget without disrupting crucial debugging or problem-shooting processes.</p>



<p>Test automation can be quicker than manual testing. It helps to avoid costly errors by eliminating communication barriers and saves money in teams by eliminating unnecessary work. Testing automation provides new forms of flexibility that enable the development team to reuse test scripts across the testing software.</p>



<p>As a business leader, do not be fooled by the short-term investment cost of introducing automated testing into your environment. Testing automation is not new and sexy functionality that you can provide to the market which is why I believe it is skipped by many businesses. Automated testing, continuous integration, and continuous delivery are critical investments to the longevity of your products.</p>



<p>Each release is always going to end up being more complex than the previous release. Employing a good testing process ensures that your products are being introduced to the market in a reliable and expected way. Because of the increased complexity, any manual testing process will need to scale to meet that complexity. Automated testing does not scale in cost the same way that manual testing does.</p>



<h2>What is Test Automation?</h2>



<p>Test Automation enables users to automate their software testing to ensure that they meet specified quality standards. Different types of testing are often depicted in pyramids. As you ascend the pyramid, the number of testing types decreases, and the costs of creating and operating the test increase. The most traditional tests were conducted using manual methods in the Pyramids in the past. It was a slow and costly procedure until automated testing tooling came into effect.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://www.headspin.io/blog/the-testing-pyramid-simplified-for-one-and-all" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img decoding="async" src="https://global-uploads.webflow.com/619e15d781b21202de206fb5/6316d9e765cd53d9937e2b6a_The-Testing-Pyramid-Simplified-for-One-and-All.webp" alt="The Testing Pyramid"/></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Headspin: The Testing Pyramid: Simplified for One and All</figcaption></figure>



<h2>Common Test Automation Pitfalls</h2>



<p>Below are some of the most common issues when adding automated testing to your technology products:</p>



<ul>
<li>Developers not participating in testing</li>



<li>Unit tests not being written with code</li>



<li>Testing tools are not being used to their fullest potential</li>



<li>No standard for code coverage</li>



<li>Best practices not being employed for a specific technology stack</li>



<li>Tests are not being run in the proper places of a pipeline.</li>
</ul>



<h2>How Automated Testing Powers DevOps?</h2>



<p>One of the core goals of DevOps is to improve <a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/benefits-of-devops/devops-flow/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="28" title="Understanding the DevOps Process Flow in 2023" target="_blank" rel="noopener">delivery flow</a>. Test automation is one of the core strategies used to help smooth out both flow and quality expectations. A cultural pillar of DevOps is continuous improvement.</p>



<p>Due to the shortened feedback loop of your continuous delivery pipeline, smaller and more nimble software testing and release cycles can be achieved by the development team. This means that your applications will be less prone to errors due to robust testing.</p>



<p>When issues are discovered in production they are not turned into a grandiose response event. A DevOps team is able to get adjustments made to both code and tests and re-release the software quickly back into production.</p>



<p>Without automating releases and tests, teams will scramble to recertify software before being ready to push it back to production with bug fixes. Worse, if your software teams do not employ any testing, you may never know about critical issues before customers bring them up.</p>



<h2>How Can I Improve Continuous Testing?</h2>



<p>Continuous testing is one of the most important things you can do to improve your success rates. If you’re doing it right, continuous testing will help you catch bugs at the earliest stages of development and make sure that problems don’t creep up in production.</p>



<p>Continuous testing helps to keep projects on track and ensure that they stay on schedule, which means that your customers get their products sooner.</p>



<p>A good way to start building a continuous test strategy is by creating an automated integration test pipeline. It should consist of a series of tests that are run automatically when new code is added to your application.</p>



<p>Automated integration tests can be especially useful when you have a large team developing multiple applications that share common code libraries or frameworks. They can also be useful for large-scale applications with many users and complex data models.</p>



<p>Continuous testing also allows developers to build trust with their customers by letting them know that their products are being continuously tested and improved. This can help to increase customer confidence in your product and boost retention rates.</p>



<h2>How Does Automated Testing Change the Role of Quality Assurance?</h2>



<p>Automated testing is a way to evaluate the quality of software. The basic idea is that you write automated tests, or scripts, to check for unexpected behaviors or errors in the code.</p>



<p>Automated testers can run these scripts automatically, which saves time and effort for both developers and QA staff. When you have automated testing in place, you can focus on other tasks, like exploring new features or fixing bugs, without worrying about whether your application is running correctly.</p>



<p>There are two types of automated testing: static and dynamic. Static testing checks for basic issues like syntax errors, security holes, and database integrity. Dynamic testing checks for unexpected behaviors such as out-of-order execution, race conditions, and timeout issues.</p>



<p>QA teams use automated testing to maintain high standards of quality throughout the development process. They can catch issues early on in the development cycle and communicate findings effectively with developers and stakeholders.</p>



<p>By reducing bugs and improving overall quality, automated testing can help organizations achieve their goals more quickly and cost-effectively.</p>



<p>A Quality Assurance Engineers&#8217; role changes when embracing test automation testing. Their role will now be to enable the entire team to contribute tests to the automation pipeline. Test cases should be developed and run as part of the normal delivery process.</p>



<p>By making this transition, Quality Assurance Engineers can now focus on higher value work like covering edge cases, improving testing tools and methodology, and leveling up team members&#8217; skills in testing.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Test Automation Stages</h2>



<p>Test Automation includes several fundamental automation techniques that should be followed for quality testing. Testing automation systems are presented in stages atop test pyramids based on their hierarchy.</p>



<h3>Integration Testing</h3>



<p>Integration testing is a type of testing that verifies how well the various units and components of a system work together. It is typically performed after unit testing, and it is meant to ensure that the individual units of the system are able to communicate and interact with each other correctly.</p>



<p>In a DevOps environment, integration testing is an important part of the development process. It helps to identify and fix issues that may arise when different units or components of the system are combined. This can include issues related to data flow, communication, and functionality.</p>



<p>Automated integration testing can be an especially useful tool in a DevOps environment, as it allows developers to quickly and efficiently test the interactions between different units and components of the system. This can help to identify and fix issues early in the development process, improving the quality and reliability of the final product.</p>



<h3>Unit Testing</h3>



<p>Unit testing is a type of testing that focuses on individual units or components of a system. It is typically the first level of testing that is performed, and it is meant to ensure that each unit of the system is working correctly.</p>



<p>In a DevOps environment, unit testing is an important part of the development process. It helps to identify and fix issues with individual units or components of the system early in the development process, improving the quality and reliability of the final product.</p>



<p>Automated unit testing can be especially useful in a DevOps environment, as it allows developers to quickly and efficiently test individual units or components of the system. This can help to identify and fix issues early in the development process, improving the overall efficiency and effectiveness of the development process.</p>



<h3>End-to-End (E2E) Testing</h3>



<p>End-to-end testing, also known as E2E testing, is a type of testing that focuses on verifying the overall functionality of a system. It is meant to ensure that the system is able to perform all of its intended functions, from start to finish, without any issues.</p>



<p>In a DevOps environment, end-to-end testing is an important part of the development process. It helps to identify and fix issues that may arise when different units or components of the system are combined and used in a real-world scenario. This can include issues related to data flow, communication, and functionality.</p>



<p>Automated end-to-end testing can be especially useful in a DevOps environment, as it allows developers to quickly and efficiently test the overall functionality of the system. This can help to identify and fix issues early in the development process, improving the quality and reliability of the final product.</p>



<h3>Exploratory Testing</h3>



<p>Exploratory testing is a type of testing that involves exploring a system or application in an unstructured way, in order to identify issues and uncover new functionality. It is typically performed by testers who have a deep understanding of the system and are able to use their expertise to test it in creative and unexpected ways.</p>



<p>In a DevOps environment, exploratory testing can be an important part of the development process. It can help to identify issues that may not have been uncovered through more structured types of testing, such as unit testing or integration testing.</p>



<p>Exploratory testing can be especially useful in a DevOps environment because it allows testers to identify issues that may not have been anticipated by the development team. This can help to improve the overall quality and reliability of the final product.</p>



<h3>System Testing</h3>



<p>System testing is a type of testing that is focused on verifying the overall functionality, performance, and reliability of a system. It is typically performed after unit testing and integration testing, and it is meant to ensure that the entire system is working correctly.</p>



<p>In a DevOps environment, system testing is an important part of the development process. It helps to identify and fix issues that may arise when different units or components of the system are combined and used in a real-world scenario. This can include issues related to data flow, communication, and functionality.</p>



<p>Automated system testing can be especially useful in a DevOps environment, as it allows developers to quickly and efficiently test the overall functionality, performance, and reliability of the system. This can help to identify and fix issues early in the development process, improving the quality and reliability of the final product.</p>



<h2>Frequently Asked Questions</h2>



<p>Below are frequently asked questions about automated testing in DevOps:</p>


<div id="rank-math-faq" class="rank-math-block">
<div class="rank-math-list ">
<div id="faq-question-1672177784986" class="rank-math-list-item">
<h3 class="rank-math-question ">How can automated testing be integrated into the DevOps workflow?</h3>
<div class="rank-math-answer ">

<p>Automated testing can be integrated into the DevOps workflow in a number of ways, depending on the needs and goals of the organization. Some common approaches include:<br />Incorporating automated testing into the continuous integration (CI) process: Automated tests can be run every time code changes are committed, helping to ensure that the codebase remains stable and functional.</p>
<p>1. <strong>Using automated testing as part of the continuous delivery (CD) process:</strong> Automated tests can be run as part of the CD process to verify that code changes can be safely deployed to production environments.<br />2. <strong>Implementing test-driven development (TDD):</strong> In this approach, automated tests are written before code is developed, with the goal of ensuring that the code meets the requirements and expectations of the tests.<br />3. <strong>Leveraging automation tools and frameworks:</strong> There are many tools and frameworks available that can be used to automate different types of testing, such as unit testing, integration testing, and acceptance testing.</p>
<p>By integrating automated testing into the DevOps workflow in these and other ways, organizations can improve the quality and reliability of their products and reduce the time and effort required to deliver them.</p>

</div>
</div>
<div id="faq-question-1672177889246" class="rank-math-list-item">
<h3 class="rank-math-question ">How can automated testing be integrated into the DevOps workflow using Ansible?</h3>
<div class="rank-math-answer ">

<p><a href="https://www.ansible.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="7" title="Ansible">Ansible</a> is a popular open-source configuration management and automation platform that can be used to automate various aspects of the DevOps workflow, including testing. Here are a few ways in which automated testing can be integrated into the DevOps workflow using Ansible:</p>
<p>1. <strong>Automating the execution of test cases:</strong> Ansible can be used to automate the execution of test cases, either as part of the continuous integration (CI) process or as part of the continuous delivery (CD) process. This can help to ensure that code changes are thoroughly tested before being deployed to production environments.<br />2. <strong>Configuring test environments: </strong>Ansible can be used to automate the configuration and setup of test environments, including installing and configuring dependencies, setting up test data, and more. This can help to streamline the testing process and reduce the time and effort required to get started.<br />3. <strong>Provisioning and managing test infrastructure:</strong> Ansible can be used to automate the provisioning and management of test infrastructures, such as test servers, databases, and other resources. This can help to ensure that testing is conducted in realistic and representative environments.</p>
<p>By using ansible to automate these and other aspects of the testing process, organizations can improve the efficiency and effectiveness of their testing efforts and better integrate testing into their DevOps workflow.</p>

</div>
</div>
<div id="faq-question-1672178053396" class="rank-math-list-item">
<h3 class="rank-math-question ">How can automated testing be integrated into the DevOps workflow using Java?</h3>
<div class="rank-math-answer ">

<p>Java is a popular programming language that can be used to automate various aspects of the DevOps workflow, including testing. Here are a few ways in which automated testing can be integrated into the DevOps workflow using Java:</p>
<p>1. <strong>Writing test cases:</strong> Java can be used to write automated test cases that verify the functionality, performance, and reliability of a system. These test cases can be run as part of the continuous integration (CI) process or as part of the continuous delivery (CD) process.<br />2. <strong>Using testing frameworks:</strong> There are several Java-based testing frameworks that can be used to automate the testing process, such as JUnit, TestNG, and Selenium. These frameworks can be used to write and execute automated test cases, as well as manage and report on test results.<br />3. <strong>Integrating with build and deployment tools:</strong> Java can be used to integrate automated testing with build and deployment tools, such as Maven and Jenkins. This can help to automate the testing process and ensure that code changes are thoroughly tested before being deployed to production environments.</p>
<p>By using Java to automate these and other aspects of the testing process, organizations can improve the efficiency and effectiveness of their testing efforts and better integrate testing into their DevOps workflow.</p>

</div>
</div>
<div id="faq-question-1672178118584" class="rank-math-list-item">
<h3 class="rank-math-question ">How can automated testing be integrated into the DevOps workflow using JavaScript?</h3>
<div class="rank-math-answer ">

<p>JavaScript is a popular programming language that can be used to automate various aspects of the DevOps workflow, including testing. Here are a few ways in which automated testing can be integrated into the DevOps workflow using JavaScript:</p>
<p>1. <strong>Writing test cases:</strong> JavaScript can be used to write automated test cases that verify the functionality, performance, and reliability of a system. These test cases can be run as part of the continuous integration (CI) process or as part of the continuous delivery (CD) process.<br />2. <strong>Using testing frameworks: </strong>There are several JavaScript-based testing frameworks that can be used to automate the testing process, such as Mocha, Jest, and Jasmine. These frameworks can be used to write and execute automated test cases, as well as manage and report on test results.<br />3. <strong>Integrating with build and deployment tools:</strong> JavaScript can be used to integrate automated testing with build and deployment tools, such as Grunt and Webpack. This can help to automate the testing process and ensure that code changes are thoroughly tested before being deployed to production environments.</p>
<p>By using JavaScript to automate these and other aspects of the testing process, organizations can improve the efficiency and effectiveness of their testing efforts and better integrate testing into their DevOps workflow.</p>

</div>
</div>
<div id="faq-question-1672177786331" class="rank-math-list-item">
<h3 class="rank-math-question ">What types of tests should be automated in a DevOps environment?</h3>
<div class="rank-math-answer ">

<p>The types of tests that should be automated in a DevOps environment depend on the specific needs and goals of the organization. However, some common types of tests that are often automated in a DevOps environment include:</p>
<p>1. <strong>Unit tests:</strong> These are focused on individual units or components of a system and are meant to ensure that each unit is working correctly.<br />2. <strong>Integration tests:</strong> These verify that the various units and components of a system work together as intended.<br />3. <strong>System tests:</strong> These test the overall functionality, performance, and reliability of the system.<br />Acceptance tests: These ensure that the system meets the requirements and expectations of the end users.</p>
<p>It is generally a good idea to automate as many types of tests as possible in a DevOps environment, as this can help to improve the quality and reliability of the final product and reduce the time and effort required to deliver it. However, it is also important to consider the resources and capabilities of the organization, as well as the risks and costs associated with automating different types of tests.</p>

</div>
</div>
<div id="faq-question-1672177793459" class="rank-math-list-item">
<h3 class="rank-math-question ">How can automated testing help to improve the quality and reliability of the final product?</h3>
<div class="rank-math-answer ">

<p>Automated testing can help to improve the quality and reliability of the final product in a number of ways:</p>
<p>1. <strong>Early detection of issues:</strong> Automated testing allows developers to identify and fix issues early in the development process before they become more difficult and costly to address.<br />2. <strong><a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/benefits-of-devops/consistency/" data-type="page" data-id="1734">Consistency</a>:</strong> Automated testing allows developers to test the system in a consistent and repeatable manner, helping to ensure that the system is reliable and performs as intended.<br />3. <strong>Thoroughness:</strong> Automated testing can be used to test the system more thoroughly and extensively than manual testing, helping to uncover more issues and ensure that the system is of high quality.<br />4. <strong><a href="https://www.valewood.org/devops-rapid-delivery/" data-type="post" data-id="1668">Speed</a>: </strong>Automated testing can be conducted more quickly than manual testing, allowing developers to test the system more frequently and identify and fix issues more quickly.</p>
<p>Overall, automated testing can help to improve the quality and reliability of the final product by identifying and fixing issues early in the development process and by providing a consistent, thorough, and efficient means of testing the system.</p>

</div>
</div>
<div id="faq-question-1672177800581" class="rank-math-list-item">
<h3 class="rank-math-question ">How can automated testing help to reduce the time and effort required to deliver the final product?</h3>
<div class="rank-math-answer ">

<p>Automated testing can help to reduce the time and effort required to deliver the final product in a number of ways:</p>
<p>1. <strong>Efficiency:</strong> Automated testing is generally faster and more efficient than manual testing, allowing developers to test the system more frequently and identify and fix issues more quickly.<br />2. <strong>Consistency: </strong>Automated testing allows developers to test the system in a consistent and repeatable manner, reducing the risk of errors and inconsistencies that can slow down the development process.<br />3. <strong>Thoroughness:</strong> Automated testing can be used to test the system more thoroughly and extensively than manual testing, helping to uncover more issues and reducing the risk of quality issues being missed.<br />4. <strong>Resource savings:</strong> Automated testing can help to reduce the need for manual testing, allowing organizations to allocate their testing resources more effectively and efficiently.</p>
<p>Overall, automated testing can help to reduce the time and effort required to deliver the final product by providing a faster, more consistent, and more thorough means of testing the system, as well as by helping organizations to more effectively and efficiently allocate their testing resources.</p>

</div>
</div>
<div id="faq-question-1672177805378" class="rank-math-list-item">
<h3 class="rank-math-question ">What tools and technologies can be used to support automated testing in a DevOps environment?</h3>
<div class="rank-math-answer ">

<p>There are many tools and technologies that can be used to support automated testing in a DevOps environment. Some examples include:</p>
<p>1. <strong>Test automation frameworks:</strong> These are specialized tools that are designed to support the creation and execution of automated test cases. Examples include JUnit, TestNG, and Selenium.<br />2. <strong>Continuous integration (CI) and continuous delivery (CD) platforms</strong>: These tools allow developers to automate the testing process as part of the CI and CD process. Examples include Jenkins, Travis CI, and CircleCI.<br />3. <strong>Virtualization and containerization technologies:</strong> These tools allow developers to create and manage virtual or containerized environments for testing, helping to ensure that tests are conducted on realistic and representative environments. Examples include <a href="https://www.docker.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="16" title="Docker" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Docker</a> and <a href="https://www.vagrantup.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="35" title="Vagrant" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Vagrant</a>.<br />4. <strong>Testing tools: </strong>There are many specialized tools that can be used to support different types of testing, such as load testing, security testing, and performance testing. Examples include JMeter, Burp Suite, and Appium.</p>
<p>By using these and other tools and technologies, organizations can effectively automate different aspects of the testing process and better integrate testing into their DevOps workflow.</p>

</div>
</div>
<div id="faq-question-1672177815227" class="rank-math-list-item">
<h3 class="rank-math-question ">What are some best practices for implementing automated testing in a DevOps environment?</h3>
<div class="rank-math-answer ">

<p>Some best practices for implementing automated testing in a DevOps environment include:</p>
<p>1. <strong>Start early:</strong> It is generally a good idea to begin automating tests as early as possible in the development process. This can help to identify and fix issues early, improving the quality and reliability of the final product.<br />2. <strong>Focus on high-value tests:</strong> It is generally more efficient and effective to automate tests that are critical to the functionality and reliability of the system, rather than tests that are less important.<br />3. <strong>Use the right tools and technologies:</strong> It is important to choose the right tools and technologies to support automated testing, based on the needs and goals of the organization.<br />4. <strong>Use good coding practices:</strong> Automated tests should be well-written and maintainable, using good coding practices such as clear and concise code, appropriate documentation, and robust error handling.<br />5. <strong>Regularly review and update tests:</strong> It is important to regularly review and update automated tests to ensure that they are still relevant and effective.</p>
<p>By following these best practices, organizations can effectively implement automated testing in their DevOps environment and improve the quality and reliability of their products.</p>

</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>


<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>As you can see, automated testing is a cornerstone to DevOps. Most focus is generally put on running automated testing against software being developed. There are a lot of advantages to developing automated testing which also looks at environmental conditions as well. Accelerate your business by introducing automated testing tools today!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Do DevOps Engineers Write a lot of Scripting Code?</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/devops-scripting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greer Shepherd]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 21:45:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tools]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1180</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Whether it’s Python, JavaScript, or other programming languages, Developers spend a lot of time writing code. More traditional infrastructure engineers are going to spend their time in a user interface configuring their systems and services to work for their organizations.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Whether it’s Python, JavaScript, or other programming languages, Developers spend a lot of time writing code. More traditional infrastructure engineers are going to spend their time in a user interface configuring their systems and services to work for their organizations. Operations teams are going to be picking up what was developed for them by other groups and determine the right ways to run it efficiently.</p>



<p><strong><a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> engineers are going to be performing configuration management efforts, software development, operations activities, and quality assurance activities. Each of these can be automated by writing code with scripting languages. This means that DevOps engineers write code!</strong></p>



<p>Let&#8217;s explore what this means to a DevOps engineer who may not be comfortable with code since they are coming from a practice that generally performs their activities inside of a user interface.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Why Scripting Code is Important</h2>



<p>Automation is important. It’s a key part of the DevOps process, which aims to reduce the time it takes to perform manual processes. Automation also increases the reliability and stability of those processes.</p>



<p>While a lot of people talk about it, they rarely talk about why. If you don’t have a good reason, there’s a good chance that you won’t see the benefits of automation in your organization. That’s why it helps to understand why you are automating in the first place.</p>



<p>DevOps organizations have a lot of tools and technologies that need to integrate together. DevOps engineers will spend almost every day automating these integrations utilizing a variety of scripting languages or DevOps tools.</p>



<p>When you spend your days configuring everything from <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="14" title="AWS" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">AWS</a> keys to the location of a database; it’s easy to understand why organizations want to reduce the amount of time spent doing it manually.</p>



<h2>DevOps and Scripts</h2>



<p>Those who work across multiple different technologies to build applications and services spend a ton of time configuring environments, virtual machines, and cloud providers.</p>



<p>That means developers have to learn how to use every single one of those tools. At first, this might feel like a chore; after all, no one wants to learn how to use Inversion of Control (IoC) or batch files to get something from AWS into their local computer or network.</p>



<p>When you look at it from the perspective of someone who spends most of his or her day typing in code and reading other people’s scripts—the process can seem more like an abomination than anything else.</p>



<p>A majority of engineers are writing scripts to make their jobs more efficient. Scripts are the shortcut version of automation. They’re designed to help engineers reduce the amount of time they spend doing system administration, delivering software to servers, monitoring systems, performing configuration management, managing cloud vendors, and many other activities.</p>



<p>I have always advocated if you perform an activity against a user interface that has an API then you should take the time to implement that activity in code via your scripting language of choice.</p>



<p>By scripting your changes out, you both get an opportunity to codify a change, but you have an opportunity to introduce that code into version control. This will help shift the responsibility of that code from a single person to an entire team.</p>



<p>Additionally, scripting gives you the opportunity to add comments to your code. Software developers utilizing high-level programming languages will add comments in their code so that the next person that picks up their work understands the intentions of their work. Changes through scripting should be treated the same way. When someone spends time writing scripts, those should be added to the collective code base and their peers should be able to understand the code and consume their work.</p>



<p>Contributing to the code base also allows that code to be integrated into CI/CD systems for future automated actions.</p>



<h2>Which DevOps Engineers Should be Working With Scripts?</h2>



<p>The first step in automating any process is figuring out who should do the automation. That can be tricky. It’s easy to think that the developers who spend most of their day writing code should be the ones to automate their work.</p>



<p>After all, they have all of the technical knowledge. But, depending on the organization, that might not be the best idea. In organizations using DevOps practices, developers aren’t soley responsible for creating new end-to-end application solutions.</p>



<p>Instead, everyone on the team is responsible for creating an entire infrastructure along with the entire DevOps lifecycle.</p>



<p>DevOps engineers are responsible for automating the deployment and operations process of software applications. They are responsible for automating everything from creating configuration files to configuring software environments.</p>



<p>Many DevOps engineers work with scripts. There are many reasons why this is the case. One reason is that scripts allow DevOps engineers to automate tasks that are repeatable across multiple environments and application iterations.</p>



<p>If an automated task must be performed multiple times during the development process, it makes sense to create a script that can be used in each environment. Another reason is that scripts help reduce errors by providing clear instructions on how to perform the task.</p>



<p>DevOps engineers should be knowledgeable about scripting languages, such as Bash, Python, Ruby, and Javascript. They should also be familiar with automation tools like <a href="https://www.docker.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="16" title="Docker" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Docker</a> and <a href="https://www.ansible.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="7" title="Ansible">Ansible</a>.</p>



<p>They should be able to identify areas where automation can improve their workflow and determine what types of changes are needed to make automation possible in their organization.</p>



<h2>Why is it So Hard to Transition from Scripting to Automation?</h2>



<p>It might seem like your engineers would love to transition from scripting to automation. After all, they are spending their day writing code.</p>



<p>Sometimes a jump from scripting to automation can be difficult. If scripts are not written in a way that they can be parameterized, those scripts will not fit into an overall automation structure natively. Additionally, when you’re used to customizing everything from your local machine to your cloud providers, the thought of learning a new configuration tool can seem like a nightmare.</p>



<p>All of this confusion can lead engineers to either choose not to automate at all or make bad choices about how to automate. The software development industry has an answer for this.</p>



<p>Most engineers will take a little bit of time to work through the transition from their previous role into one that is inclusive of DevOps. This is why it is so critical to work with the team on learning DevOps and embracing a full DevOps transition.</p>



<p>Most software development starts as writing scripts, shell scripting, or learning bash. From there, it will expand into utilizing different popular programming languages. If your background is in Office365 administration, you will not go through this general progression.</p>



<p>Developers should take new DevOps engineers under their wing and help them utilize tools that may not be ultimately familiar with. DevOps engineering is the combination of many different skill sets breaking down traditional barriers. Helping DevOps engineers write scripts that are able to be integrated into a larger set of automation will be a huge step forward for anyone feeling lost in this adoption.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>How to Get Started With Automation in a DevOps Organization</h2>



<p>DevOps engineers constantly improve their automation, but there’s a lot to learn. That’s why it’s important to bring on someone to help with the transition to automation.</p>



<p>There are a few things you can do to get started. First, look at your existing scripts and see if you have any that could be automated. Are there any tasks that are taking more time than they should? If so, you might want to take a closer look at them. Next, look at your existing infrastructure. Do you have a known, consistent state? If so, you might want to take a closer look at your scripts.</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>If you’re a DevOps engineer who is coming from a user interface, the idea of writing code that can automate different tasks may seem scary. You may feel overwhelmed by the scope of this responsibility and wonder whether you can actually do it.</p>



<p>To start, you can check out some resources that are available on <a href="https://www.github.com/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="6" title="Github" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">GitHub</a>. One of the best ways to get started is to dive right into the world of scripting. The Python programming language is great for beginner developers because it’s very easy to pick up and performs well under the hood. Python has a free online course available that teaches you the basics with a few projects you can complete.</p>



<p>Once you know your way around Python, you can move on to the next step. As you progress, you can check out some of the other scripting languages in use. There are many options out there, and most of them are open-source and available for use. Your best bet is to choose one that you feel comfortable with, and then get familiar with the basics. You can find plenty of tutorials and documentation on how to get started with any of them.</p>



<p>When you feel ready, you can start experimenting with the different ways to configure your systems.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What are the two major benefits of DevOps?</title>
		<link>https://www.valewood.org/major-benefits-of-devops/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greer Shepherd]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 21:16:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DevOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[delivery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=488</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The first benefit of DevOps is that it enables organizations to release software faster, more reliably, and with higher quality. By breaking down the barriers between development and operations, DevOps allows teams to work together more effectively and efficiently. This&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The first benefit of <a href="https://www.valewood.org/topics/devops/" data-internallinksmanager029f6b8e52c="15" title="How To Leverage the DevOps Methodology for Success!​" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevOps</a> is that it enables organizations to release software faster, more reliably, and with higher quality. By breaking down the barriers between development and operations, DevOps allows teams to work together more effectively and efficiently. This helps companies get new features and updates into the hands of their customers more quickly.</p>



<p>The second benefit of DevOps is that it helps organizations become more agile. By automating the deployment process, DevOps makes it possible for companies to respond quickly to changes in customer demand or market conditions. This allows businesses to be more competitive and stay ahead of the curve.</p>



<p>Let&#8217;s take a look at each of these benefits in detail!</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Benefit #1: Deliver technology faster and at higher quality</h2>



<p>When your customers want more complex software products and expect you to deliver for them more quickly, the ways in which your company revolutionizes its product and service offerings will require a complete revamp. Collaboration and productivity enhancements brought about by DevOps are a big assist in meeting the innovation objectives of businesses.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The DevOps method of app development provides a company with a number of benefits, but the following five are the most important for any business that wishes to be inventive, available, and scalable. The following are those in question:</p>



<h3>Accelerate Time To Market</h3>



<p>DevOps reduces the amount of time it takes to bring a product to market, which in turn boosts business revenue. As a result of bringing together the IT and development teams to collaborate, the amount of time required to construct, test, and launch services or features is cut significantly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The DevOps strategy enables businesses to rapidly introduce new features, rapidly improve already existing ones, and rapidly make these new or improved features available to users.</p>



<h3>Changing in Response to the Industry and Competition</h3>



<p>You have to consistently offer high-quality items if you want to succeed in an industry that is very competitive. Even if you had a fantastic idea for a business and had already started building it, that wouldn&#8217;t help you capture market share. You are in need of an improved strategy as well as a process, both of which are provided by DevOps.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The delivery of new code is made both speedy and dependable thanks to DevOps. In addition, it allows teams to construct a scalable and robust application environment while still providing users with an outstanding experience. This approach not only helps acquire the market but also thrives in a competitive market by boosting the user base and income. In other words, it is a win-win situation.</p>



<h3>Keeping the System Reliable While Preserving Its Stability</h3>



<p>Continuous testing or <a href="https://www.valewood.org/devops-testing/" data-type="post" data-id="1239">automated testing</a> is something that DevOps encourages. Testing that is automated enables engineers to provide test results that are more accurate, offer fast feedback on the build, and monitor the completion of all operations. When the team searches for results, the DevOps methodology provides time savings by accelerating the availability and the entire body of work related to results in analysis on each CI/CT cycle.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This helps the team get results more quickly. The team is able to simply manage the system&#8217;s stability and dependability while also guaranteeing that the software products have excellent performance and availability.</p>



<h3>Bringing Down The Average Time To Recovery</h3>



<p>The bigger the financial effect that a corporation will have to deal with, the longer the MTTR will be. MTTR, which stands for &#8220;mean time to recovery,&#8221; is a problem that can be solved via DevOps. When a service experiences an outage, having DevOps in place may help speed up the process of repair, reaction, and recovery.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It provides assistance for monitoring mission-critical systems, which enables users to gain real-time insights on decreased performance as well as entire outages caused by events and failures. The methodology of DevOps not only makes it easier to collect precise information but also makes the incident-management system more automated. In this method, it is feasible to swiftly address the issue, which will ultimately result in a reduced MTTR.</p>



<h3>Capabilities for Providing a Better Experience to Customers</h3>



<p>DevOps approaches also place an emphasis on the one-of-a-kind characteristics of software designed for the user experience. The development of both the quality of the software and the customer experience may be sped up with the use of DevOps.&nbsp;</p>



<p>DevOps specialists monitor the customer&#8217;s point of view, plan sprints in accordance with that perspective, and test the product with the customer&#8217;s objective in mind. The team not only rapidly develops new features but also defines and enhances the whole customer journey for omnichannel.</p>



<p>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7120242057450442"
     data-ad-slot="6094810801"></ins>
	<script>(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});</script>
</p>



<h2>Benefit #2: React to changing market conditions more quickly</h2>



<p>These days, businesses undergo digital transformations by adopting innovative technology and methods. Keeping up with the digital economy is a top priority, and as a result, they are putting in extra effort to improve in all areas.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They need to improve their financial performance, product quality, product speed to market, and overall company adaptability. Maintaining competitive flexibility requires effective communication, collaboration, and bug-free code, all of which may be attained through the use of Agile and DevOps processes.</p>



<h3>Create a Culture-Oriented Structure</h3>



<p>It is common practice for an organization&#8217;s culture and structure to become one and the same. Teams need to adjust their mindset in order to use DevOps successfully. To put it simply, DevOps is a rearrangement of the teams and the way they work together and communicate.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Only when individuals work well together as a team can organizations make effective use of the available resources and technology. Both the development and operations teams need each other&#8217;s support. Being able to think critically sets humans apart from machines.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Therefore, agile culture and the way humans naturally think are incompatible with the sequential waterfall paradigm. There is an urgent need to proactively address these difficulties, and the classic waterfall approach can do just that. It can also impart the benefits of the DevOps paradigm and harmonize the organizational structure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This will boost overall collaboration and adaptability and guarantee that the company&#8217;s culture and the culture of its employees are properly melded. By focusing on the whole value chain of software delivery, DevOps is the logical next step after Agile.</p>



<h3>Streamline Techniques, Procedures, and Policies</h3>



<p>Collaboration across the organization&#8217;s development, testing, infrastructure, and IT teams is essential. Thus, the organization&#8217;s rules, procedures, and processes should reflect this. DevOps needs to reevaluate its workflow, roles, responsibilities, and methodologies if it is to attain genuine agility.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other words, they need to have a mentality that is consistent with the agile culture, which centers on producing incremental results and accommodating change. It&#8217;s not as simple as just adding weekly scrums on top of everything else, so be prepared for some complexity.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Development and operations must collaborate with automation technologies and fully integrated processes to operate in a succession of brief efforts and genuinely execute production-ready code that can actually be delivered to clients.</p>



<h3>Streamline Rapid Growth with Minimal Discomfort</h3>



<p>Agility in DevOps is achieved by bringing together the principles of <a href="https://www.valewood.org/devops-rapid-delivery/" data-type="post" data-id="1668">rapid development</a>, high throughput, and careful scheduling to improve dependability and minimize disturbance. </p>



<p>To take advantage of Agile&#8217;s rapid iteration cycles without sacrificing quality, the DevOps model may be used to zero in on the best approach and set you up with the best agile testing tools. It helps businesses find their footing so they can effectively and efficiently adapt to changing market conditions and capitalize on emerging possibilities.</p>



<h3>Remove Organizational Barriers</h3>



<p>Organizational agility may be improved by closing the communication and collaboration gaps across departments like operations, development, and testing. By enabling continuous development, testing, and deployment with a reliable toolchain, agility may be accomplished.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There is a tight coupling between the teams, instruments, and procedures in this method. The success of the DevOps model relies on effective communication and cooperation between several functional teams, which guarantees zero barriers across multiple agile teams supported by the proper collaboration technologies.</p>



<h3>Maintain Constant Monitoring</h3>



<p>For DevOps to be effective and for a plan to be developed, feedback is essential. Having fast and accurate input is crucial to the success of a DevOps approach. Each deployment should record the basic metrics of duration, expense, and quality. Over time, this information may be examined to determine DevOps&#8217;s efficiency and adaptability and to pinpoint problem spots.</p>



<p>Culture-based indicators like team cohesion, the average time to resolve conflicts, sense of pride and ownership, and so on can be challenging to quantify. When determining the speed and efficiency of DevOps, however, these cultural criteria are crucial.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Organizational culture, methods, mentality, and toolchain should be streamlined in order to expand the DevOps model and keep it agile and relevant for providing excellent deliveries. For this reason, it is essential to employ experienced teams that can work together to concentrate on constant development and evaluation.</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>By focusing on the whole value chain of software delivery, DevOps is the logical next step after Agile. Additionally, the DevOps model helps businesses find their footing so they can effectively and efficiently adapt to changing market conditions and capitalize on emerging possibilities.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
